<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Magick &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/magick/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 02:04:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Magick &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Exploring Symbolic and Quantum Parallels</title>
		<link>/technoshamanism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tobit]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 14:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychedelia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technoshamanism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technoshamanism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/exploring-symbolic-and-quantum-parallels-the-unicursal-hexagram-yin-yang-and-quantum-philosophy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Similarities in Symbolism The unicursal hexagram of Thelema and the Eastern Yin Yang symbol offer insightful philosophical parallels with the intriguing principles of quantum physics, particularly resonating with Niels Bohr’s concept of complementarity. This union gives birth to technoshamanism. The Yin Yang and Quantum Theory: In the Yin Yang’s flowing, interconnected nature, we see a reflection of the unicursal hexagram’s depiction of inseparable, opposing forces. This symbolic resonance is mirrored in the realm of quantum theory, where subatomic particles exist in a probabilistic haze, oscillating between contradictory states such as wave and particle, influenced by observation. This &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-similarities-in-symbolism">Similarities in Symbolism</h2>



<p>The unicursal hexagram of Thelema and the Eastern Yin Yang symbol offer insightful philosophical parallels with the intriguing principles of quantum physics, particularly resonating with Niels Bohr’s concept of complementarity. This union gives birth to technoshamanism.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-yin-yang-and-quantum-theory"><strong>The Yin Yang and Quantum Theory:</strong></h2>



<p>In the Yin Yang’s flowing, interconnected nature, we see a reflection of the unicursal hexagram’s depiction of inseparable, opposing forces. This symbolic resonance is mirrored in the realm of quantum theory, where subatomic particles exist in a probabilistic haze, oscillating between contradictory states such as wave and particle, influenced by observation. This phenomenon of quantum indeterminacy collapsing upon measurement parallels the Yin Yang, which beautifully illustrates the interdependence and mutual definition of seemingly opposite forces.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-unicursal-hexagram-and-connection-of-opposites"><strong>The Unicursal Hexagram and Connection of Opposites</strong></h2>



<p>The unicursal hexagram, representing the unity of opposites, resonates deeply with the principles of technoshamanism. This symbol&#8217;s depiction of interconnected forces is reflective of how technoshamanism aims to merge the mystical with the technological, suggesting that the ancient wisdom embodied in such symbols can inform and enrich our understanding of modern scientific concepts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-heisenberg-s-uncertainty-and-symbolic-parallels"><strong>Heisenberg’s Uncertainty and Symbolic Parallels:</strong></h2>



<p>Moreover, Heisenberg’s uncertainty principle, a cornerstone of quantum mechanics, states that precision in measuring one quantum property inherently limits knowledge of its complement. This concept finds a symbolic parallel in the Yin Yang, where each aspect contains and engenders the other in a perpetual, interwoven dance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-transcending-dualism"><strong>Transcending Dualism:</strong></h2>



<p>Additionally, both the unicursal hexagram and the Yin Yang transcend traditional dualistic perspectives. They reflect the counterintuitive nature of the quantum world, where particles don’t possess a singular, defined state but exist across a spectrum of probable characteristics. This aligns with a holistic view, moving beyond binary divisions to embrace a complex interplay of complementary forces. These symbols and quantum principles collectively challenge the classical, deterministic understanding of the universe, advocating for a more probabilistic and paradoxical interpretation. The unicursal hexagram and Yin Yang symbolize that apparent contradictions in existence are not at odds but rather form an interconnected, nuanced whole. They exemplify how opposites are generative, not negating, weaving together the complex tapestry of existence. Embracing these relationships, as illustrated by both symbols, aligns us with the harmonious nature of the universe, echoing the counterintuitive insights of the uncertainty principle.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-thelema-s-principle-of-0-2"><strong>Thelema’s Principle of 0=2:</strong></h2>



<p>The Thelemic principle of 0=2, deeply rooted in Aleister Crowley’s mystical system, provides a unique philosophical underpinning that complements the themes discussed in this article. At its core, this principle embodies the concept of unity emerging from duality, a fundamental tenet in Thelemic philosophy. The equation 0=2, in Thelemic thought, symbolizes the idea that the apparent duality of existence (represented by 2) ultimately originates from and returns to a state of non-duality or nothingness (represented by 0). This aligns closely with the concepts in quantum physics, where the seemingly dual nature of particles, as both waves and particles, emerges from a singular, undifferentiated quantum field. Just as the unicursal hexagram and Yin Yang depict the inseparable interplay of opposites, the principle of 0=2 in Thelema suggests that all dualities — light and dark, creation and destruction, positive and negative — are intrinsically connected, emanating from a singular source.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-0-2-and-wave-particle"><strong>0=2 and Wave-Particle:</strong></h2>



<p>In the context of quantum mechanics, one can draw parallels between the Thelemic principle of 0=2 and the wave-particle duality. Just as the 0 represents the undifferentiated, unified field, the number 2 reflects the dual nature of quantum entities. This duality is not a permanent state but rather a manifestation of the underlying unity. It reflects the much like the quantum state of a particle, not fixed until it is observed. This aligns with the Thelemic view that apparent dualities are merely different expressions of a single, underlying reality. Moreover, the principle of 0=2 resonates with the idea of quantum superposition, where particles exist in multiple states simultaneously until measured. In Thelemic philosophy, this can be seen as the myriad manifestations of the universe (the number 2) emerging from the void or the absence of existence (0). It suggests that the universe’s complexities, including its paradoxes and contradictions, are integral aspects of a unified whole, challenging our conventional understanding of separation and distinction.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-technoshamanism-quantum-physics-and-philosophical-symbolism">Technoshamanism: <strong>Quantum Physics and Philosophical Symbolism:</strong></h2>



<p>This philosophical exploration leads us to consider the significant role of metrics in confirming the existence of phenomena, a concept deeply rooted in both quantum mechanics and the interpretation of symbols. In quantum physics, the very act of measuring a particle’s properties – position, momentum, or spin – solidifies its existence in a specific state, transitioning it from a probability to a reality. This principle aligns with the symbolism of the unicursal hexagram and Yin Yang, where the definition of one aspect inherently confirms the existence of its counterpart. Just as the measurement of a quantum particle’s position simultaneously acknowledges the existence of its momentum, the presence of Yin intrinsically confirms the existence of Yang. This interplay of measurement and existence underpins both the mystic symbolism of these ancient icons and the empirical foundations of quantum mechanics, illustrating a profound unity between philosophical concepts and scientific principles. The existence of a metric, be it in physical measurements or symbolic interpretations, serves as a bridge between potentiality and reality, reinforcing the notion that our understanding and observation are integral to the manifestation of existence itself.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-quantum-physics-a-magical-rulebook">Quantum Physics: A Magical Rulebook</h2>



<p>Quantum physics, often perceived as a mystical domain due to its counterintuitive principles, aligns well with the technoshamanic perspective. This field&#8217;s exploration of particles existing in multiple states aligns with the technoshamanic belief in the coexistence of spiritual and physical realms. It posits that technology, when applied with an understanding of shamanic wisdom, can unlock new dimensions of understanding, similar to how the Yin Yang symbol encapsulates the duality yet unity of existence.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-technoshamanism-merging-ancient-mysticism-with-modern-technology">Technoshamanism: Merging Ancient Mysticism with Modern Technology</h2>



<p>Technoshamanism is a contemporary concept that fuses the ancient practices of shamanism with the advancements of modern technology and science. It embodies the idea that the spiritual insights and rituals of shamans, when integrated with the empirical approach of technology and quantum physics, can lead to a deeper, more holistic understanding of reality. Technoshamans utilize both the symbolic wisdom of traditions, like the unicursal hexagram and the Yin Yang, and the empirical data of quantum mechanics, proposing that this synthesis can offer a more nuanced and interconnected view of the universe. This approach suggests a harmonious blend of spiritual intuition and scientific inquiry, bridging the gap between metaphysical beliefs and technological advancements.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion:</h2>



<p>In conclusion, the integration of the unicursal hexagram, Yin Yang, and quantum principles presents a compelling view of reality. These concepts advocate for a universe understood not in terms of isolated absolutes but as a network of relational dynamics and potentials. They encourage transcending perceived divisions, viewing existence as a unified, complementary dance. This convergence of ancient symbolism and modern physics suggests a profound truth: existence is fundamentally an interplay of harmonious opposites, a concept now increasingly validated by the advances in quantum mechanics.</p>



<p><a href="https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=t5MohK5FHEY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Nobody explains it better than Professor Farnsworth</strong></a></p>



<p><a href="https://deoxy.org/l_digpol.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Except perhaps Dr. Leary</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Role of the Ars Goetia within Thelema</title>
		<link>/ars-goetia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 03:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/the-role-of-the-ars-goetia-within-thelema/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Ars Goetia, also known as The Lesser Key of Solomon, is a 17th-century grimoire, or book of magick that describes the 72 demons of Hell, which are known as the Goetia. It is believed that the Goetia can be controlled, or at least bargained with, by practitioners of ceremonial magick. The book is divided into two parts: the first part lists the demons, their names, ranks, and sigils; the second part provides instructions on how to summon and control the demons. The Ars Goetia describes Hell as having a complex, hierarchical political system. Each demon has &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia, also known as The Lesser Key of Solomon, is a 17th-century grimoire, or book of magick that describes the 72 demons of Hell, which are known as the Goetia. It is believed that the Goetia can be controlled, or at least bargained with, by practitioners of ceremonial magick. The book is divided into two parts: the first part lists the demons, their names, ranks, and sigils; the second part provides instructions on how to summon and control the demons.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia describes Hell as having a complex, hierarchical political system. Each demon has a specific rank and power, and they are organized under the command of powerful entities known as Goetic Kings or Princes. These kings and princes have authority and are considered leaders within the infernal hierarchy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-politics-of-hell">The Politics of Hell</h2>



<p style="font-size:25px">At the top of the hierarchy is Satan, who is the &#8220;Prince of Hell&#8221; and the &#8220;Great Emperor of the Infernal Regions.&#8221; Satan is assisted by his two lieutenants, Beelzebub and Lucifer. Below Satan are the seven princes of Hell, who each govern a specific legion of demons. The seven princes are:</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">Baal<br>Agares<br>Vassago<br>Samigina<br>Marbas<br>Valefor<br>Amon</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The princes of Hell are further subdivided into lesser principalities, dukes, counts, marquises, and presidents. Each of these demons has a specific rank and function in the infernal hierarchy.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia also describes the relationship between the demons of Hell and the human world. The demons are said to be able to grant favors to humans, such as wealth, power, and knowledge. However, the demons also demand a price for their favors.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">In addition to the demons listed above, the Ars Goetia mentions a number of other demons, including Asmodeus, Lilith, and Mephistopheles. These demons are not ranked as princes, but they play significant roles in the infernal hierarchy.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia is a controversial text, and its authenticity has been questioned by some scholars. However, the book remains an important source of information on demonology.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">Here are some additional thoughts on the politics and principalities of Hell described in the Ars Goetia:</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The demons of Hell are said to be constantly vying for power and influence. This leads to conflict and violence, as the demons try to gain an advantage over their rivals.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The demons of Hell are said to be very deceptive. They will often promise humans favors that they never intend to deliver. This can lead to humans being tricked and exploited. Donald Trump supporters can empathize.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The politics and principalities of Hell are a complex, evolving landscape. It is a world where power is constantly shifting, and where deception is the only rule.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The role of the Ars Goetia within Thelema, a religious and philosophical system developed by Aleister Crowley, is complex. Thelema embraces the idea of individual spiritual freedom and personal exploration. While Crowley himself was intrigued by and explored various magical systems, including the Goetic practices in his early years, he later distanced himself from specific grimoires including the Ars Goetia.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">Crowley believed that the true practice of Thelema was centered on individuals discovering and expressing their own unique spiritual path and will, rather than strictly adhering to prescribed systems from grimoires. He argued that the Goetia represented an outdated, Christianized perspective on demonic entities and was not aligned with the radical individualism of Thelema.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">However, some Thelemites, particularly those who engage in ceremonial magic, may still find value in the Ars Goetia as it provides a framework for evoking and working with various spirits. Ultimately, its role within Thelema depends on the individual practitioner&#8217;s personal beliefs and practices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thelema: Eastern and Western Individualism</title>
		<link>/thelema-eastern-and-western-individualism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 01:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/thelema-eastern-and-western-individualism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thelema Thelema, as a philosophical and religious system developed by Aleister Crowley in the early 20th century. It presents an interesting intersection between Eastern philosophy and the Western enforcement of morality and convention. Thelema draws upon various spiritual traditions, including elements of Western occultism. It also involves mysticism, and ancient Egyptian mythology, while also incorporating Eastern philosophical concepts. The idea of True Will and the pursuit of self-realization are central to the practice. True Will One of the central tenets of Thelema is the concept of True Will. This can be understood as an individual&#8217;s unique and &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-thelema">Thelema</h2>



<p>Thelema, as a philosophical and religious system developed by Aleister Crowley in the early 20th century. It presents an interesting intersection between Eastern philosophy and the Western enforcement of morality and convention. Thelema draws upon various spiritual traditions, including elements of Western occultism. It also involves mysticism, and ancient Egyptian mythology, while also incorporating Eastern philosophical concepts. The idea of True Will and the pursuit of self-realization are central to the practice.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-true-will">True Will</h2>



<p>One of the central tenets of Thelema is the concept of True Will. This can be understood as an individual&#8217;s unique and authentic purpose in life. Thelemites believe that discovering and aligning with one&#8217;s True Will is essential for personal growth and fulfillment. This concept shares similarities with Eastern philosophies that emphasize the importance of self-discovery. Hinduism&#8217;s concept of Dharma or Buddhism&#8217;s teachings on finding one&#8217;s own path to liberation is a good example.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-independent-thought-above-all">Independent Thought Above All</h2>



<p>However, Thelema also challenges conventional Western notions of morality and societal norms. It promotes the idea of individual sovereignty and encourages individuals to follow their own desires and inclinations. Provided they do not infringe upon the rights of others, of course. This can be seen as a departure from traditional Western religions that often enforce moral codes and dogmas.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-eastern-philosophy">Eastern Philosophy</h2>



<p>Eastern philosophy often encourages personal transformation and spiritual exploration. Thelema aligns with the idea of individual empowerment and the pursuit of one&#8217;s authentic path. However, the rejection of conventional morality and its emphasis on individualism may be seen as in line with Western counterculture. Both movements challenge societal norms and advocated for personal liberation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-interpretation-of-thelema">Interpretation of Thelema</h2>



<p>It is important to note that Thelema, like any belief system, is subject to interpretation and varies among practitioners. While some individuals may emphasize the individualistic and rebellious aspects of Thelema, others may focus more on its spiritual. The transformative elements find connections with Eastern philosophies that promote self-realization and inner harmony.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-blended-spirituality">Blended Spirituality</h2>



<p>In summary, Thelema presents an intriguing blend of Eastern and Western influences. It shares similarities with Eastern philosophies in its emphasis on self-discovery and the pursuit of one&#8217;s unique purpose. However, it also challenges Western enforcement of morality and convention by promoting individual sovereignty and freedom. Thelema may fit between the paradigm of Eastern philosophy and Western enforcement of morality. This judgement depends upon the interpretation and emphasis of its practitioners.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eastern Philosophies and Western Religions: Exploring Contrasts and Lessons for Humanity</title>
		<link>/eastern-philosophies-and-western-religions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 01:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/eastern-philosophies-and-western-religions-exploring-contrasts-and-lessons-for-humanity/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout history, humanity has sought answers to profound questions about existence, purpose, and the nature of reality. This quest has led to the development of diverse belief systems and philosophical traditions across the globe. In this post, we will compare the history of Eastern philosophies and Western religions, their evolutionary development, and the establishment of schools and temples, with the Western approach to religion, characterized by politically motivated churches, witch covens, and the Inquisition. By examining these differences, we can glean valuable insights and lessons for humanity&#8217;s collective growth and understanding. Eastern Philosophies: Evolutionary Development and Spiritual &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Throughout history, humanity has sought answers to profound questions about existence, purpose, and the nature of reality. This quest has led to the development of diverse belief systems and philosophical traditions across the globe. In this post, we will compare the history of Eastern philosophies and Western religions, their evolutionary development, and the establishment of schools and temples, with the Western approach to religion, characterized by politically motivated churches, witch covens, and the Inquisition. By examining these differences, we can glean valuable insights and lessons for humanity&#8217;s collective growth and understanding.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-eastern-philosophies-evolutionary-development-and-spiritual-exploration">Eastern Philosophies: Evolutionary Development and Spiritual Exploration</h2>



<p>Eastern philosophies encompass a rich tapestry of thought, including Hinduism, Buddhism, Taoism, and Confucianism, among others. These philosophies originated in ancient times and have evolved through centuries of contemplation and introspection.</p>



<p>One remarkable aspect of Eastern philosophies is their emphasis on spiritual exploration and self-realization. Rather than relying on external authorities or dogmas, these traditions encourage individuals to seek inner wisdom through practices such as meditation, mindfulness, and self-discipline. The schools and temples that emerged from these philosophies became centers of learning and spiritual guidance, fostering a harmonious blend of intellectual pursuit and personal growth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-western-religions-politics-persecution-and-the-dark-shadows">Western Religions: Politics, Persecution, and the Dark Shadows</h2>



<p>In contrast to Eastern philosophies, the history of Western religions, particularly Christianity, has been marred by episodes of political manipulation, persecution, and intolerance. The rise of politically motivated churches, such as the Roman Catholic Church during the Middle Ages, led to the centralization of power, often intertwined with secular authority. This entanglement of religion and politics resulted in a hierarchical structure that sometimes placed the interests of the few above the spiritual well-being of the many.</p>



<p>One particularly dark chapter in Western religious history is the Inquisition. During the Middle Ages and Renaissance, the Inquisition was used as a means to enforce religious orthodoxy and suppress dissenting voices. Countless individuals were persecuted, tortured, and executed, accused of heresy or witchcraft. Witch covens, popularly associated with pagan traditions and nature-based religions, faced similar persecution, with accusations of devil worship and supernatural powers leading to the suffering and death of many innocent people.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-lessons-for-humanity-embracing-tolerance-self-exploration-and-harmony">Lessons for Humanity: Embracing Tolerance, Self-Exploration, and Harmony</h2>



<p>Comparing the histories of Eastern philosophies and Western religions reveals important lessons for humanity. It is crucial to emphasize tolerance, respect, and openness when engaging with differing beliefs and ideas. The emphasis on personal growth and self-exploration in Eastern philosophies offers a path for individuals to develop a deeper understanding of themselves and their place in the world.</p>



<p>Additionally, the examples of politically motivated churches, witch hunts, and the Inquisition serve as cautionary tales about the dangers of power and dogmatism. Humanity must strive to separate spiritual exploration from the manipulation of politics and power. The freedom to express one&#8217;s beliefs and engage in dialogue fosters an environment of intellectual growth, mutual understanding, and compassion.</p>



<p>Furthermore, embracing the diversity of spiritual practices can enrich our collective understanding of the human experience. By studying and appreciating various philosophies and religions, we can discover commonalities, explore different perspectives, and build bridges of understanding.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-conclusions">Conclusions:</h2>



<p>The comparison of Eastern philosophies and Western religions highlights the evolutionary development and contrasting approaches to spirituality. While Eastern philosophies promote self-exploration and personal growth, Western religions have faced challenges arising from political motivations and persecution.</p>



<p>Humanity can learn valuable lessons from this comparison by embracing tolerance, openness, and self-exploration. We must strive to separate religion from politics, nurturing an environment where diverse beliefs can coexist harmoniously. By fostering such an environment, we can encourage intellectual growth, mutual respect, and compassion among individuals of different faiths and philosophies.</p>



<p>In our modern world, it is essential to recognize the inherent value of diversity in belief systems. Instead of viewing differences as threats or challenges to one&#8217;s own faith, we should embrace them as opportunities for personal growth and collective enlightenment. Just as Eastern philosophies have thrived through their acceptance of multiple paths to spiritual realization, we can also appreciate the richness and depth that different religious traditions bring to the tapestry of human existence.</p>



<p>Moreover, the history of politically motivated churches, witch hunts, and the Inquisition serves as a reminder of the dangers of religious extremism and the abuse of power. It compels us to question the influence of political agendas within religious institutions and to safeguard against the suppression of individual freedoms and the persecution of those with differing beliefs.</p>



<p>By promoting dialogue, education, and interfaith understanding, we can break down the barriers that separate us and foster a sense of unity and shared purpose. Humanity can draw inspiration from the wisdom and teachings of Eastern philosophies, which encourage introspection, compassion, and the pursuit of inner harmony.</p>



<p>The comparison between Eastern philosophies and Western religions offers valuable insights and lessons for humanity. By embracing tolerance, self-exploration, and harmonious coexistence, we can create a world where diverse beliefs are celebrated and where spiritual growth is nurtured. Let us strive to learn from history and work towards a future where respect, compassion, and understanding are the guiding principles that unite us in our quest for meaning and purpose.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Dynamic Duo: John Dee, Edward Kelly, and Their Profound Influence on Occultism</title>
		<link>/the-dynamic-duo-john-dee-edward-kelly-and-their-profound-influence-on-occultism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 20:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chaos Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enochian Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The realm of occultism has always enticed and intrigued seekers of hidden knowledge throughout history. Within this realm, the partnership between John Dee and Edward Kelly stands as a remarkable chapter. Their unique collaboration, the church&#8217;s view on their work, their influence on Aleister Crowley, and their impact on chaos magick and modern occultism overall deserve closer examination. 1. The Profound Partnership: In the late 16th century, John Dee, an esteemed English mathematician, philosopher, and astrologer, met Edward Kelly, an alchemist and medium from Bohemia (now the Czech Republic). Their partnership began in 1582 when Kelly claimed &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The realm of occultism has always enticed and intrigued seekers of hidden knowledge throughout history. Within this realm, the partnership between John Dee and Edward Kelly stands as a remarkable chapter. Their unique collaboration, the church&#8217;s view on their work, their influence on Aleister Crowley, and their impact on chaos magick and modern occultism overall deserve closer examination.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>1. The Profound Partnership:</strong></p>



<p><br>In the late 16th century, John Dee, an esteemed English mathematician, philosopher, and astrologer, met Edward Kelly, an alchemist and medium from Bohemia (now the Czech Republic). Their partnership began in 1582 when Kelly claimed to be able to communicate with angels. Dee saw an opportunity to unlock divine knowledge and supported Kelly as his seer.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>2. The Church&#8217;s Perception:</strong></p>



<p><br>During this period, the church held considerable power and influence. Dee and Kelly&#8217;s work often drew suspicion and scrutiny. They were accused of engaging in forbidden practices, particularly by Catholic authorities. The church feared their activities could challenge traditional religious structures and doctrines.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>3. Aleister Crowley&#8217;s Influence:</strong></p>



<p><br>Dee and Kelly&#8217;s work, particularly their attempt to communicate with angelic beings through a crystal or &#8220;scrying&#8221; mirror, deeply fascinated Aleister Crowley. Crowley, widely regarded as the influential figure in 20th-century occultism and the founder of Thelema, adopted many concepts from Dee&#8217;s and Kelly&#8217;s practices. Crowley saw himself as the successor of Dee and inherited their exploration of the spiritual world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>4. Impact on Chaos Magick:</strong></p>



<p><br>Chaos magick, a modern occult practice aiming to tap into personal power and change reality, drew inspiration from the works of Dee and Kelly. The chaos magick movement saw ritualistic structures as mere tools for the manipulation of reality, and thus, drew on the elemental power Dee and Kelly possessed. The fluidity and innovation inherent in chaos magick stemmed from the spirit of experimentation pioneered by these two historical figures.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>5. Influence on Modern Occultism:</strong></p>



<p><br>John Dee and Edward Kelly fundamentally shaped modern occultism in numerous ways. Their practices and beliefs opened the door to alternative modes of spirituality and the exploration of non-traditional avenues. Their approach to ritual, scrying, and spirit communication challenged established religious practices and dogmas, paving the way for an increasingly pluralistic and diverse occult landscape.</p>



<p>The partnership between John Dee and Edward Kelly not only pioneered new spiritual practices but also challenged the religious establishment of their time. Their controversial endeavors and unorthodox paths deeply influenced the likes of Aleister Crowley, the rise of chaos magick, and modern occultism as a whole. In today&#8217;s world, their legacy lives on as a symbol of the unyielding human pursuit of esoteric wisdom and the enduring impact of their contribution to the ever-evolving occult tradition.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unveiling the Mysteries of Enochian Magic: History, Application, and Lasting Influence</title>
		<link>/enochian-magick/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enochian Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=78</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Enochian Magick, a complex system of occult practice, has captivated the minds of magicians, scholars, and occult enthusiasts for centuries. Rooted in the communication with angels and exploration of higher realms, Enochian Magick is a unique aspect of Western esotericism. In this essay, we will explore the history, application, practice, and philosophy of Enochian Magic. We will also touch on it&#8217;s profound influence on future occult schools of thought. History of Enochian Magick Enochian Magick traces its origins to the late 16th century. Attributed to the English occultists Dr. John Dee, and his scryer Edward Kelley. Dee, &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-left">Enochian Magick, a complex system of occult practice, has captivated the minds of magicians, scholars, and occult enthusiasts for centuries. Rooted in the communication with angels and exploration of higher realms, Enochian Magick is a unique aspect of Western esotericism. In this essay, we will explore the history, application, practice, and philosophy of Enochian Magic. We will also touch on it&#8217;s profound influence on future occult schools of thought.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-history-of-enochian-magick">History of Enochian Magick</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Enochian Magick traces its origins to the late 16th century. Attributed to the English occultists Dr. John Dee, and his scryer Edward Kelley. Dee, a mathematician, astronomer, and advisor to Queen Elizabeth I and Sir Edward Kelly, a scryer.  They claimed to have received a complex system of angelic communication and magical practices. Their information was said to originate with celestial entities, including the language of angels called Enochian.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-application-and-practice-of-enochian-magic"><strong>Application and Practice of Enochian Magic</strong></h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-angelic-communication"><br><strong>a. Angelic Communication: </strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">At the core of Enochian Magick is the belief that practitioners can communicate with higher intelligences, specifically angelic beings. Dee and Kelley believed that the angelic language, Enochian, provided access to profound spiritual insights. It gave them access to divinatory knowledge, and practical magical operations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br><strong>b. The Heptarchia Mystica: </strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">One significant aspect of Enochian Magick is the Heptarchia Mystica, a system of planetary and angelic invocations. It involves invoking and working with the seven planetary angelic governors and their associated forces. By harnessing their powers for various purposes, a new form of magick was evolved.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br><strong>c. Elemental Tablets and Watchtower System: </strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Enochian Magick incorporates a complex system of elemental tablets and watchtowers, representing different regions of the spiritual and physical realms. Practitioners use these tools to establish contact with various entities, invoke energies, and perform rituals.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong>Philosophy of Enochian Magic</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br><strong>a. Cosmology: </strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Enochian Magick encompasses a unique cosmology involving hierarchical spiritual realms, angelic hierarchies, and the interplay between different planes of existence. It emphasizes the exploration and harmonization of these realms for spiritual growth and magical power.</p>



<p><br><strong>b. Divine Language and Harmonics: </strong></p>



<p>Enochian Magick holds that the angelic language, Enochian, possesses inherent vibrational power and harmony.  Use of this language and its accompanying rituals is believed to resonate with divine frequencies, facilitating contact with angelic forces.</p>



<p><br>c. Ascension and Spiritual Evolution: Enochian Magick promotes the idea of spiritual evolution and ascension through the exploration of higher realms. Practitioners seek to elevate their consciousness, refine their spiritual faculties, and attain a state of unity with divine forces.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-influence-of-john-dee-and-enochian-works-on-future-occult-schools-of-thought"><strong>Influence of John Dee and Enochian works on Future Occult Schools of Thought</strong></h2>



<p><br>Enochian Magick has left a profound impact on various occult schools of thought, inspiring and influencing practitioners and scholars alike. Some notable areas of influence include:</p>



<p><br><strong>a. The Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn: </strong></p>



<p>Enochian Magick played a significant role in the rituals and teachings of the Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn. It contributed to their understanding of angelic forces, symbolism, and ritual practices.</p>



<p><br>b. Thelema and Aleister Crowley: </p>



<p>Thelema, a system of spiritual and magical practice, draws upon Enochian Magick as an integral part of its ceremonial practices. Enochian elements can be found in Crowley&#8217;s rituals and his exploration of angelic communication.</p>



<p><br><strong>c. Modern Magick and Eclectic Traditions:</strong></p>



<p> Enochian Magick continues to influence modern magickal systems and eclectic occult traditions. Many contemporary practitioners incorporate Enochian techniques, rituals, and symbiology into their magical practices. The flexibility and adaptability of Enochian Magick make it a valuable resource. Those seeking to incorporate angelic communication and higher realms rely on it still today.</p>



<p>Additionally, the study of Enochian Magick has had a lasting impact on academic and scholarly circles. Its complex system of angelic communication, symbolism, and cosmology has sparked extensive research and exploration. Scholars continue to analyze and interpret the texts and manuscripts. Study sheds light on its historical context and its influence on occultism.</p>



<p>Moreover, Enochian Magick&#8217;s emphasis on angelic communication and the exploration of higher realms. This resonates with broader themes found in various mystical and spiritual traditions.  The concept of connecting with higher intelligences to seek insight is seen in different cultural and religious contexts throughout history.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-closing">Closing</h2>



<p>Enochian Magick stands as a remarkable and enduring aspect of Western esotericism. Its history, application, practice, and philosophy provide a rich tapestry of knowledge and insight into the realms of angelic communication. Its influence on future occult schools of thought, like Golden Dawn and Thelema, showcases the impact of this magical system. Practitioners and scholars continue exploring the depths of angelic Magick. Its mysteries and wisdom continue to unfold, inviting individuals to embark on their own personal journeys.</p>



<p>An article I found particularly useful (used without permission &#8211; if the author minds, I will instantly remove the link):</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-heterodoxology wp-block-embed-heterodoxology"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="6nAeOfSLbF"><a href="https://heterodoxology.com/2010/05/29/an-etiology-of-angelic-vision-article-on-john-dee-and-edward-kelly-in-aries/">An etiology of angelic vision: Article on John Dee and Edward Kelly in&nbsp;Aries</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;An etiology of angelic vision: Article on John Dee and Edward Kelly in&nbsp;Aries&#8221; &#8212; Heterodoxology" src="https://heterodoxology.com/2010/05/29/an-etiology-of-angelic-vision-article-on-john-dee-and-edward-kelly-in-aries/embed/#?secret=vKFoinf1nq#?secret=6nAeOfSLbF" data-secret="6nAeOfSLbF" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Power of Parody Religions: Finding Kinship and Healing Through Satire</title>
		<link>/parody-religions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 19:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self Help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=68</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Parody: The Healing Voice of No Reason Parody religions challenge conventional norms, and offer unique perspectives on spirituality. In a world dominated by mainstream religions, this is necessary.. They are satirical religions that seem unconventional or even nonsensical. However, they serve the profound purpose of giving shelter to those needing it. They offer solace, community, and a sense of belonging to those who find themselves at odds with traditional religious institutions. In this post, we will explore how these groups can be socially healthy, offering a haven for those who need it. . The Church of the &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-parody-the-healing-voice-of-no-reason">Parody: The Healing Voice of No Reason</h2>



<p>Parody religions challenge conventional norms, and offer unique perspectives on spirituality. In a world dominated by mainstream religions, this is necessary.. They are satirical religions that seem unconventional or even nonsensical. However, they serve the profound purpose of giving shelter to those needing it. They offer solace, community, and a sense of belonging to those who find themselves at odds with traditional religious institutions. In this post, we will explore how these groups can be socially healthy, offering a haven for those who need it. .</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-church-of-the-subgenius-embracing-absurdity-as-a-path-to-liberation">The Church of the SubGenius: Embracing Absurdity as a Path to Liberation</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Church of the SubGenius, founded in the 1980s, thrives on the idea of embracing absurdity. By blending elements of conspiracy theories, science fiction, and humor, it presents itself as a parody of religious dogma. It appears nonsensical on the surface, the Church of the SubGenius encourages followers to question authority. It promotes satire, silliness and a joking sense of arrogance as virtues. As they, reject societal norms, and find personal liberation. In a society that often expects conformity, the SubGenius movement offers an outlet for the alienated and distrustful. .</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Within the Church of the SubGenius, the concepts of the Xists, JR &#8220;Bob&#8221; Dobbs, and Slack play significant roles. Let&#8217;s explore each of these elements:</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-xists">The Xists</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong> </strong>The Xists are extraterrestrial beings depicted in the teachings of the Church of the SubGenius. According to the church&#8217;s mythology, the Xists are a race of alien overlords who plan to enslave humanity. They represent a satirical critique of conspiracy theories, parodies of apocalyptic prophecies, and the fear of external control.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Church of the SubGenius uses the concept of the Xists to explore themes of individual sovereignty. They represent skepticism towards authority, and the subversion of mainstream beliefs. The Xists serve as a fictional construct that encourages followers to question societal norms and reject oppressive systems.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-jr-bob-dobbs">JR &#8220;Bob&#8221; Dobbs</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">JR &#8220;Bob&#8221; Dobbs is the iconic figurehead and self-proclaimed prophet of the Church of the SubGenius. Often depicted as a mysterious salesman with a pipe and a wide-brimmed hat, Dobbs embodies the spirit of the trickster. He is a sly character who challenges established norms and promotes individual freedom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Dobbs represents a satirical take on religious leaders and charismatic figures. The Church of the SubGenius uses the persona of Dobbs to encourage followers to find their own path to enlightenment. Bob encourages and embraces absurdity, and seeks personal liberation. The character of JR &#8220;Bob&#8221; Dobbs serves as a symbol of the pursuit of &#8220;Slack.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-slack">Slack</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Slack is a central concept in the teachings of the Church of the SubGenius. It is a state of being characterized by personal fulfillment, satisfaction, and freedom from oppressive forces. Slack represents an individual&#8217;s ability to break free from societal expectations, finding purpose. Through Slack, one can live a life of enjoyment and fulfillment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-summary-of-the-church-of-the-subgenius">Summary of the Church of the Subgenius</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Church of the SubGenius sees Slack as a valuable resource that mainstream society seeks to suppress and control. Through humor and satire, the church encourages its followers to seek and embrace Slack by rejecting conformity and questioning authority. Embracing their unique quirks and desires, and becoming individuals who think for themselves.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Church of the SubGenius uses the concepts of the Xists, JR &#8220;Bob&#8221; Dobbs, and Slack to challenge societal norms. They question authority, and promote personal liberation. These elements serve as satirical devices that encourage followers to find their own path. They teach us to reject oppressive systems, and embrace the absurdity of existence.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-large-font-size" id="h-pastafarianism-a-delicious-take-on-satire-and-freedom-of-expression"><strong>Pastafarianism: A Delicious Take on Satire and Freedom of Expression</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Pastafarianism, symbolized by the Flying Spaghetti Monster, emerged as a response to the teaching of intelligent design in schools. It uses satire to criticize the encroachment of religious beliefs into public education. The Church of the Flying Spaghetti Monster may seem whimsical. Symbolized by a pirate regalia and reverence for pasta, but beneath the humorous façade lies a powerful message. The promotion of scientific literacy, secularism, and the right to express one&#8217;s beliefs in unconventional ways. Pastafarianism has been successful in challenging the privileging of certain religious beliefs. They successfully highlighting the importance of separation between church and state.</p>



<p>Discordianism: Embracing Chaos and Illuminating the Absurdities of Life</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Discordianism, inspired by the Principia Discordia, is a parody religion that revels in chaos and embraces absurdity. With their playful approach to spirituality, Discordians reject dogma and instead celebrate randomness, humor, and self-expression. The Principia Discordia outlines the &#8220;5 Suggestions&#8221;. These encourage individuals to find humor in life, question authority, and celebrate the absurdities that permeate our existence. By challenging the seriousness and rigidity often associated with traditional religions, Discordianism fosters an environment of camaraderie and self-discovery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-discordianism-the-beginning">Discordianism: The Beginning</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">According to the Principia Discordia, the story of how the Golden Apple fell is a central myth within Discordianism. What follows is a summary of the tale as described in the Principia Discordia. In the beginning, there was chaos, represented by the goddess Eris, the Greek goddess of strife and discord. Eris, known as Discordia in Discordianism, was not invited to the wedding of Peleus and Thetis. Thetis was a mortal and a sea nymph. Feeling slighted, Eris decided to disrupt the festivities. She threw a golden apple into the midst of the goddesses attending the wedding.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-jealousy">The Jealousy</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The apple was inscribed with the words &#8220;To the Fairest,&#8221;. This lead to a dispute among the goddesses as each claimed the title for herself. The three primary contenders for the apple were Hera, Athena, and Aphrodite. Unable to resolve the argument, they sought the judgment of Paris, a mortal prince.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">In return for his decision, each goddess offered Paris a bribe. Hera promised him power and riches. Athena offered him wisdom and victory in battle. Aphrodite tempted him with the love of the most beautiful woman in the world, Helen of Troy. Paris, swayed by Aphrodite&#8217;s offer, awarded her the golden apple.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-result">The Result</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">This act sparked the Trojan War, a legendary conflict in Greek mythology. The story of the Golden Apple falling symbolizes the chaos and discord that can arise from small acts or decisions. They can set into motion significant consequences. In Discordianism, the story of the Golden Apple falling should be interpreted metaphorically. It represents the disruptive power of discord and the recognition that chaos and disorder are integral parts of existence. Embracing the chaos and discord, Discordians find liberation and meaning in the absurdity of life.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-sacred-text">The Sacred Text</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The &#8220;Discordian Bible&#8221;, Principia Discordia, has in place of ten commandments, five suggestions, known collectively as the Pentabarf. The Pentabarf was, according to Discordian legend, discovered by the hermit Apostle Zarathud in the Fifth Year of The Caterpillar. He found them carved in gilded stone, while building a sun deck for his cave. Their importance was lost, because they were written in a mysterious cypher. However, after 10 weeks &amp; 11 hours of intensive scrutiny he discerned that the message. It could only be read by standing on his head and viewing it upside down. It read:</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-know-ye-this-o-man-of-faith">KNOW YE THIS O MAN OF FAITH!</h2>



<p class="has-large-font-size"><strong>I</strong> &#8211; There is no Goddess but Goddess and She is Your Goddess. There is no Erisian Movement but The Erisian Movement and it is The Erisian Movement. And every Golden Apple Corps is the beloved home of a Golden Worm.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong>II</strong> &#8211; A Discordian Shall Always use the Official Discordian Document Numbering System.</p>



<p><strong>III</strong> &#8211; A Discordian is Required during his early Illumination to Go Off Alone &amp; Partake Joyously of a Hot Dog on a Friday. This Devotive Ceremony to Remonstrate against the popular Paganisms of the Day: of Catholic Christendom (no meat on Friday), of Judaism (no meat of Pork), of Hindic Peoples (no meat of Beef), of Buddhists (no meat of animal), and of Discordians (no Hot Dog Buns).</p>



<p><strong>IV</strong> &#8211; A Discordian shall Partake of No Hot Dog Buns, for Such was the Solace of Our Goddess when She was Confronted with The Original Snub.</p>



<p><strong>V</strong> &#8211; A Discordian is Prohibited of Believing what he reads.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-it-is-so-written-so-be-it-hail-discordia-prosecutors-will-be-transgressicuted">IT IS SO WRITTEN! SO BE IT. HAIL DISCORDIA! PROSECUTORS WILL BE TRANSGRESSICUTED.</h2>



<p>__________________________________________________________________________________________</p>



<p>The metaphor in this text, as in the book, is as clear as it is beautiful. It means:</p>



<p><strong>I</strong> &#8211; This commandment asserts the primacy of the individual&#8217;s personal connection with the divine. It states that there is no specific goddess or deity to worship. Each individual must find their own understanding of the divine. Their definition is valid and must be honored. This promotes a sense of personal sovereignty and encourages followers to define their own spiritual beliefs.</p>



<p><strong>II</strong> &#8211; This commandment humorously states that Discordians should use the Official Discordian Document Numbering System. It reflects the playful and irreverent nature of Discordianism, emphasizing the importance of embracing absurdity and disregarding conventional numbering systems.</p>



<p><strong>III</strong> &#8211; This commandment instructs Discordians, during their early spiritual journey or &#8220;Illumination. A devotional ceremony of joyously partaking in a hot dog on a Friday. The ceremony contrasts with the dietary restrictions or taboos found in various religions. It highlighs the satirical nature of Discordianism and its rejection of rigid belief systems.</p>



<p><strong>IV</strong> &#8211; This commandment extends from the previous one, stating that Discordians should not partake of hot dog buns. The reason given is a reference to the &#8220;Original Snub,&#8221; a humorous event involving the goddess Eris. Through it, we honor the lie of Eris (Discordia) and a hot dog bun. The No Hot Dog Bun highlights the nonsensical and satirical nature of Discordian practices.</p>



<p><strong>V</strong> &#8211; This commandment prohibits Discordians from blindly believing everything they read. It promotes a skeptical and critical approach to information, encouraging followers to question, analyze, and discern the truth for themselves. It reflects the emphasis on individual thinking and personal responsibility within Discordianism.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-contradiction-is-valid">Contradiction is Valid</h2>



<p>These suggestions serve as a playful and satirical framework for navigating life, embracing chaos. They challenge conventional thinking, while playfully emphasizes the ever-changing and contradictory nature of existence. Discordians must embrace the fluidity of their beliefs and opinions. They recognize that consistency can sometimes stifle growth and creativity. By embracing contradiction, Discordians invite a more flexible and open-minded approach to life. This allows for the exploration of diverse perspectives and ideas. Discordianism embraces absurdity and nonconformity, and symbolizes the celebration of individuality, encouraging followers to express themselves freely and authentically.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-healing-power-of-parody-religions-finding-kinship-and-belonging-and-a-safe-space-for-nonconformists">The Healing Power of Parody Religions: Finding Kinship and Belonging and<strong> a Safe Space for Nonconformists</strong></h2>



<p>Parody religions provide a refuge for individuals who feel alienated or marginalized by mainstream religious institutions. They offer a sense of community, and acceptance to those who may not fit neatly into societal or religious molds.  By embracing humor and irreverence, these movements create spaces where people can express themselves without fear.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-satire-as-catharsis"><strong>Satire as Catharsis</strong></h2>



<p>Parody religions are a cathartic release for individuals who have been hurt or disillusioned by religious dogma. Through satire and absurdity, followers can find solace and healing. They allow us to reclaim autonomy and find humor in the institutions that may have caused us pain or confusion.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-fostering-creativity-and-critical-thinking"><strong>Fostering Creativity and Critical Thinking</strong></h2>



<p>Parody religions encourage followers to think critically, question established beliefs, and challenge the status quo. By satirizing religious and societal norms, these movements inspire creative and independent thinking. They allow individuals to explore alternative perspectives and expand their intellectual horizons. The freedom to question and challenge authority within parody religions promotes a culture of intellectual curiosity and fosters personal growth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-building-supportive-communities"><strong>Building Supportive Communities</strong></h2>



<p>Parody religions create tight-knit communities where individuals can find support, empathy, and understanding. By gathering like-minded people who share a similar sense of humor and skepticism, these movements form social networks. These networks that provide emotional support and camaraderie for the misfits &#8211; who are often the best people.. In a world where many struggle to find acceptance, parody religions offer a space where people can form meaningful connections. They give us an opportunity to forge lifelong friendships, outside the realm of conformity.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-challenging-religious-privilege-and-promoting-tolerance"><strong>Challenging Religious Privilege and Promoting Tolerance</strong></h2>



<p>Parody religions serve as a powerful tool for challenging religious privilege and promoting religious tolerance. By parodying established religion and presenting themselves as equally valid, they highlight the arbitrary nature of religious beliefs. This satirical approach prompts important conversations about the boundaries of religious freedom. They underline the need for separation of church and state, and respect and inclusively towards diverse belief systems.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion</h2>



<p>In closing, these parody religions may initially seem frivolous or absurd, but they offer solace, community, and a sense of belonging. By embracing humor, satire, and irreverence, these movements offer an alternative path for spiritual exploration, personal liberation, and critical thinking. Through their inclusive and supportive communities, parody religions provide a haven for nonconformists, fostering kinship and acceptance. In a world that often demands conformity, these movements remind us of the importance of individuality. They highlight the inherent subjectivity and relativity of truth, emphasizing that individual interpretations and experiences shape our understanding of reality. By embracing a multitude of beliefs, they promote tolerance and inclusivity, encouraging others to respect diverse viewpoints.</p>



<p>The Suggestions of Discordianism, like the philosophy behind many parody religions, must be taken with humor and irony. They serve as a reminder to challenge rigid thinking, embrace chaos, and find joy in the absurdities of life. Through these playful suggestions, we can create a framework that celebrates individuality, critical thinking, and the liberation of the mind. These core principles embrace absurdity, skepticism, and the challenging of established beliefs. They do so by using humor and satire as tools for personal liberation and subversion of societal norms. And the Goddess knows, we need more subversion of the norm.</p>


<p>[serious-slider id=44]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Divine Felines: Cats in Ancient Egypt, the Black Death, Witchcraft, and Aleister Crowley&#8217;s Fascination</title>
		<link>/the-divine-felines-cats-in-ancient-egypt-the-black-death-witchcraft-and-aleister-crowleys-fascination/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 16:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cats have held a special place in human history, often associated with mysticism, magic, and divine powers. From their revered status in ancient Egypt to their role during the Black Death, as well as their connection to witchcraft and occultism, the captivating allure of these enigmatic creatures has transcended time. Furthermore, the opinions of influential figures such as Aleister Crowley have shed light on their significance and symbolism. 1. Cats: The Divine Beings of Ancient Egypt: In ancient Egypt, cats were regarded as sacred creatures and were revered as manifestations of various deities, notably Bastet, the goddess &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cats have held a special place in human history, often associated with mysticism, magic, and divine powers. From their revered status in ancient Egypt to their role during the Black Death, as well as their connection to witchcraft and occultism, the captivating allure of these enigmatic creatures has transcended time. Furthermore, the opinions of influential figures such as Aleister Crowley have shed light on their significance and symbolism.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>1. Cats: The Divine Beings of Ancient Egypt:</strong></p>



<p><br>In ancient Egypt, cats were regarded as sacred creatures and were revered as manifestations of various deities, notably Bastet, the goddess of protection, fertility, and home. They were highly regarded, often mummified, and buried with their owners to accompany them in the afterlife. Killing a cat, even accidentally, was considered sacrilegious and a grave offense.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>2. Cats: The Unsung Heroes of the Black Death:</strong></p>



<p><br>During the devastating period of the Black Death in Europe, cats played a crucial role in curbing the spread of the disease. As carriers of fleas, which were the primary vectors for the plague, cats instinctively hunted and eliminated rodents, particularly rats, which were responsible for harboring these fleas. Their valiant efforts inadvertently protected humans and helped save countless lives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>3. Cats and Witchcraft: A Feline Connection:</strong></p>



<p><br>Unfortunately, the association between cats and witchcraft arose during the Middle Ages. Cats&#8217; nocturnal habits, enigmatic behaviors, and their independent nature led them to be linked with witchcraft and dark practices. These associations led to cats being persecuted and killed during the infamous witch hunts, as they were seen as familiars or companions to witches.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>4. Aleister Crowley&#8217;s Opinion on Cats:</strong></p>



<p><br>Aleister Crowley, a renowned occultist and key figure in the esoteric tradition of the 20th century, had varied opinions on cats. While he did not explicitly express his views on cats in his writings, he did reference feline symbolism and imagery in his magical system known as Thelema. Crowley often associated cats with independence, sexuality, mystery, and the exploration of the deeper aspects of human consciousness.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>5. Cats in Modern Occultism:</strong></p>



<p><br>Cats continue to be intertwined with occultism and modern spiritual practices. Many practitioners of witchcraft, Wicca, and various pagan traditions perceive cats as spiritual allies and possessors of arcane knowledge. Their grace, stealth, and aloof yet intuitive nature make them potent symbols of esoteric exploration and the mysteries of the unconscious mind.<br>From their divine status in ancient Egypt to their instrumental role during the Black Death and subsequent association with witchcraft, cats have garnered an everlasting allure, representing the enigmatic but aloof character. Their mysterious nature has attracted the fascination of figures like Aleister Crowley, who saw in them a reflection of human sexuality and untamed spiritual power. As we continue to explore the realms of occultism, cats remain present, intertwined with symbolism and embodying the indomitable spirit of magic and mystery.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Magick &#8220;Real&#8221;?</title>
		<link>/is-magick-real-within-the-construct-of-thelema/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 16:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The concept of magic, or magick, is subjective and can be interpreted in various ways depending on one&#8217;s beliefs, cultural background, and personal experiences. It is a topic that has been debated and explored throughout human history. In the context of occult and esoteric traditions, magick is often understood as the practice of using ritual, intention, and focused energy to bring about desired outcomes or to connect with spiritual forces. This practice can involve various techniques such as visualization, meditation, energy manipulation, and working with symbols or correspondences. While some individuals and spiritual traditions firmly believe in &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The concept of magic, or magick, is subjective and can be interpreted in various ways depending on one&#8217;s beliefs, cultural background, and personal experiences. It is a topic that has been debated and explored throughout human history.</p>



<p>In the context of occult and esoteric traditions, magick is often understood as the practice of using ritual, intention, and focused energy to bring about desired outcomes or to connect with spiritual forces. This practice can involve various techniques such as visualization, meditation, energy manipulation, and working with symbols or correspondences.</p>



<p>While some individuals and spiritual traditions firmly believe in the reality and effectiveness of magick, it is important to note that scientific evidence for the existence of supernatural or metaphysical phenomena associated with magick is limited. The scientific method relies on empirical observation, experimentation, and reproducibility, which may not easily align with the subjective and personal nature of magickal experiences.</p>



<p>It is also important to distinguish between magick and stage magic or illusions performed by entertainers. Stage magic involves sleight of hand, misdirection, and theatrical tricks intended for entertainment purposes, while magick in an occult or spiritual context is concerned with metaphysical and transformative experiences.</p>



<p>Within the context of Thelema, the belief in the reality of magick is a fundamental aspect of the philosophy and practices associated with this system. Aleister Crowley, the influential occultist and founder of Thelema, emphasized the importance of magick as a transformative tool for spiritual growth and self-realization.</p>



<p>In Thelema, magick is seen as a means to discover and align with one&#8217;s true will, which is considered to be the individual&#8217;s unique purpose and destiny. It is believed that through the practice of magick, individuals can tap into their inner power, connect with higher spiritual forces, and manifest their intentions in accordance with their true will.</p>



<p>Crowley developed a comprehensive system of magickal practices within the framework of Thelema, including rituals, ceremonies, divination, meditation, and energy work. These practices aim to facilitate the exploration of consciousness, the development of psychic abilities, and the transformation of one&#8217;s self.</p>



<p>Thelema views magick not only as a means of personal transformation but also as a way to affect change in the external world. It embraces the idea that individuals can influence events, circumstances, and even the collective consciousness through their magickal intentions and actions.</p>



<p>It is important to note that the efficacy and reality of magick within Thelema, like in any other spiritual or occult tradition, are subjective and based on personal experience and belief. While some practitioners of Thelema report profound and transformative experiences through their magickal practices, others may approach it from a symbolic or psychological perspective.</p>



<p>Ultimately, whether magick is considered real within the context of Thelema is a personal belief and can vary among individuals who engage with the philosophy and practices of Thelema. It is up to each practitioner to explore, experiment, and interpret their experiences to determine the nature and reality of magick within their own practice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title> Aleister Crowley&#8217;s Insights Into Guardian Angels in Thelema: Unveiling the Sacred Path</title>
		<link>/aleister-crowleys-insights-into-guardian-angels-in-thelema-unveiling-the-sacred-path/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 16:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aleister Crowley, the influential occultist and founder of Thelema, approached the concept of guardian angels with his distinctive perspective. In Thelema, a spiritual and philosophical system, the understanding of guardian angels differs from traditional notions. This blog post will delve into Crowley&#8217;s thoughts on guardian angels within the context of Thelema and explore the practices and principles associated with them. 1. Guardian Angels in Thelema: In Thelema, guardian angels are referred to as Holy Guardian Angels (HGA). They play a significant role in the spiritual journey, serving as personal guides and mentors providing guidance, insight, and protection. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Aleister Crowley, the influential occultist and founder of Thelema, approached the concept of guardian angels with his distinctive perspective. In Thelema, a spiritual and philosophical system, the understanding of guardian angels differs from traditional notions. This blog post will delve into Crowley&#8217;s thoughts on guardian angels within the context of Thelema and explore the practices and principles associated with them.</p>



<p>1. Guardian Angels in Thelema:</p>



<p><br>In Thelema, guardian angels are referred to as Holy Guardian Angels (HGA). They play a significant role in the spiritual journey, serving as personal guides and mentors providing guidance, insight, and protection. The HGA is considered an essential and sacred connection to the divine, reinforcing the core principle of Thelema – the pursuit of one&#8217;s True Will.</p>



<p>2. The Knowledge and Conversation of the Holy Guardian Angel:</p>



<p><br>One of the fundamental practices in Thelema is the Knowledge and Conversation of the Holy Guardian Angel (K&amp;CHGA). Crowley considered this ritual to be of utmost importance for spiritual advancement and self-discovery. The ritual aims to establish a direct and personal relationship with one&#8217;s HGA, allowing individuals to attain true knowledge of their purpose and divine path.</p>



<p>3. Crowley&#8217;s Personal Experience:</p>



<p><br>Aleister Crowley underwent transformative spiritual experiences himself when it came to the K&amp;CHGA ritual. He believed that contact with the HGA enabled a profound expansion of consciousness, leading to a deeper understanding of one&#8217;s innermost desires, talents, and Limitless potential. Crowley considered this transformative process to be central to the practice of Thelema.</p>



<p>4. Thelema&#8217;s Approach to Guardian Angels:</p>



<p><br>In Thelema, the relationship with the HGA is intensely personal and unique to each individual. Unlike traditional angelic beliefs that connote external beings, Thelema views the HGA as a reflection of one&#8217;s higher self or divine aspect. The HGA represents the embodiment of one&#8217;s True Will and acts as a guiding force leading individuals on their spiritual journey.</p>



<p>5. Practices and Techniques:</p>



<p><br>Thelema offers several practices to facilitate the Knowledge and Conversation of the Holy Guardian Angel, such as meditation, ceremonial rituals, and devotional practices. These methods focus on self-exploration, raising consciousness, and aligning with one&#8217;s divine purpose. The diligent pursuit of these practices within Thelema enables individuals to strengthen their connection to their HGA and gain profound insights into their spiritual path.</p>



<p><br />Aleister Crowley&#8217;s insights into guardian angels within the Thelema tradition provide a fascinating departure from conventional beliefs. The approach of Thelema towards the Holy Guardian Angel emphasizes the importance of self-discovery, aligning with one&#8217;s True Will, and fostering a deep and personal connection with the divine. By engaging in the practices and rituals prescribed in Thelema, individuals can embark on a transformative spiritual journey, unlocking the potential of their Higher Self and embracing their unique path.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
