<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Deadly Cults &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/deadly-cults/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 20:59:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Deadly Cults &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Development of an Exo-Toxic Memetype</title>
		<link>/the-development-of-an-exo-toxic-memetype/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 14:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deadly Cults]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=60</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rarely spotted in the wild these days, the albino Klansman is most often seen in the traditional garb, consisting of white sheets and a dunce hat. The Ku Klux Klan (KKK) was founded in Pulaski, Tennessee, in 1865 by six Confederate veterans: John C. Lester, John B. Kennedy, James R. Crowe, Frank O. McCord, Richard R. Reed, and Calvin E. Jones. Initially, the Klan was formed as a social club for Confederate veterans, but it quickly transformed into a brainless terrorist organization with a deeply rooted ideology of racial hatred and a deep, rich love for beer, &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Rarely spotted in the wild these days, the albino Klansman is most often seen in the traditional garb, consisting of white sheets and a dunce hat. The Ku Klux Klan (KKK) was founded in Pulaski, Tennessee, in 1865 by six Confederate veterans: John C. Lester, John B. Kennedy, James R. Crowe, Frank O. McCord, Richard R. Reed, and Calvin E. Jones. Initially, the Klan was formed as a social club for Confederate veterans, but it quickly transformed into a brainless terrorist organization with a deeply rooted ideology of racial hatred and a deep, rich love for beer, burning crosses, and being alone in the woods at night with groups of men.</p>



<p>The KKK&#8217;s history can be divided into three distinct waves:</p>



<p>1. First Wave (1865-1870s): The KKK emerged in the aftermath of the American Civil War, during the Reconstruction era. It primarily targeted newly freed African Americans and their allies, aiming to suppress their civil and political rights. The Klan used violence, intimidation, and terrorism to undermine Reconstruction efforts and restore white supremacy in the South.</p>



<p>2. Second Wave (1910s-1940s): The Klan experienced a resurgence in the early 20th century, fueled by factors such as the Great Migration of African Americans to Northern cities and a fear of social change. This iteration of the Klan expanded its targets to include not only African Americans but also Catholics, Jews, immigrants, and other minority groups. The KKK&#8217;s influence reached beyond the South, spreading to states throughout the country.</p>



<p>3. Third Wave (1960s-present): The KKK saw another resurgence during the Civil Rights Movement of the 1960s. Opposing desegregation and racial equality, the KKK carried out acts of violence, including bombings, arson, and murders, in an attempt to intimidate and terrorize African Americans and civil rights activists. The KKK&#8217;s influence declined in the later years, but small factions and extremist groups still exist today.</p>



<p>The beliefs of the KKK are rooted in white supremacy, racial purity, and nativism. They promote the idea of racial hierarchy, with white Protestants at the top and other racial and religious groups as inferior. The KKK seeks to maintain white dominance, oppose racial integration, and preserve what they perceive as the traditional American way of life.</p>



<p>The impact of the KKK&#8217;s bigotry on America has been devastating. Throughout its history, the KKK has been responsible for numerous acts of violence, including lynchings, bombings, and assassinations. Its actions have instilled fear and perpetuated a climate of racial hatred, leading to the oppression, suffering, and loss of lives of countless individuals.</p>



<p>The KKK&#8217;s ideology and actions have hindered progress toward racial equality and social justice in the United States. Their acts of terror have contributed to systemic racism, social divisions, and deep-seated prejudices that continue to affect American society. Efforts to combat racism and promote equality are ongoing, but the legacy of the KKK&#8217;s bigotry remains a painful reminder of the challenges that persist. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Title: Understanding the Operating Thetan Levels of Scientology</title>
		<link>/title-understanding-the-operating-thetan-levels-of-scientology/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 14:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deadly Cults]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=44</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction:Scientology, a controversial and secretive religion founded by L. Ron Hubbard in the early 1950s, places significant emphasis on the concept of the &#8220;Operating Thetan&#8221; (OT). Operating Thetan refers to the highest spiritual state a Scientologist can achieve through advanced training and auditing. In this blog post, we aim to provide an in-depth understanding of the Operating Thetan levels in Scientology, exploring their purpose, progression, and associated practices. 1. The Bridge to Total Freedom:The Scientology journey towards becoming an Operating Thetan is often referred to as &#8220;The Bridge to Total Freedom.&#8221; It is a comprehensive and structured &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Introduction:<br>Scientology, a controversial and secretive religion founded by L. Ron Hubbard in the early 1950s, places significant emphasis on the concept of the &#8220;Operating Thetan&#8221; (OT). Operating Thetan refers to the highest spiritual state a Scientologist can achieve through advanced training and auditing. In this blog post, we aim to provide an in-depth understanding of the Operating Thetan levels in Scientology, exploring their purpose, progression, and associated practices.</p>



<p>1. The Bridge to Total Freedom:<br>The Scientology journey towards becoming an Operating Thetan is often referred to as &#8220;The Bridge to Total Freedom.&#8221; It is a comprehensive and structured path that Scientologists follow to attain spiritual enlightenment and liberation from the constraints of the physical world.</p>



<p>2. OT Levels:<br>The OT levels are a series of progressing stages that individuals undergo in their journey towards becoming an Operating Thetan. While specific details regarding these levels are guarded within Scientology, some information has been made available:</p>



<p>&nbsp; a. OT I: Focuses on achieving spiritual awareness and increased control over one&#8217;s own spiritual being.</p>



<p>&nbsp; b. OT II: Involves delving into past traumatic experiences, particularly incidents involving extraterrestrial beings called &#8220;body thetans.&#8221;</p>



<p>&nbsp; c. OT III: A pivotal level in Scientology, it addresses the discovery and handling of &#8220;The Wall of Fire,&#8221; unlocking hidden memories of an alien dictator called Xenu who allegedly caused trauma to humanity.</p>



<p>&nbsp; d. OT IV: Focuses on the repair and restoration of one&#8217;s own spiritual abilities, including the ability to confront and handle suppressive influences.</p>



<p>&nbsp; e. OT V-VIII: These levels further develop spiritual freedom, personal abilities, and control over one&#8217;s own life and destiny.</p>



<p>3. Training and Auditing:<br>To progress through the OT levels, Scientology practitioners undergo extensive training and rigorous auditing sessions. Auditing involves a form of counseling in which an individual is guided through specific questions and techniques to address past traumas, negative emotions, and limiting beliefs.</p>



<p>4. Secrecy and Confidentiality:<br>Scientology places great importance on the confidentiality of the materials and teachings associated with the OT levels. The secretive nature of these levels has contributed to controversies surrounding the organization, including legal battles and criticism from former members and outside observers.</p>



<p>Conclusion:<br>The Operating Thetan levels form a significant part of the spiritual journey within Scientology. While their specific details remain largely confidential, the OT levels are believed to provide Scientologists with tools and practices aimed at achieving spiritual enlightenment, personal empowerment, and control over their own destinies. As with any religious or spiritual practice, opinions on Scientology&#8217;s Operating Thetan levels and the associated teachings vary widely, and individuals are encouraged to explore and form their own conclusions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
