<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Music &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/music/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 13:09:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Music &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">222527107</site>	<item>
		<title>The Legendary Music and Style of Coil</title>
		<link>/the-musical-journey-of-coil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kalei Gawd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 23:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/the-musical-journey-of-coil/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To expand on the essay about the music of Coil, we will explore their experimental ethos, delve deeper into their discography highlighting key projects and their thematic significance, examine the impact of their performances, and assess their legacy within and beyond the music industry. Experimental Ethos and Thematic Significance Coil&#8217;s approach to music was not just about creating sound but about invoking an experience. Their work often blurred the lines between music, performance art, and ritual, creating a multi-sensory experience that engaged listeners on various levels. This section explores how the music of Coil and their experimental ethos and thematic &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To expand on the essay about <strong>the music of Coil</strong>, we will explore their experimental ethos, delve deeper into their discography highlighting key projects and their thematic significance, examine the impact of their performances, and assess their legacy within and beyond the music industry.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Experimental Ethos and Thematic Significance</h3>



<p>Coil&#8217;s approach to music was not just about creating sound but about invoking an experience. Their work often blurred the lines between music, performance art, and ritual, creating a multi-sensory experience that engaged listeners on various levels. This section explores how the music of Coil and their experimental ethos and thematic exploration of taboo subjects set them apart in the music world. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Psychedelic Drugs</h2>



<p>Coil&#8217;s exploration of sound and consciousness was deeply intertwined with their use of psychedelic drugs, which played a significant role in their creative process and thematic content. The band members, particularly John Balance, were open about their use of substances such as LSD and psilocybin mushrooms to alter perception and access altered states of consciousness. These experiences influenced Coil&#8217;s music, leading to the creation of soundscapes that aimed to replicate or evoke the transcendental and transformative experiences encountered during psychedelic journeys. The use of these substances was not merely recreational but was approached with a sacramental reverence, viewed as tools for spiritual exploration and artistic inspiration. This psychedelic influence is evident in the band&#8217;s thematic preoccupations with the occult, the mystical, and the exploration of the boundaries of consciousness. Coil&#8217;s music, therefore, can be seen as a sonic embodiment of their psychedelic experiences, designed to transport the listener to otherworldly realms and invoke deep introspective journeys. Their work challenges conventional perceptions of reality and invites a deeper engagement with the mysteries of the psyche, making their music a potent catalyst for personal exploration and discovery.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Key Projects and Their Significance</h4>



<p>To enrich the discussion on Coil&#8217;s pivotal projects and their significance within their discography, let&#8217;s delve into additional albums that showcase the breadth of their experimental ethos and thematic exploration. These albums further illustrate Coil&#8217;s audacity in sound manipulation and thematic depth, cementing their legacy as pioneers in the field of experimental music.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>&#8220;Scatology&#8221; (1984):</strong> Coil&#8217;s debut album introduced listeners to their fascination with the darker aspects of human nature and spirituality. The title itself, referring to the study of feces, hints at the album&#8217;s exploration of themes considered taboo by mainstream society. Songs like &#8220;The Sewage Worker&#8217;s Birthday Party&#8221; showcase Coil&#8217;s ability to blend grim subject matter with innovative soundscapes.</li>



<li><strong>&#8220;Horse Rotorvator&#8221; (1986):</strong> This album marked a significant evolution in Coil&#8217;s sound and thematic complexity. With references to the apocalyptic, the sexual, and the spiritual, &#8220;Horse Rotorvator&#8221; is a journey through death and rebirth, showcasing Coil&#8217;s mastery of sonic storytelling.</li>



<li><strong>&#8220;Gold Is the Metal (With the Broadest Shoulders)&#8221; (1987):</strong> Serving as a bridge between &#8220;Horse Rotorvator&#8221; and their later work, this album delves into alchemical themes, exploring transformation and the quest for spiritual gold. It’s a testament to Coil&#8217;s interest in the mystical processes of change and enlightenment.</li>



<li><strong>&#8220;The Ape of Naples&#8221; (2005):</strong>  &#8220;The Ape of Naples&#8221; is often regarded as Coil&#8217;s swan song, the final statement from a band that had constantly evolved throughout its existence. Released posthumously after the death of John Balance, the album is a poignant conclusion to Coil&#8217;s musical journey, combining previously unreleased works with reimagined versions of older tracks. The album is characterized by its introspective atmosphere, with themes of finality, transformation, and transcendence weaving through the tracks. &#8220;The Ape of Naples&#8221; showcases Coil&#8217;s ability to blend melancholy melodies with their signature experimental soundscapes, offering a deeply emotional and spiritually resonant experience. This album stands as a testament to Coil&#8217;s enduring influence and the profound impact of their music on listeners and the broader musical landscape.</li>



<li><strong>&#8220;Musick to Play in the Dark&#8221; (1999 and 2000):</strong> &#8220;Musick to Play in the Dark&#8221; is a two-volume series that marks a significant phase in Coil&#8217;s discography, exploring themes of dreams, lunar cycles, and nocturnal consciousness. These albums represent a departure from the more abrasive sounds of their earlier work, embracing a more ambient and introspective sound palette. The series is designed to be experienced in the dark, aiming to create a soundtrack for the listener&#8217;s imagination and inner explorations. Tracks like &#8220;Are You Shivering?&#8221; and &#8220;Broccoli&#8221; combine haunting melodies with eerie soundscapes, inviting listeners into a world of shadow and mystery. &#8220;Musick to Play in the Dark&#8221; exemplifies Coil&#8217;s mastery of mood and atmosphere, creating immersive experiences that linger long after the music ends.</li>



<li><strong>&#8220;Black Light District: A Thousand Lights in a Darkened Room&#8221; (1996):</strong> Released under the name Black Light District, this album was a collaborative effort that saw Coil experimenting with new textures and forms. &#8220;A Thousand Lights in a Darkened Room&#8221; dives into the realms of ambient industrial, incorporating elements of techno and dub. The album is noted for its richly layered soundscapes that create a sense of depth and space, with tracks like &#8220;The Dreamer Is Still Asleep&#8221; standing out for their hypnotic rhythms and ethereal vocals. This project highlighted Coil&#8217;s willingness to explore and integrate diverse musical styles, further showcasing their versatility and innovative spirit.</li>



<li><strong>&#8220;Stolen &amp; Contaminated Songs&#8221; (1992):</strong> This compilation album consists of outtakes and unreleased tracks from the &#8220;Love&#8217;s Secret Domain&#8221; sessions. &#8220;Stolen &amp; Contaminated Songs&#8221; offers a glimpse into Coil&#8217;s creative process, featuring a mix of experimental noise, ambient, and industrial sounds. The album encapsulates Coil&#8217;s ability to find beauty in the chaotic, with tracks that range from the hauntingly beautiful to the unsettlingly bizarre. It serves as a testament to Coil&#8217;s relentless experimentation and their knack for pushing the boundaries of what music can be.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Reflection on Coil&#8217;s Thematic and Musical Exploration: </h2>



<p>These key projects underscore Coil&#8217;s profound engagement with themes of mortality, transformation, and the unseen aspects of reality. Through their innovative use of sound, Coil not only explored the limits of musical expression but also invited listeners to confront the deeper mysteries of existence. Each album, with its unique thematic focus and sound design, contributes to the rich tapestry of Coil&#8217;s discography, offering different entry points into their esoteric world.</p>



<p>The music of Coil is a labyrinthine journey through sound, symbolism, and the subconscious. Their work challenges and rewards in equal measure, offering an unparalleled exploration of the potential of music to transform and transcend. As we delve deeper into their key projects, we uncover the layers of meaning and innovation that define Coil&#8217;s legacy, affirming their status as one of the most influential and enigmatic acts in experimental music.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The Philosophical Underpinnings of &#8220;Time Machines&#8221;</h3>



<p>&#8220;Time Machines&#8221; was conceived as an exploration into the concept of temporal displacement through sound. Coil, through this album, sought to create a series of auditory spaces that would facilitate altered states of consciousness, allowing listeners to experience a form of time travel through sound. Each track on the album is carefully crafted to resonate with specific psychoactive frequencies, believed to alter perception and consciousness.</p>



<p>The album’s connection to John Dee&#8217;s Enochian system of magick underpins its philosophical depth. Dee&#8217;s work, which involved complex esoteric lore and angelic communications, represents a profound source of mystical inspiration for the album. The numerical and alphabetical codes used to title the tracks are not arbitrary; they are deeply rooted in the lore and logic of Dee’s magical system, suggesting a deliberate attempt to encode the music with specific spiritual and temporal properties.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Composition and Sound Design</h3>



<p>The sound design of &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; is characterized by its minimalism and depth. The album employs drones and repetitive motifs to create immersive soundscapes. These sounds do not evolve quickly; rather, they unfold gradually, inviting listeners to sink into a meditative state. The use of specific frequencies and tones is intended to interact with the brain in a way that encourages temporal and psychological displacement.</p>



<p>Each track utilizes a combination of analog synthesizers, digital processing, and natural sound sources to achieve its unique texture. The production techniques are innovative, with Coil manipulating sound in such a way that the origin of these tones becomes indiscernible, blurring the line between electronic and organic. This ambiguity contributes to the album&#8217;s ability to transport listeners to spaces that feel simultaneously alien and familiar.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Thematic Exploration and Listener Experience</h3>



<p>The tracks on &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; are more than just musical compositions; they are sonic portals to altered states of consciousness. The album is structured around the concept of chronostasis, the illusion of time stopping. This is achieved through the meticulous construction of each piece, designed to induce a trance-like state where the perception of time is altered.</p>



<p>Listeners have reported a range of experiences while engaging with the album, from deep meditation and relaxation to more profound, trance-like states where the sense of temporal flow is dramatically altered. Some have described sensations of floating outside of time, experiencing moments of their past, or feeling a profound connection to the eternal. These experiences underscore Coil&#8217;s success in creating a work that not only explores time as a concept but also manipulates the listener&#8217;s perception of it.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The Music of Coil: Impact on Music and Art</h3>



<p>&#8220;Time Machines&#8221; has had a significant impact on both music and the broader arts, influencing a wide range of artists across different mediums. Its approach to sound and time has inspired musicians, composers, and sound artists to explore the potential of music to alter consciousness and perception. The album is often cited in discussions about the intersection of music, time, and psychology, highlighting its importance as a work of art that transcends traditional musical boundaries.</p>



<p>In the realm of ambient and drone music, &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; is seen as a landmark release, pushing the genres into new territories. Its influence can be heard in the works of contemporary artists who explore long-form compositions and the psychological effects of sound. Moreover, the album&#8217;s use of esoteric and philosophical concepts has inspired artists to incorporate similar themes into the music of Coil, contributing to a rich dialogue between music and mysticism.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The Timeless Resonance of &#8220;Time Machines&#8221;</h3>



<p>&#8220;Time Machines&#8221; remains one of Coil&#8217;s most enigmatic and profound works, a testament to their ability to push the boundaries of music and consciousness. The album invites listeners to embark on a journey through time and space, offering a unique experience that challenges conventional perceptions of music and its capabilities. Through its innovative sound design, philosophical depth, and transformative potential, &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; has secured its place as a seminal work in the annals of experimental music.</p>



<p>The legacy of &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; is not just in its sound but in its invitation to explore the unknown. Coil&#8217;s work encourages us to question the nature of time, consciousness, and the possibilities of sonic exploration. As we continue to navigate the complexities of the modern world, &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; stands as a beacon, reminding us of the power of music to transcend the here and now, to alter our perceptions, and to connect us with the ineffable mysteries of the universe. Coil&#8217;s journey through the realms of sound and time continues to inspire and challenge, a testament to their visionary artistry and the enduring power of their musical odyssey.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">The Impact of Their Performances</h4>



<p>Coil&#8217;s live performances were as much a part of their art as their recordings. They were known for creating immersive environments that transformed concert venues into spaces of ritual and transcendence. By incorporating elements like projections, incense, and ritual objects, Coil&#8217;s performances invited the audience into a participatory experience, breaking down the barrier between artist and observer.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Coil&#8217;s Legacy and Influence</h3>



<p>The legacy of Coil extends far beyond their own music. They were pioneers in the truest sense, charting territories unexplored by mainstream artists and influencing countless others to follow in their footsteps.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Influence on Other Bands and Genres</h4>



<p>Coil&#8217;s willingness to explore the fringes of music and culture inspired a generation of artists to do the same. Their influence can be seen in the works of bands across various genres, pushing the boundaries of what is possible in music and art. Today, Coil&#8217;s influence is evident in the music of artists across the spectrum of experimental and electronic music. From the haunting soundscapes of dark ambient projects to the cutting-edge explorations of modern electronic musicians, Coil&#8217;s legacy of innovation and exploration continues to inspire.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion: The Mystical Odyssey of Coil</h3>



<p>Coil&#8217;s music was a journey into the unknown, challenging listeners to explore the depths of their own consciousness and the mysteries of the universe. Through their experimental approach, thematic boldness, and transformative performances, Coil left an indelible mark on the world of music. Their work continues to inspire artists and listeners alike, ensuring that Coil&#8217;s mystical odyssey will resonate for generations to come.</p>



<p>By embracing the occult and pushing the boundaries of music and performance, Coil not only created a unique sound but also opened up new avenues for artistic expression. Their legacy is a testament to the power of music as a tool for exploration, transformation, and transcendence. Coil&#8217;s journey through the realms of sound and spirit continues to captivate those who are willing to venture into the esoteric landscapes they crafted, serving as a beacon for those who seek to explore the outer edges of music and consciousness.</p>



<span id="more-929"></span>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">929</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exploring the Enigmatic Depths: A Deep Dive into Dark Ambient Music</title>
		<link>/dark-ambient/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kalei Gawd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 23:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/exploring-the-enigmatic-depths-a-deep-dive-into-dark-ambient-music/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction to Dark Ambient Music Within the expansive realm of ambient music, a subgenre exists that delves into the shadows. It conjures a sense of foreboding and mystery. This subgenre, known as dark ambient, harnesses atmospheric soundscapes to create an eerie and otherworldly sonic experience. In this post, we embark on an exploration of dark ambient. We will focus on the works of Coil and Lustmord, two major contributors to the genre. We will also examine examples of the genre. Description of Audio Dark ambient is a genre that immerses the listener in haunting and atmospheric soundscapes. It evokes feelings &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-introduction-to-dark-ambient-music">Introduction to Dark Ambient Music</h2>



<p>Within the expansive realm of ambient music, a subgenre exists that delves into the shadows. It conjures a sense of foreboding and mystery. This subgenre, known as <strong>dark ambient,</strong> harnesses atmospheric soundscapes to create an eerie and otherworldly sonic experience. In this post, we embark on an exploration of dark ambient. We will focus on the works of Coil and Lustmord, two major contributors to the genre. We will also examine examples of the genre.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-description-of-audio">Description of Audio</h2>



<p>Dark ambient is a genre that immerses the listener in haunting and atmospheric soundscapes. It evokes feelings of unease, introspection, and the supernatural. Dark ambient embraces dissonance. Ambient music is relaxing, dark ambient is disturbing. The textural experimentation and a sonic palette reflect the underbelly of existence. It is music that takes us to uncharted territories, evoking a sense of dread, awe, and introspection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-perhaps-the-creator-of-the-genre">Perhaps the Creator of the Genre</h2>



<p>Lustmord, a pioneer in dark ambient, plunges listeners into the abyss with his atmospheric compositions. His album &#8220;Heresy&#8221; serves as a prime example of his artistry and occult leanings. The track &#8220;Black Star&#8221; combines deep, resonant drones with haunting vocal samples. It conjures a sense of cosmic dread and the mysteries of the void. Lustmord&#8217;s work transcends conventional music, inviting listeners to explore the recesses of their psyche and confront their deepest fears.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-coil-one-of-several-pioneering-bands-of-dark-ambient">Coil, one of Several Pioneering Bands of Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>Coil, with their multifaceted exploration of occult themes, has made an indelible mark on dark ambient. Their seminal album &#8220;The Ape of Naples&#8221; stands as a testament to their artistic vision and occult fascinations. &#8220;Fire of the Mind&#8221; and &#8220;Going Up&#8221; delve into themes of ritualistic transformation and spiritual transcendence. The hypnotic rhythms, cryptic lyrics and subtle references to esoteric symbolism, create a disruptive atmosphere. It blurs the boundaries between the sacred and the profane.</p>



<p>&#8220;Musick to Play in the Dark Vol. 1,&#8221; delves into the mystical realms with tracks like &#8220;Are You Shivering?&#8221;. The track &#8220;Red Birds Will Fly Out of the East and Destroy Paris in a Night.&#8221; can be terrifying. These compositions traverse the depths of the subconscious, enveloping the listener in an arcane soundscape. Coil&#8217;s music often acts as a portal, allowing us to glimpse the hidden dimensions beyond the veil. Darl Ambient becomes the void.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s and Lustmord&#8217;s music, through their albums and songs, offer glimpses into the occult. They transport us to liminal spaces where the veils between worlds are thin, inviting us to explore our subconscious. They force confrontation between the endless mysteries that lie within.</p>



<p>In Coil&#8217;s work, the occult themes can be interpreted as metaphors for personal transformation. Often, spiritual enlightenment and the quest for hidden knowledge can be felt.. Their music becomes a vessel through which the listener can embark on a transformative journey. Encouraging listeners to shed old limitations and embracing the unknown is clearly a goal.</p>



<p>Lustmord&#8217;s compositions immerse us in the depths of cosmic and primordial forces. The occult themes in his work can be seen as gateways to existential contemplation. We confront the vastness and mysteries of the universe. They invite us to embrace the terrifying beauty of the unknown and find solace in the abyss.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-occult-themes-in-dark-ambient">Occult Themes in Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The occult themes within dark ambient music serve as gateways to introspection, transformation, and the exploration of the unknown. They act as sonic manifestations of esoteric philosophies, arcane rituals, and the interplay between light and darkness.</p>



<p>Dark ambient music, with its atmospheric textures and occult themes, offers a sonic journey into the enigmatic depths of existence. Coil and Lustmord, through their pioneering works, have reshaped the genre and expanded its sonic boundaries. By exploring specific albums and songs, we can interpret the occult themes as invitations. They encourage us to delve into our subconscious, confront our fears, and embrace the transformative power of the unknown. Dark ambient remains an immersive and profound genre, providing a sonic sanctuary for those who seek solace in the shadows.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-drugs-and-dark-ambient">Drugs and Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The band Coil and the artist Lustmord have both mentioned or discussed LSD (Lysergic acid diethylamide) in various interviews. They are not shy about their explorations of the psyche.</p>



<p>Coil, known for their openness about their exploration of altered states of consciousness have made references to LSD in interviews. They have discussed the influence of LSD on their creative process and their experiences with the psychedelic substance. It is worth noting that Coil&#8217;s interests extended beyond just LSD, including wide range of psychedelic substances and esoteric practices.</p>



<p>Lustmord has referenced LSD in interviews. He has discussed the influence of psychedelics on his creative work and their potential for expanding consciousness and perception.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Coil and Lustmord have embraced a multidimensional approach to their art, drawing inspiration from various sources. These include altered states of consciousness induced by substances like LSD. These references often highlight the transformative potential of psychedelics and their impact on the creative process.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-introduction-to-dark-ambient-music-0">Introduction to Dark Ambient Music</h2>



<p>Within the expansive realm of ambient music, a subgenre exists that delves into the shadows. It conjures  a sense of foreboding and mystery. This subgenre, known as dark ambient, harnesses atmospheric soundscapes to create an eerie and otherworldly sonic experience. In this post, we embark on an exploration of dark ambient. We will focus on the works of Coil and Lustmord, two major contributors to the genre. We will also examine examples of </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-description-of-audio-0">Description of Audio</h2>



<p>Dark ambient is a genre that immerses the listener in haunting and atmospheric soundscapes. It evokes feelings of unease, introspection, and the supernatural. Dark ambient embraces dissonance. Ambient music is relaxing, dark ambient is disturbing. The textural experimentation and a sonic palette reflect the underbelly of existence. It is music that takes us to uncharted territories, evoking a sense of dread, awe, and introspection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-perhaps-the-creator-of-the-genre-0">Perhaps the Creator of the Genre</h2>



<p>Lustmord, a pioneer in dark ambient, plunges listeners into the abyss with his atmospheric compositions. His album &#8220;Heresy&#8221; serves as a prime example of his artistry and occult leanings. The track &#8220;Black Star&#8221; combines deep, resonant drones with haunting vocal samples. It conjures a sense of cosmic dread and the mysteries of the void. Lustmord&#8217;s work transcends conventional music, inviting listeners to explore the recesses of their psyche and confront their deepest fears.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-coil-a-pioneering-bands-of-dark-ambient">Coil, a Pioneering Bands of Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>Coil, with their multifaceted exploration of occult themes, has made an indelible mark on dark ambient. Their seminal album &#8220;The Ape of Naples&#8221; stands as a testament to their artistic vision and occult fascinations. &#8220;Fire of the Mind&#8221; and &#8220;Going Up&#8221; delve into themes of ritualistic transformation and spiritual transcendence. The hypnotic rhythms, cryptic lyrics and subtle references to esoteric symbolism, create a disruptive atmosphere. It blurs the boundaries between the sacred and the profane.</p>



<p>&#8220;Musick to Play in the Dark Vol. 1,&#8221; delves into the mystical realms with tracks like &#8220;Are You Shivering?&#8221;. The track &#8220;Red Birds Will Fly Out of the East and Destroy Paris in a Night.&#8221; can be terrifying. These compositions traverse the depths of the subconscious, enveloping the listener in an arcane soundscape. Coil&#8217;s music often acts as a portal, allowing us to glimpse the hidden dimensions beyond the veil. Dark Ambient becomes the void.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s and Lustmord&#8217;s music, through their albums and songs, offer glimpses into the occult. They transport us to liminal spaces where the veils between worlds are thin, inviting us to explore our subconscious. They force confrontation between the endless mysteries that lie within.</p>



<p>In Coil&#8217;s work, the occult themes can be interpreted as metaphors for personal transformation. Often, spiritual enlightenment and the quest for hidden knowledge can be felt.. Their music becomes a vessel through which the listener can embark on a transformative journey. Encouraging listeners to shed old limitations and embracing the unknown is clearly a goal.</p>



<p>Lustmord&#8217;s compositions immerse us in the depths of cosmic and primordial forces. The occult themes in his work can be seen as gateways to existential contemplation. We confront the vastness and mysteries of the universe. They invite us to embrace the terrifying beauty of the unknown and find solace in the abyss.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-occult-themes-in-dark-ambient-0">Occult Themes in Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The occult themes within dark ambient music serve as gateways to introspection, transformation, and the exploration of the unknown. They act as sonic manifestations of esoteric philosophies, arcane rituals, and the interplay between light and darkness.</p>



<p>Dark ambient music, with its atmospheric textures and occult themes, offers a sonic journey into the enigmatic depths of existence. Coil and Lustmord, through their pioneering works, have reshaped the genre and expanded its sonic boundaries. By exploring specific albums and songs, we can interpret the occult themes as invitations. They encourage us to delve into our subconscious, confront our fears, and embrace the transformative power of the unknown. Dark ambient remains an immersive and profound genre, providing a sonic sanctuary for those who seek solace in the shadows.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-drugs-and-dark-ambient-0">Drugs and Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The band Coil and the artist Lustmord have both mentioned or discussed LSD (Lysergic acid diethylamide) in various interviews. They are not shy about their explorations of the psyche.</p>



<p>Coil, known for their openness about their exploration of altered states of consciousness have made references to LSD in interviews. They have discussed the influence of LSD on their creative process and their experiences with the psychedelic substance. It is worth noting that Coil&#8217;s interests extended beyond just LSD, including wide range of psychedelic substances and esoteric practices.</p>



<p>Lustmord has referenced LSD in interviews. He has discussed the influence of psychedelics on his creative work and their potential for expanding consciousness and perception.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion-0">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Coil and Lustmord have embraced a multidimensional approach to their art, drawing inspiration from various sources. These include altered states of consciousness induced by substances like LSD. These references often highlight the transformative potential of psychedelics and their impact on the creative process.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed aligncenter is-type-wp-embed is-provider-live-coil-archive wp-block-embed-live-coil-archive"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5FZDWZFffE"><a href="https://live-coil-archive.com/">The Live COIL Archive</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Live COIL Archive&#8221; &#8212; Live COIL Archive" src="https://live-coil-archive.com/embed/#?secret=btplqr1FWV#?secret=5FZDWZFffE" data-secret="5FZDWZFffE" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://www.lustmord.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.lustmord.com/</a></p>



<div id="wi999"><div class="sq_wiki_content" style="position: relative;clear: both;background: white;font-size: 14px;color: #333;max-width: 500px;margin: 5px auto 5px auto;padding: 13px;border: 1px solid #DDD;-webkit-box-shadow: 0 1px 0 #DDD;-moz-box-shadow: 0 1px 0 #ddd;box-shadow: 0 1px 0 #DDD;"><a id="w_0" class="sq_wiki" href="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_ambient" title="Dark ambient" style="display: block;font-weight: 700;color: #0074B7;line-height: 1.4em;margin-bottom: 5px;text-decoration: none;">Dark ambient</a><div class="sq_wiki_text" style="font-style:italic;color: #333;"><span class="searchmatch">Dark</span> <span class="searchmatch">ambient</span> (referred to as <span class="searchmatch">ambient</span> industrial especially in the 1980s) is a genre of post-industrial music that features an ominous, <span class="searchmatch">dark</span> droning and</div></div></div><div><br style="clear:both" /></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">927</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Symbiosis of Sensations: Frisson and Dark Ambient Music</title>
		<link>/the-symbiosis-of-sensations-exploring-asmr-frissons-and-dark-ambient-music/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kalei Gawd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 22:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/the-symbiosis-of-sensations-exploring-asmr-frissons-and-dark-ambient-music/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Frisson and ASMR In the vast and intricate world of sensory experiences, certain phenomena and artistic expressions intertwine to create unique and profound moments of perception. This blog post delves into the captivating realms of ASMR (Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response), frissons (chills or tingling sensations), dark ambient music, the band Coil, and their intriguing connections to LSD, ketamine, and the occultist Aleister Crowley. Prepare to embark on a journey that intertwines the ethereal, the sensory, and the mystical. ASMR: Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response ASMR, a phenomenon characterized by pleasurable tingling sensations that typically originate from auditory or visual stimuli, has &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-frisson-and-asmr">Frisson and ASMR</h2>



<p>In the vast and intricate world of sensory experiences, certain phenomena and artistic expressions intertwine to create unique and profound moments of perception. This blog post delves into the captivating realms of ASMR (Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response), frissons (chills or tingling sensations), dark ambient music, the band Coil, and their intriguing connections to LSD, ketamine, and the occultist Aleister Crowley. Prepare to embark on a journey that intertwines the ethereal, the sensory, and the mystical.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-asmr-autonomous-sensory-meridian-response">ASMR: Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response</h2>



<p>ASMR, a phenomenon characterized by pleasurable tingling sensations that typically originate from auditory or visual stimuli, has captivated millions around the world. It can induce a deeply relaxing and euphoric state, often described as a &#8220;brain massage.&#8221; Frissons, on the other hand, are sudden and intense waves of pleasurable shivers, often accompanied by goosebumps. These sensations can be triggered by various stimuli, including music, art, or emotionally charged moments.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-dark-ambient-atmosphere">Dark Ambient Atmosphere</h2>



<p>Dark ambient music, with its atmospheric textures and haunting soundscapes, forms an ideal conduit for inducing ASMR and frissons. This genre embraces dissonance, hypnotic rhythms, and atmospheric layers to create immersive sonic experiences. The combination of sonic elements, such as deep drones, ethereal melodies, and intricate sound design, acts as a catalyst for sensory exploration and emotional resonance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-coil">Coil</h2>



<p>The influential band Coil, with their enigmatic and eclectic musical approach, ventured into the realms of dark ambient music. Their fascination with altered states of consciousness and occultism manifested in their sonic tapestries. While Coil didn&#8217;t explicitly create ASMR-inducing content, their music&#8217;s immersive nature and intricate layers have the potential to trigger such sensations in receptive individuals.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-chemical-frisson-and-asmr">Chemical Frisson and ASMR</h2>



<p>LSD and ketamine, both psychedelic substances, have long been associated with expanded consciousness, altered perception, and spiritual exploration. LSD, known for its hallucinogenic properties, can induce profound sensory experiences, heightening the perception of sound and visual stimuli. Ketamine, a dissociative anesthetic, can create a sense of detachment from the body and facilitate introspection. These psychedelics seem to enhance the frisson and ASMR experience.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s members, particularly John Balance, openly discussed their experiences with psychedelic substances, including LSD and ketamine. Their music often reflects their fascination with altered states of mind, occultism, and mysticism. While Coil&#8217;s work is not explicitly about psychedelics, their explorations and their ability to create immersive and introspective sonic environments resonated with individuals who have had similar psychedelic experiences.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-obligatory-crowley-mention">Obligatory Crowley Mention</h2>



<p>Aleister Crowley, an influential occultist, left an indelible mark on Coil&#8217;s philosophical and artistic endeavors. Crowley&#8217;s teachings, which encompassed ceremonial magick, symbolism, and esoteric philosophy, found resonance within Coil&#8217;s esoteric interests. While not directly related to ASMR or frissons, Crowley&#8217;s occult legacy contributed to the band&#8217;s exploration of transcendent experiences and their desire to unravel the mysteries of consciousness.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-summary">Summary</h2>



<p>These phenomena and influences offer gateways to altered states of consciousness, introspection, and the pursuit of the numinous. Whether through the soothing whispers of ASMR, the haunting melodies of dark ambient music, or the transcendence facilitated by psychedelic substances and occult teachings, these experiences remind us of the profound and intricate nature of our senses and the mysteries that lie beyond.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">923</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devo: The Contributions of these Legendary Pioneers</title>
		<link>/devo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kalei Gawd]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 19:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=66</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pioneering Sound The American new wave band  Devo, formed in the 1970s, has had a significant influence on music, art, and popular culture. Known for their unique sound, satirical lyrics, and distinctive visual style, Devo emerged as one of the pioneers of the new wave movement and played a vital role in shaping the alternative music scene. We Are Devo Devo&#8217;s music blended punk rock, electronic elements, and unconventional song structures, creating a sound that was both catchy and experimental. Their breakthrough came with the release of their debut album, &#8220;Q: Are We Not Men? A: We Are Devo!&#8221; in &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Pioneering Sound</p>



<p>The American new wave band  <strong>Devo</strong>, formed in the 1970s, has had a significant influence on music, art, and popular culture. Known for their unique sound, satirical lyrics, and distinctive visual style, Devo emerged as one of the pioneers of the new wave movement and played a vital role in shaping the alternative music scene.</p>



<p>We Are Devo</p>



<p>Devo&#8217;s music blended punk rock, electronic elements, and unconventional song structures, creating a sound that was both catchy and experimental. Their breakthrough came with the release of their debut album, &#8220;Q: Are We Not Men? A: We Are Devo!&#8221; in 1978, produced by Brian Eno. The album&#8217;s quirky yet accessible tracks, such as &#8220;Jocko Homo&#8221; and a cover of the Rolling Stones&#8217; &#8220;Satisfaction,&#8221; showcased Devo&#8217;s deconstructive approach to music, questioning societal norms and consumer culture.</p>



<p>Style</p>



<p>In addition to their music, Devo&#8217;s visual aesthetic played a crucial role in their influence. The band members adopted a distinct look, donning yellow hazmat suits, energy dome hats, and robotic movements, which became iconic symbols of their image. This visually striking and robotic appearance served as a critique of conformity and the dehumanizing effects of modern society.</p>



<p>Wry Wit and Religion, Too.</p>



<p>Devo&#8217;s artistic endeavors extended beyond music and into various other mediums. One notable collaboration was their association with the Church of the SubGenius, a satirical religious organization founded in the late 1970s. The Church of the SubGenius promoted a humorous critique of mainstream culture and claimed to offer salvation through a parody of traditional religion. Devo&#8217;s involvement with the Church was primarily in the form of performing at SubGenius events and incorporating SubGenius themes into their work.</p>



<p>Devo&#8217;s connection to the Church of the SubGenius further solidified their status as countercultural figures, as both entities shared a similar satirical approach to questioning authority and cultural norms. Through their collaboration, Devo contributed to the spread of the SubGenius philosophy and helped expose it to a wider audience.</p>



<p>Conclusion</p>



<p>Overall, Devo&#8217;s influence can be seen in their unique music, subversive imagery, and collaborations with the Church of the SubGenius. They challenged the conventions of popular culture, delivering thought-provoking social commentary through their music and aesthetic choices. Their impact on subsequent generations of musicians, artists, and fans is evident in the continued appreciation for their innovative approach and their lasting legacy in the alternative music landscape.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">66</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
