<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Philosophy &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/philosophy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 22:32:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Philosophy &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Exploring Symbolic and Quantum Parallels</title>
		<link>/technoshamanism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tobit]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 14:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychedelia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technoshamanism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technoshamanism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/exploring-symbolic-and-quantum-parallels-the-unicursal-hexagram-yin-yang-and-quantum-philosophy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Similarities in Symbolism The unicursal hexagram of Thelema and the Eastern Yin Yang symbol offer insightful philosophical parallels with the intriguing principles of quantum physics, particularly resonating with Niels Bohr’s concept of complementarity. This union gives birth to technoshamanism. The Yin Yang and Quantum Theory: In the Yin Yang’s flowing, interconnected nature, we see a reflection of the unicursal hexagram’s depiction of inseparable, opposing forces. This symbolic resonance is mirrored in the realm of quantum theory, where subatomic particles exist in a probabilistic haze, oscillating between contradictory states such as wave and particle, influenced by observation. This &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-similarities-in-symbolism">Similarities in Symbolism</h2>



<p>The unicursal hexagram of Thelema and the Eastern Yin Yang symbol offer insightful philosophical parallels with the intriguing principles of quantum physics, particularly resonating with Niels Bohr’s concept of complementarity. This union gives birth to technoshamanism.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-yin-yang-and-quantum-theory"><strong>The Yin Yang and Quantum Theory:</strong></h2>



<p>In the Yin Yang’s flowing, interconnected nature, we see a reflection of the unicursal hexagram’s depiction of inseparable, opposing forces. This symbolic resonance is mirrored in the realm of quantum theory, where subatomic particles exist in a probabilistic haze, oscillating between contradictory states such as wave and particle, influenced by observation. This phenomenon of quantum indeterminacy collapsing upon measurement parallels the Yin Yang, which beautifully illustrates the interdependence and mutual definition of seemingly opposite forces.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-unicursal-hexagram-and-connection-of-opposites"><strong>The Unicursal Hexagram and Connection of Opposites</strong></h2>



<p>The unicursal hexagram, representing the unity of opposites, resonates deeply with the principles of technoshamanism. This symbol&#8217;s depiction of interconnected forces is reflective of how technoshamanism aims to merge the mystical with the technological, suggesting that the ancient wisdom embodied in such symbols can inform and enrich our understanding of modern scientific concepts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-heisenberg-s-uncertainty-and-symbolic-parallels"><strong>Heisenberg’s Uncertainty and Symbolic Parallels:</strong></h2>



<p>Moreover, Heisenberg’s uncertainty principle, a cornerstone of quantum mechanics, states that precision in measuring one quantum property inherently limits knowledge of its complement. This concept finds a symbolic parallel in the Yin Yang, where each aspect contains and engenders the other in a perpetual, interwoven dance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-transcending-dualism"><strong>Transcending Dualism:</strong></h2>



<p>Additionally, both the unicursal hexagram and the Yin Yang transcend traditional dualistic perspectives. They reflect the counterintuitive nature of the quantum world, where particles don’t possess a singular, defined state but exist across a spectrum of probable characteristics. This aligns with a holistic view, moving beyond binary divisions to embrace a complex interplay of complementary forces. These symbols and quantum principles collectively challenge the classical, deterministic understanding of the universe, advocating for a more probabilistic and paradoxical interpretation. The unicursal hexagram and Yin Yang symbolize that apparent contradictions in existence are not at odds but rather form an interconnected, nuanced whole. They exemplify how opposites are generative, not negating, weaving together the complex tapestry of existence. Embracing these relationships, as illustrated by both symbols, aligns us with the harmonious nature of the universe, echoing the counterintuitive insights of the uncertainty principle.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-thelema-s-principle-of-0-2"><strong>Thelema’s Principle of 0=2:</strong></h2>



<p>The Thelemic principle of 0=2, deeply rooted in Aleister Crowley’s mystical system, provides a unique philosophical underpinning that complements the themes discussed in this article. At its core, this principle embodies the concept of unity emerging from duality, a fundamental tenet in Thelemic philosophy. The equation 0=2, in Thelemic thought, symbolizes the idea that the apparent duality of existence (represented by 2) ultimately originates from and returns to a state of non-duality or nothingness (represented by 0). This aligns closely with the concepts in quantum physics, where the seemingly dual nature of particles, as both waves and particles, emerges from a singular, undifferentiated quantum field. Just as the unicursal hexagram and Yin Yang depict the inseparable interplay of opposites, the principle of 0=2 in Thelema suggests that all dualities — light and dark, creation and destruction, positive and negative — are intrinsically connected, emanating from a singular source.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-0-2-and-wave-particle"><strong>0=2 and Wave-Particle:</strong></h2>



<p>In the context of quantum mechanics, one can draw parallels between the Thelemic principle of 0=2 and the wave-particle duality. Just as the 0 represents the undifferentiated, unified field, the number 2 reflects the dual nature of quantum entities. This duality is not a permanent state but rather a manifestation of the underlying unity. It reflects the much like the quantum state of a particle, not fixed until it is observed. This aligns with the Thelemic view that apparent dualities are merely different expressions of a single, underlying reality. Moreover, the principle of 0=2 resonates with the idea of quantum superposition, where particles exist in multiple states simultaneously until measured. In Thelemic philosophy, this can be seen as the myriad manifestations of the universe (the number 2) emerging from the void or the absence of existence (0). It suggests that the universe’s complexities, including its paradoxes and contradictions, are integral aspects of a unified whole, challenging our conventional understanding of separation and distinction.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-technoshamanism-quantum-physics-and-philosophical-symbolism">Technoshamanism: <strong>Quantum Physics and Philosophical Symbolism:</strong></h2>



<p>This philosophical exploration leads us to consider the significant role of metrics in confirming the existence of phenomena, a concept deeply rooted in both quantum mechanics and the interpretation of symbols. In quantum physics, the very act of measuring a particle’s properties – position, momentum, or spin – solidifies its existence in a specific state, transitioning it from a probability to a reality. This principle aligns with the symbolism of the unicursal hexagram and Yin Yang, where the definition of one aspect inherently confirms the existence of its counterpart. Just as the measurement of a quantum particle’s position simultaneously acknowledges the existence of its momentum, the presence of Yin intrinsically confirms the existence of Yang. This interplay of measurement and existence underpins both the mystic symbolism of these ancient icons and the empirical foundations of quantum mechanics, illustrating a profound unity between philosophical concepts and scientific principles. The existence of a metric, be it in physical measurements or symbolic interpretations, serves as a bridge between potentiality and reality, reinforcing the notion that our understanding and observation are integral to the manifestation of existence itself.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-quantum-physics-a-magical-rulebook">Quantum Physics: A Magical Rulebook</h2>



<p>Quantum physics, often perceived as a mystical domain due to its counterintuitive principles, aligns well with the technoshamanic perspective. This field&#8217;s exploration of particles existing in multiple states aligns with the technoshamanic belief in the coexistence of spiritual and physical realms. It posits that technology, when applied with an understanding of shamanic wisdom, can unlock new dimensions of understanding, similar to how the Yin Yang symbol encapsulates the duality yet unity of existence.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-technoshamanism-merging-ancient-mysticism-with-modern-technology">Technoshamanism: Merging Ancient Mysticism with Modern Technology</h2>



<p>Technoshamanism is a contemporary concept that fuses the ancient practices of shamanism with the advancements of modern technology and science. It embodies the idea that the spiritual insights and rituals of shamans, when integrated with the empirical approach of technology and quantum physics, can lead to a deeper, more holistic understanding of reality. Technoshamans utilize both the symbolic wisdom of traditions, like the unicursal hexagram and the Yin Yang, and the empirical data of quantum mechanics, proposing that this synthesis can offer a more nuanced and interconnected view of the universe. This approach suggests a harmonious blend of spiritual intuition and scientific inquiry, bridging the gap between metaphysical beliefs and technological advancements.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion:</h2>



<p>In conclusion, the integration of the unicursal hexagram, Yin Yang, and quantum principles presents a compelling view of reality. These concepts advocate for a universe understood not in terms of isolated absolutes but as a network of relational dynamics and potentials. They encourage transcending perceived divisions, viewing existence as a unified, complementary dance. This convergence of ancient symbolism and modern physics suggests a profound truth: existence is fundamentally an interplay of harmonious opposites, a concept now increasingly validated by the advances in quantum mechanics.</p>



<p><a href="https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=t5MohK5FHEY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Nobody explains it better than Professor Farnsworth</strong></a></p>



<p><a href="https://deoxy.org/l_digpol.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Except perhaps Dr. Leary</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eastern Philosophies and Western Religions: Exploring Contrasts and Lessons for Humanity</title>
		<link>/eastern-philosophies-and-western-religions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 01:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/eastern-philosophies-and-western-religions-exploring-contrasts-and-lessons-for-humanity/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout history, humanity has sought answers to profound questions about existence, purpose, and the nature of reality. This quest has led to the development of diverse belief systems and philosophical traditions across the globe. In this post, we will compare the history of Eastern philosophies and Western religions, their evolutionary development, and the establishment of schools and temples, with the Western approach to religion, characterized by politically motivated churches, witch covens, and the Inquisition. By examining these differences, we can glean valuable insights and lessons for humanity&#8217;s collective growth and understanding. Eastern Philosophies: Evolutionary Development and Spiritual &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Throughout history, humanity has sought answers to profound questions about existence, purpose, and the nature of reality. This quest has led to the development of diverse belief systems and philosophical traditions across the globe. In this post, we will compare the history of Eastern philosophies and Western religions, their evolutionary development, and the establishment of schools and temples, with the Western approach to religion, characterized by politically motivated churches, witch covens, and the Inquisition. By examining these differences, we can glean valuable insights and lessons for humanity&#8217;s collective growth and understanding.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-eastern-philosophies-evolutionary-development-and-spiritual-exploration">Eastern Philosophies: Evolutionary Development and Spiritual Exploration</h2>



<p>Eastern philosophies encompass a rich tapestry of thought, including Hinduism, Buddhism, Taoism, and Confucianism, among others. These philosophies originated in ancient times and have evolved through centuries of contemplation and introspection.</p>



<p>One remarkable aspect of Eastern philosophies is their emphasis on spiritual exploration and self-realization. Rather than relying on external authorities or dogmas, these traditions encourage individuals to seek inner wisdom through practices such as meditation, mindfulness, and self-discipline. The schools and temples that emerged from these philosophies became centers of learning and spiritual guidance, fostering a harmonious blend of intellectual pursuit and personal growth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-western-religions-politics-persecution-and-the-dark-shadows">Western Religions: Politics, Persecution, and the Dark Shadows</h2>



<p>In contrast to Eastern philosophies, the history of Western religions, particularly Christianity, has been marred by episodes of political manipulation, persecution, and intolerance. The rise of politically motivated churches, such as the Roman Catholic Church during the Middle Ages, led to the centralization of power, often intertwined with secular authority. This entanglement of religion and politics resulted in a hierarchical structure that sometimes placed the interests of the few above the spiritual well-being of the many.</p>



<p>One particularly dark chapter in Western religious history is the Inquisition. During the Middle Ages and Renaissance, the Inquisition was used as a means to enforce religious orthodoxy and suppress dissenting voices. Countless individuals were persecuted, tortured, and executed, accused of heresy or witchcraft. Witch covens, popularly associated with pagan traditions and nature-based religions, faced similar persecution, with accusations of devil worship and supernatural powers leading to the suffering and death of many innocent people.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-lessons-for-humanity-embracing-tolerance-self-exploration-and-harmony">Lessons for Humanity: Embracing Tolerance, Self-Exploration, and Harmony</h2>



<p>Comparing the histories of Eastern philosophies and Western religions reveals important lessons for humanity. It is crucial to emphasize tolerance, respect, and openness when engaging with differing beliefs and ideas. The emphasis on personal growth and self-exploration in Eastern philosophies offers a path for individuals to develop a deeper understanding of themselves and their place in the world.</p>



<p>Additionally, the examples of politically motivated churches, witch hunts, and the Inquisition serve as cautionary tales about the dangers of power and dogmatism. Humanity must strive to separate spiritual exploration from the manipulation of politics and power. The freedom to express one&#8217;s beliefs and engage in dialogue fosters an environment of intellectual growth, mutual understanding, and compassion.</p>



<p>Furthermore, embracing the diversity of spiritual practices can enrich our collective understanding of the human experience. By studying and appreciating various philosophies and religions, we can discover commonalities, explore different perspectives, and build bridges of understanding.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-conclusions">Conclusions:</h2>



<p>The comparison of Eastern philosophies and Western religions highlights the evolutionary development and contrasting approaches to spirituality. While Eastern philosophies promote self-exploration and personal growth, Western religions have faced challenges arising from political motivations and persecution.</p>



<p>Humanity can learn valuable lessons from this comparison by embracing tolerance, openness, and self-exploration. We must strive to separate religion from politics, nurturing an environment where diverse beliefs can coexist harmoniously. By fostering such an environment, we can encourage intellectual growth, mutual respect, and compassion among individuals of different faiths and philosophies.</p>



<p>In our modern world, it is essential to recognize the inherent value of diversity in belief systems. Instead of viewing differences as threats or challenges to one&#8217;s own faith, we should embrace them as opportunities for personal growth and collective enlightenment. Just as Eastern philosophies have thrived through their acceptance of multiple paths to spiritual realization, we can also appreciate the richness and depth that different religious traditions bring to the tapestry of human existence.</p>



<p>Moreover, the history of politically motivated churches, witch hunts, and the Inquisition serves as a reminder of the dangers of religious extremism and the abuse of power. It compels us to question the influence of political agendas within religious institutions and to safeguard against the suppression of individual freedoms and the persecution of those with differing beliefs.</p>



<p>By promoting dialogue, education, and interfaith understanding, we can break down the barriers that separate us and foster a sense of unity and shared purpose. Humanity can draw inspiration from the wisdom and teachings of Eastern philosophies, which encourage introspection, compassion, and the pursuit of inner harmony.</p>



<p>The comparison between Eastern philosophies and Western religions offers valuable insights and lessons for humanity. By embracing tolerance, self-exploration, and harmonious coexistence, we can create a world where diverse beliefs are celebrated and where spiritual growth is nurtured. Let us strive to learn from history and work towards a future where respect, compassion, and understanding are the guiding principles that unite us in our quest for meaning and purpose.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sigmund Freud and Carl Jung: Contributions to Contemporary Occultist Thought</title>
		<link>/sigmund-freud-and-carl-jung-contributions-to-contemporary-occultist-thought/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 15:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Both Sigmund Freud and Carl Jung have had a significant impact on contemporary occultism, including their ideas on dreams, the unconscious mind, and the collective unconscious. These psychological concepts have found resonance and integration within modern occult systems, including Thelema and chaos magick. Let&#8217;s explore this influence and overlap in more detail: 1. Freud and Dreams: Freud proposed that dreams are a gateway to the unconscious mind, containing hidden desires, repressed thoughts, and symbolic representations of unresolved conflicts. His psychoanalytic approach to dream interpretation emphasized the role of personal unconscious material, such as sexual and aggressive instincts, &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Both Sigmund Freud and Carl Jung have had a significant impact on contemporary occultism, including their ideas on dreams, the unconscious mind, and the collective unconscious. These psychological concepts have found resonance and integration within modern occult systems, including Thelema and chaos magick. Let&#8217;s explore this influence and overlap in more detail:</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">1. Freud and Dreams:</p>



<p><br />Freud proposed that dreams are a gateway to the unconscious mind, containing hidden desires, repressed thoughts, and symbolic representations of unresolved conflicts. His psychoanalytic approach to dream interpretation emphasized the role of personal unconscious material, such as sexual and aggressive instincts, in shaping dream content. Freud&#8217;s work on dreams has influenced contemporary occultism by highlighting the importance of exploring the symbolic and subconscious dimensions of the human psyche.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">In Thelema:</p>



<p><br />In Thelema, the exploration of dreams and their interpretation plays a role in understanding one&#8217;s True Will, personal desires, and subconscious motivations. Aleister Crowley, the founder of Thelema, recognized the significance of dreams as a source of insight and guidance in aligning with one&#8217;s True Will. Thelemites often engage in practices such as dream journaling, lucid dreaming, and ritual work to enhance dream recall, interpretation, and integration into their spiritual journey.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">2. Jung and the Collective Unconscious:</p>



<p><br />Jung expanded on Freud&#8217;s ideas and introduced the concept of the collective unconscious, which he believed contains universal, archetypal patterns and symbols shared by all humanity. Jung argued that these collective archetypes are reflected in myths, folklore, and dreams across cultures and have a profound influence on human behavior and spiritual experiences. His work emphasized the idea of individuation, the process of integrating the conscious and unconscious aspects of the self.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">In Thelema:</p>



<p><br />Jung&#8217;s concept of the collective unconscious resonates with Thelema&#8217;s view of universal archetypes and symbols. Thelema recognizes the existence of archetypal forces, such as the Egyptian deities in the pantheon of Nuit, Hadit, and Ra-Hoor-Khuit. These archetypes are believed to represent aspects of the human psyche and serve as catalysts for personal transformation and spiritual evolution. Thelemites may explore these archetypes through ritual, meditation, and visualization to connect with deeper layers of the self and tap into collective spiritual currents.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">3. Contemporary Occultism and Psychological Paradigms:</p>



<p><br />Contemporary occult systems, including chaos magick, have embraced psychological paradigms influenced by Freud and Jung. Chaos magick, in particular, places a strong emphasis on individual belief, personal gnosis, and the manipulation of subjective experience. It draws from a diverse range of psychological models, including aspects of psychoanalysis, to inform its practices.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">In Chaos Magick:</p>



<p><br />Chaos magick incorporates psychological techniques, such as sigilization and visualization, to reprogram the subconscious mind and manifest desired outcomes. The psychological concepts of Freud and Jung, including dream analysis, symbolism, and the exploration of the unconscious, can be integrated into chaos magick practices to enhance the efficacy of ritual work, self-transformation, and personal evolution.</p>



<p>Freud and Jung&#8217;s ideas on dreams, the unconscious mind, and the collective unconscious have influenced contemporary occultism by providing frameworks for understanding the depths of the human psyche and its spiritual dimensions. These concepts have found resonance and practical application within Thelema and chaos magick, enriching their practices with psychological insights, dreamwork, and the exploration of archetypal forces.</p>



<span id="more-110"></span>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
