<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Enochian Magick &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/magick/enochian-magick/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 17:28:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Enochian Magick &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">222527107</site>	<item>
		<title>The Dynamic Duo: John Dee, Edward Kelly, and Their Profound Influence on Occultism</title>
		<link>/the-dynamic-duo-john-dee-edward-kelly-and-their-profound-influence-on-occultism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 20:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chaos Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enochian Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The realm of occultism has always enticed and intrigued seekers of hidden knowledge throughout history. Within this realm, the partnership between John Dee and Edward Kelly stands as a remarkable chapter. Their unique collaboration, the church&#8217;s view on their work, their influence on Aleister Crowley, and their impact on chaos magick and modern occultism overall deserve closer examination. 1. The Profound Partnership: In the late 16th century, John Dee, an esteemed English mathematician, philosopher, and astrologer, met Edward Kelly, an alchemist and medium from Bohemia (now the Czech Republic). Their partnership began in 1582 when Kelly claimed &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The realm of occultism has always enticed and intrigued seekers of hidden knowledge throughout history. Within this realm, the partnership between John Dee and Edward Kelly stands as a remarkable chapter. Their unique collaboration, the church&#8217;s view on their work, their influence on Aleister Crowley, and their impact on chaos magick and modern occultism overall deserve closer examination.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>1. The Profound Partnership:</strong></p>



<p><br>In the late 16th century, John Dee, an esteemed English mathematician, philosopher, and astrologer, met Edward Kelly, an alchemist and medium from Bohemia (now the Czech Republic). Their partnership began in 1582 when Kelly claimed to be able to communicate with angels. Dee saw an opportunity to unlock divine knowledge and supported Kelly as his seer.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>2. The Church&#8217;s Perception:</strong></p>



<p><br>During this period, the church held considerable power and influence. Dee and Kelly&#8217;s work often drew suspicion and scrutiny. They were accused of engaging in forbidden practices, particularly by Catholic authorities. The church feared their activities could challenge traditional religious structures and doctrines.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>3. Aleister Crowley&#8217;s Influence:</strong></p>



<p><br>Dee and Kelly&#8217;s work, particularly their attempt to communicate with angelic beings through a crystal or &#8220;scrying&#8221; mirror, deeply fascinated Aleister Crowley. Crowley, widely regarded as the influential figure in 20th-century occultism and the founder of Thelema, adopted many concepts from Dee&#8217;s and Kelly&#8217;s practices. Crowley saw himself as the successor of Dee and inherited their exploration of the spiritual world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>4. Impact on Chaos Magick:</strong></p>



<p><br>Chaos magick, a modern occult practice aiming to tap into personal power and change reality, drew inspiration from the works of Dee and Kelly. The chaos magick movement saw ritualistic structures as mere tools for the manipulation of reality, and thus, drew on the elemental power Dee and Kelly possessed. The fluidity and innovation inherent in chaos magick stemmed from the spirit of experimentation pioneered by these two historical figures.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>5. Influence on Modern Occultism:</strong></p>



<p><br>John Dee and Edward Kelly fundamentally shaped modern occultism in numerous ways. Their practices and beliefs opened the door to alternative modes of spirituality and the exploration of non-traditional avenues. Their approach to ritual, scrying, and spirit communication challenged established religious practices and dogmas, paving the way for an increasingly pluralistic and diverse occult landscape.</p>



<p>The partnership between John Dee and Edward Kelly not only pioneered new spiritual practices but also challenged the religious establishment of their time. Their controversial endeavors and unorthodox paths deeply influenced the likes of Aleister Crowley, the rise of chaos magick, and modern occultism as a whole. In today&#8217;s world, their legacy lives on as a symbol of the unyielding human pursuit of esoteric wisdom and the enduring impact of their contribution to the ever-evolving occult tradition.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">112</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unveiling the Mysteries of Enochian Magic: History, Application, and Lasting Influence</title>
		<link>/enochian-magick/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enochian Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=78</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Enochian Magick, a complex system of occult practice, has captivated the minds of magicians, scholars, and occult enthusiasts for centuries. Rooted in the communication with angels and exploration of higher realms, Enochian Magick is a unique aspect of Western esotericism. In this essay, we will explore the history, application, practice, and philosophy of Enochian Magic. We will also touch on it&#8217;s profound influence on future occult schools of thought. History of Enochian Magick Enochian Magick traces its origins to the late 16th century. Attributed to the English occultists Dr. John Dee, and his scryer Edward Kelley. Dee, &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-left">Enochian Magick, a complex system of occult practice, has captivated the minds of magicians, scholars, and occult enthusiasts for centuries. Rooted in the communication with angels and exploration of higher realms, Enochian Magick is a unique aspect of Western esotericism. In this essay, we will explore the history, application, practice, and philosophy of Enochian Magic. We will also touch on it&#8217;s profound influence on future occult schools of thought.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-history-of-enochian-magick">History of Enochian Magick</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Enochian Magick traces its origins to the late 16th century. Attributed to the English occultists Dr. John Dee, and his scryer Edward Kelley. Dee, a mathematician, astronomer, and advisor to Queen Elizabeth I and Sir Edward Kelly, a scryer.  They claimed to have received a complex system of angelic communication and magical practices. Their information was said to originate with celestial entities, including the language of angels called Enochian.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-application-and-practice-of-enochian-magic"><strong>Application and Practice of Enochian Magic</strong></h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-a-angelic-communication"><br><strong>a. Angelic Communication: </strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">At the core of Enochian Magick is the belief that practitioners can communicate with higher intelligences, specifically angelic beings. Dee and Kelley believed that the angelic language, Enochian, provided access to profound spiritual insights. It gave them access to divinatory knowledge, and practical magical operations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br><strong>b. The Heptarchia Mystica: </strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">One significant aspect of Enochian Magick is the Heptarchia Mystica, a system of planetary and angelic invocations. It involves invoking and working with the seven planetary angelic governors and their associated forces. By harnessing their powers for various purposes, a new form of magick was evolved.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br><strong>c. Elemental Tablets and Watchtower System: </strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Enochian Magick incorporates a complex system of elemental tablets and watchtowers, representing different regions of the spiritual and physical realms. Practitioners use these tools to establish contact with various entities, invoke energies, and perform rituals.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong>Philosophy of Enochian Magic</strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br><strong>a. Cosmology: </strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Enochian Magick encompasses a unique cosmology involving hierarchical spiritual realms, angelic hierarchies, and the interplay between different planes of existence. It emphasizes the exploration and harmonization of these realms for spiritual growth and magical power.</p>



<p><br><strong>b. Divine Language and Harmonics: </strong></p>



<p>Enochian Magick holds that the angelic language, Enochian, possesses inherent vibrational power and harmony.  Use of this language and its accompanying rituals is believed to resonate with divine frequencies, facilitating contact with angelic forces.</p>



<p><br>c. Ascension and Spiritual Evolution: Enochian Magick promotes the idea of spiritual evolution and ascension through the exploration of higher realms. Practitioners seek to elevate their consciousness, refine their spiritual faculties, and attain a state of unity with divine forces.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-influence-of-john-dee-and-enochian-works-on-future-occult-schools-of-thought"><strong>Influence of John Dee and Enochian works on Future Occult Schools of Thought</strong></h2>



<p><br>Enochian Magick has left a profound impact on various occult schools of thought, inspiring and influencing practitioners and scholars alike. Some notable areas of influence include:</p>



<p><br><strong>a. The Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn: </strong></p>



<p>Enochian Magick played a significant role in the rituals and teachings of the Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn. It contributed to their understanding of angelic forces, symbolism, and ritual practices.</p>



<p><br>b. Thelema and Aleister Crowley: </p>



<p>Thelema, a system of spiritual and magical practice, draws upon Enochian Magick as an integral part of its ceremonial practices. Enochian elements can be found in Crowley&#8217;s rituals and his exploration of angelic communication.</p>



<p><br><strong>c. Modern Magick and Eclectic Traditions:</strong></p>



<p> Enochian Magick continues to influence modern magickal systems and eclectic occult traditions. Many contemporary practitioners incorporate Enochian techniques, rituals, and symbiology into their magical practices. The flexibility and adaptability of Enochian Magick make it a valuable resource. Those seeking to incorporate angelic communication and higher realms rely on it still today.</p>



<p>Additionally, the study of Enochian Magick has had a lasting impact on academic and scholarly circles. Its complex system of angelic communication, symbolism, and cosmology has sparked extensive research and exploration. Scholars continue to analyze and interpret the texts and manuscripts. Study sheds light on its historical context and its influence on occultism.</p>



<p>Moreover, Enochian Magick&#8217;s emphasis on angelic communication and the exploration of higher realms. This resonates with broader themes found in various mystical and spiritual traditions.  The concept of connecting with higher intelligences to seek insight is seen in different cultural and religious contexts throughout history.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-closing">Closing</h2>



<p>Enochian Magick stands as a remarkable and enduring aspect of Western esotericism. Its history, application, practice, and philosophy provide a rich tapestry of knowledge and insight into the realms of angelic communication. Its influence on future occult schools of thought, like Golden Dawn and Thelema, showcases the impact of this magical system. Practitioners and scholars continue exploring the depths of angelic Magick. Its mysteries and wisdom continue to unfold, inviting individuals to embark on their own personal journeys.</p>



<p>An article I found particularly useful (used without permission &#8211; if the author minds, I will instantly remove the link):</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-heterodoxology wp-block-embed-heterodoxology"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="C4i5sbxnKI"><a href="https://heterodoxology.com/2010/05/29/an-etiology-of-angelic-vision-article-on-john-dee-and-edward-kelly-in-aries/">An etiology of angelic vision: Article on John Dee and Edward Kelly in&nbsp;Aries</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;An etiology of angelic vision: Article on John Dee and Edward Kelly in&nbsp;Aries&#8221; &#8212; Heterodoxology" src="https://heterodoxology.com/2010/05/29/an-etiology-of-angelic-vision-article-on-john-dee-and-edward-kelly-in-aries/embed/#?secret=szcYNCSBUm#?secret=C4i5sbxnKI" data-secret="C4i5sbxnKI" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">78</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
