<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Chaos Magick &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/magick/chaos-magick/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 20:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Chaos Magick &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Dynamic Duo: John Dee, Edward Kelly, and Their Profound Influence on Occultism</title>
		<link>/the-dynamic-duo-john-dee-edward-kelly-and-their-profound-influence-on-occultism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 20:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chaos Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enochian Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The realm of occultism has always enticed and intrigued seekers of hidden knowledge throughout history. Within this realm, the partnership between John Dee and Edward Kelly stands as a remarkable chapter. Their unique collaboration, the church&#8217;s view on their work, their influence on Aleister Crowley, and their impact on chaos magick and modern occultism overall deserve closer examination. 1. The Profound Partnership: In the late 16th century, John Dee, an esteemed English mathematician, philosopher, and astrologer, met Edward Kelly, an alchemist and medium from Bohemia (now the Czech Republic). Their partnership began in 1582 when Kelly claimed &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The realm of occultism has always enticed and intrigued seekers of hidden knowledge throughout history. Within this realm, the partnership between John Dee and Edward Kelly stands as a remarkable chapter. Their unique collaboration, the church&#8217;s view on their work, their influence on Aleister Crowley, and their impact on chaos magick and modern occultism overall deserve closer examination.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>1. The Profound Partnership:</strong></p>



<p><br>In the late 16th century, John Dee, an esteemed English mathematician, philosopher, and astrologer, met Edward Kelly, an alchemist and medium from Bohemia (now the Czech Republic). Their partnership began in 1582 when Kelly claimed to be able to communicate with angels. Dee saw an opportunity to unlock divine knowledge and supported Kelly as his seer.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>2. The Church&#8217;s Perception:</strong></p>



<p><br>During this period, the church held considerable power and influence. Dee and Kelly&#8217;s work often drew suspicion and scrutiny. They were accused of engaging in forbidden practices, particularly by Catholic authorities. The church feared their activities could challenge traditional religious structures and doctrines.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>3. Aleister Crowley&#8217;s Influence:</strong></p>



<p><br>Dee and Kelly&#8217;s work, particularly their attempt to communicate with angelic beings through a crystal or &#8220;scrying&#8221; mirror, deeply fascinated Aleister Crowley. Crowley, widely regarded as the influential figure in 20th-century occultism and the founder of Thelema, adopted many concepts from Dee&#8217;s and Kelly&#8217;s practices. Crowley saw himself as the successor of Dee and inherited their exploration of the spiritual world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>4. Impact on Chaos Magick:</strong></p>



<p><br>Chaos magick, a modern occult practice aiming to tap into personal power and change reality, drew inspiration from the works of Dee and Kelly. The chaos magick movement saw ritualistic structures as mere tools for the manipulation of reality, and thus, drew on the elemental power Dee and Kelly possessed. The fluidity and innovation inherent in chaos magick stemmed from the spirit of experimentation pioneered by these two historical figures.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>5. Influence on Modern Occultism:</strong></p>



<p><br>John Dee and Edward Kelly fundamentally shaped modern occultism in numerous ways. Their practices and beliefs opened the door to alternative modes of spirituality and the exploration of non-traditional avenues. Their approach to ritual, scrying, and spirit communication challenged established religious practices and dogmas, paving the way for an increasingly pluralistic and diverse occult landscape.</p>



<p>The partnership between John Dee and Edward Kelly not only pioneered new spiritual practices but also challenged the religious establishment of their time. Their controversial endeavors and unorthodox paths deeply influenced the likes of Aleister Crowley, the rise of chaos magick, and modern occultism as a whole. In today&#8217;s world, their legacy lives on as a symbol of the unyielding human pursuit of esoteric wisdom and the enduring impact of their contribution to the ever-evolving occult tradition.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chaos Magick: Unleashing the Power of the Unpredictable</title>
		<link>/chaos-magick-unleashing-the-power-of-the-unpredictable-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chaos Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=76</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the realm of occultism, few movements have caused as much disruption and controversy as Chaos Magick. Emerging in the late 20th century, Chaos Magick introduced a radical departure from traditional occult systems, emphasizing individuality, experimentation, and a pragmatic approach to magic. This blog post will delve into the origins of Chaos Magick, its core principles, and how it differs from other systems of magick. We will also explore the contributions of Discordianism, the Church of the Subgenius, as well as influential intellectuals like Timothy Leary and Robert Anton Wilson, who shook up society with their ideas. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the realm of occultism, few movements have caused as much disruption and controversy as Chaos Magick. Emerging in the late 20th century, Chaos Magick introduced a radical departure from traditional occult systems, emphasizing individuality, experimentation, and a pragmatic approach to magic. This blog post will delve into the origins of Chaos Magick, its core principles, and how it differs from other systems of magick. We will also explore the contributions of Discordianism, the Church of the Subgenius, as well as influential intellectuals like Timothy Leary and Robert Anton Wilson, who shook up society with their ideas.</p>



<p>The Birth of Chaos Magick:<br />Chaos Magick emerged in the 1970s as a response to the rigid dogmas and hierarchical structures present in traditional occult practices. It draws inspiration from diverse sources such as Aleister Crowley&#8217;s Thelema, Austin Osman Spare&#8217;s sigil magick, and elements of Eastern philosophy. The seminal work &#8220;Liber Null&#8221; by Peter J. Carroll became a cornerstone of Chaos Magick, outlining its core principles and practices.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Principles of Chaos Magick:</strong></p>



<p><br>1. Paradigm Shifting: Chaos Magick encourages practitioners to adopt a flexible approach by constantly shifting belief systems or &#8220;paradigms&#8221; to achieve desired results. This implies that the practitioner&#8217;s beliefs and symbols are tools rather than ultimate truths.</p>



<p><br>2. Belief as a Tool: Chaos Magick emphasizes that belief is a means to an end. It encourages practitioners to choose beliefs that are personally empowering and conducive to achieving their goals.</p>



<p><br>3. Sigil Magick: Sigilization, inspired by Austin Osman Spare, is a central technique in Chaos Magick. It involves the creation and charging of symbols (sigils) that represent the practitioner&#8217;s intentions. These sigils are then released into the subconscious mind, bypassing the conscious rationality.</p>



<p><br>4. Result-Based Magick: One of the defining features of Chaos Magick is its pragmatic focus on achieving desired results rather than adherence to specific rituals or belief systems. This approach allows practitioners to adapt and experiment with different techniques to find what works best for them.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Result-Based Chaos Magick vs. Other Systems:</strong></p>



<p><br>Compared to other magical systems, Chaos Magick places a greater emphasis on individuality, adaptability, and personal experience. It rejects the notion of an external objective reality and encourages practitioners to explore subjectivity as a source of power. By adopting a result-oriented approach, Chaos Magick dispenses with the need for complex rituals or adherence to particular deities, allowing practitioners to create their own methods based on what brings them desired outcomes.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Influence of Discordianism and the Church of the Subgenius:</strong></p>



<p><br>Discordianism and the Church of the Subgenius have made significant contributions to the discussion surrounding Chaos Magick and modern occultism. Discordianism, founded by Greg Hill and Kerry Thornley, promotes a playful and irreverent approach to spirituality. It challenges fixed beliefs, embraces chaos, and emphasizes the importance of humor in breaking down rigid structures. The Church of the Subgenius, established by Ivan Stang and Philo Drummond, parodies organized religion while advocating for individual freedom, personal mythology, and slack (a state of optimal functioning without undue effort).</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>Intellectual Influencers:</strong></p>



<p><br>Timothy Leary and Robert Anton Wilson played crucial roles in shaking up society through their exploration of mind-altering substances and unconventional philosophies. Leary, a psychologist, promoted the use of psychedelics as a means of expanding consciousness and challenging societal norms. Wilson, on the other hand, explored various mystical and occult traditions, incorporating them into his writings, most notably in the &#8220;Illuminatus!&#8221; trilogy co-authored with Robert Shea. Their works contributed to the countercultural movements of the time and sparked a reevaluation of established belief systems.</p>



<p>Other influential intellectuals who have left a lasting impact on the discussion of Chaos Magick and modern occultism include:</p>



<p>1. Austin Osman Spare: Considered one of the pioneers of Chaos Magick, Spare developed the concept of sigil magick, which became a fundamental practice within Chaos Magick. His emphasis on personal experience and the power of the individual greatly influenced the movement.</p>



<p>2. Alan Moore: Renowned comic book writer and occultist, Moore has incorporated elements of Chaos Magick into his works, such as &#8220;Promethea&#8221; and &#8220;The Invisibles.&#8221; His writings explore the relationship between art, spirituality, and the manipulation of symbols.</p>



<p>3. Grant Morrison: A prolific comic book writer and Chaos Magick practitioner, Morrison has integrated magical concepts and practices into his work, including &#8220;The Invisibles&#8221; and &#8220;Doom Patrol.&#8221; He advocates for the use of imagination and storytelling as tools for transformation.</p>



<p>4. Hakim Bey: Peter Lamborn Wilson, writing under the pseudonym Hakim Bey, introduced the concept of &#8220;Temporary Autonomous Zones&#8221; (TAZ) as spaces of resistance and freedom. His ideas, influenced by anarchism and Sufism, resonate with the Chaos Magick emphasis on individual sovereignty.</p>



<p>5. Phil Hine: A prominent Chaos Magick practitioner and writer, Phil Hine has made significant contributions to the development and understanding of Chaos Magick. His books, such as &#8220;Condensed Chaos&#8221; and &#8220;Prime Chaos,&#8221; provide practical insights and techniques for aspiring practitioners.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>The Impact of Chaos Magick and Modern Occultism:</strong></p>



<p><br>Chaos Magick&#8217;s influence extends beyond the realm of occultism, impacting popular culture, art, and spirituality. Its emphasis on personal empowerment, individuality, and the use of symbolism resonates with a generation seeking alternative paths to self-discovery and personal transformation.</p>



<p>Moreover, Chaos Magick&#8217;s rejection of dogma and its focus on results have allowed for experimentation and innovation in magical practices. This fluid approach has opened doors for practitioners to explore diverse systems, adapt rituals, and blend various traditions to suit their unique needs and desires.</p>



<p>In conclusion, Chaos Magick introduced a disruptive and innovative approach to occultism, challenging established beliefs, and encouraging practitioners to embrace chaos and subjectivity. Result-based Chaos Magick, with its emphasis on personal empowerment and adaptability, sets it apart from other magical systems. Discordianism, the Church of the Subgenius, and influential intellectuals like Timothy Leary and Robert Anton Wilson have contributed to the discussion of Chaos Magick, infusing it with humor, countercultural ideas, and unconventional philosophies. As Chaos Magick continues to evolve, it remains a catalyst for personal exploration and a pathway to unlocking the untapped potential within each practitioner.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
