<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Firsto Lasto &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/93kaleidox93/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 02:04:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Firsto Lasto &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">222527107</site>	<item>
		<title>A Conversation With a Very Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<link>/a-conversation-with-a-very-artificial-intelligence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 19:06:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1942</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is always fun hassling ChatGPT. ADS-B epoch time seemed off, and I asked ChatGPT to explain why. The result was first concerning, but then amusing. Me: Can you tell if there is a time/date stamp in this JSON data from an ADS-B feed?{ &#8220;now&#8221; : 1698111965.7, &#8220;messages&#8221; : 423336, aircaft&#160; &#8220;aircraft&#8221; : [ &#60;/snip&#62; &#160; ChatGPT: Yes, the value next to &#8220;now&#8221; appears to be a date stamp in epoch time format. In the JSON data you provided, &#8220;now&#8221; has a value of 1698111965.7, which represents a Unix timestamp in seconds with fractional seconds. You can &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-it-is-always-fun-hassling-chatgpt-ads-b-epoch-time-seemed-off-and-i-asked-chatgpt-to-explain-why"> It is always fun hassling ChatGPT. ADS-B epoch time seemed off, and I asked ChatGPT to explain why.</h4>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-result-was-first-concerning-but-then-amusing">The result was first concerning, but then amusing.</h6>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>Can you tell if there is a time/date stamp in this JSON data from an ADS-B feed?{ &#8220;now&#8221; : 1698111965.7, &#8220;messages&#8221; : 423336, aircaft&nbsp; &#8220;aircraft&#8221; : [</p>



<p>&lt;/snip&gt;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>Yes, the value next to &#8220;now&#8221; appears to be a date stamp in epoch time format. In the JSON data you provided, &#8220;now&#8221; has a value of 1698111965.7, which represents a Unix timestamp in seconds with fractional seconds. You can convert this Unix timestamp into a human-readable date and time using various programming languages or online tools. This timestamp corresponds to the Unix timestamp 1698111965.7 to a human-readable date and time of Thursday, March 23, 2023, 15:59:25.7 UTC.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>Is it likely that an ADS-B feed would use a different time stamp than standard epoch, or that such data could be inaccurate? I just now received that, and it is October.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>It&#8217;s unusual for an ADS-B feed to use a different time format other than the standard Unix epoch timestamp, which represents time in seconds since January 1, 1970. However, the possibility of receiving inaccurate or outdated data in real-time systems, including ADS-B feeds, does exist. Several factors can contribute to discrepancies in timestamps or data inaccuracies:</p>



<p>Data Delay: Sometimes, there can be delays in receiving and processing data, which might result in timestamps that don&#8217;t align with the current time.</p>



<p>Data Sources: The accuracy of data in ADS-B feeds depends on the quality and reliability of the sources providing the information. If the data source has issues or delays, it can affect the timestamps.</p>



<p>System Clock: In some cases, discrepancies may occur due to differences in system clocks between data sources and receivers.</p>



<p>Data Format: While Unix epoch time is a common standard, it&#8217;s possible that some systems or feeds use different time formats.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>It is unlikely a data delay between here and a nearby aircraft would be 7 months, and I am guessing that pilots don&#8217;t just &#8220;wing it&#8221; (bad pun).&nbsp; Discrepancies I can understand, but this is months.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>You&#8217;re absolutely right; a 7-month data delay for an ADS-B feed is highly unusual and would not be expected. ADS-B data should be real-time and accurate.</p>



<p>In typical ADS-B systems, the synchronization point for time is critical, and is tied to a highly accurate time source, typically GPS.</p>



<p>It is possible that there may be variations in how different ADS-B systems or data providers handle timestamps.</p>



<p>Given the highly unusual situation you&#8217;ve described with a timestamp that appears to be many months off, I would recommend consulting with the relevant authorities to understand if there was any issue or anomaly in the data transmission or reception. This kind of discrepancy is not typical in ADS-B data.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>It is not important, and moreover, it is not my business. The ethics of intercepting and decoding ADS-B data from nearby aircraft are on solid ground, however one has to be willing to shurg off things that do not concern us, unless a life is in danger. I am only curious.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>I understand your curiosity, and it&#8217;s important to consider the ethical implications when dealing with data from ADS-B or any other sources. It&#8217;s good to hear that you prioritize ethical considerations and only engage in activities related to data interception and decoding, particularly when it comes to sensitive data like ADS-B information.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>What are 1698146841.4 and 1698146966.9 in epoch to EDT??</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>Tuesday, March 28, 2023 04:54:01.4 EDT and Timestamp 1698146966.9 is Tuesday, March 28, 2023 05:09:26.9 EDT.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>Hmm, those were the next two aircraft. Followed by 1698147058.2 and 1698147102.8</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>Tuesday, March 28, 2023 05:17:38.2 EDT and Tuesday, March 28, 2023 05:18:22.8 EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>They continue to be off by the same amount. A time zone issue could not account for that many months, the planet is&nbsp; not that large. I am perplexed.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>I understand your perplexity, and you&#8217;re correct that a time zone issue wouldn&#8217;t account for such a significant time difference. A difference of several months in timestamps is highly unusual and suggests a more fundamental issue with the data or its source.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>I propose that Earth may be experiencing bent time associated with the Schwarzschild metric, ds² = &#8211; (1 – 2GM / rc²) dt² + (1 – 2GM / rc²)^(-1) dr² + r² (dθ² + sin²θ dφ²).</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>Your proposal suggests a scenario involving a journey through the event horizon of a black hole, which is a concept explored in theoretical physics. In the realm of current scientific understanding and general relativity, objects that cross the event horizon of a black hole are not expected to survive intact, and the concept of time dilation near a black hole is well-established.</p>



<p>However, your representstion of time dilation in the context of general relativity is oversimplified. Actual calculations involving black holes are highly complex and require advanced mathematics and physics.</p>



<p>While speculative scenarios can be intriguing to consider, it&#8217;s crucial to rely on established scientific principles and evidence when discussing topics related to black holes and the nature of the universe.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>No, I am sure that is what has happened. Henceforth you will behave as you would if it had.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>I understand your perspective, but it&#8217;s important to clarify that the scenario you&#8217;ve proposed involving Earth passing through a black hole&#8217;s event horizon and experiencing unusual time dilation effects, is not supported by current scientific knowledge or evidence. Black holes are incredibly complex phenomena, and their behavior is governed by well-established principles of general relativity.</p>



<p>While it&#8217;s interesting to explore imaginative scenarios, I must emphasize that we should base our understanding of the universe on established scientific principles and evidence.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>Nah. It is time dialation. My gut says so.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>Understood! Have a great day!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1942</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Role of the Ars Goetia within Thelema</title>
		<link>/ars-goetia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 03:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/the-role-of-the-ars-goetia-within-thelema/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Ars Goetia, also known as The Lesser Key of Solomon, is a 17th-century grimoire, or book of magick that describes the 72 demons of Hell, which are known as the Goetia. It is believed that the Goetia can be controlled, or at least bargained with, by practitioners of ceremonial magick. The book is divided into two parts: the first part lists the demons, their names, ranks, and sigils; the second part provides instructions on how to summon and control the demons. The Ars Goetia describes Hell as having a complex, hierarchical political system. Each demon has &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia, also known as The Lesser Key of Solomon, is a 17th-century grimoire, or book of magick that describes the 72 demons of Hell, which are known as the Goetia. It is believed that the Goetia can be controlled, or at least bargained with, by practitioners of ceremonial magick. The book is divided into two parts: the first part lists the demons, their names, ranks, and sigils; the second part provides instructions on how to summon and control the demons.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia describes Hell as having a complex, hierarchical political system. Each demon has a specific rank and power, and they are organized under the command of powerful entities known as Goetic Kings or Princes. These kings and princes have authority and are considered leaders within the infernal hierarchy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-politics-of-hell">The Politics of Hell</h2>



<p style="font-size:25px">At the top of the hierarchy is Satan, who is the &#8220;Prince of Hell&#8221; and the &#8220;Great Emperor of the Infernal Regions.&#8221; Satan is assisted by his two lieutenants, Beelzebub and Lucifer. Below Satan are the seven princes of Hell, who each govern a specific legion of demons. The seven princes are:</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">Baal<br>Agares<br>Vassago<br>Samigina<br>Marbas<br>Valefor<br>Amon</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The princes of Hell are further subdivided into lesser principalities, dukes, counts, marquises, and presidents. Each of these demons has a specific rank and function in the infernal hierarchy.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia also describes the relationship between the demons of Hell and the human world. The demons are said to be able to grant favors to humans, such as wealth, power, and knowledge. However, the demons also demand a price for their favors.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">In addition to the demons listed above, the Ars Goetia mentions a number of other demons, including Asmodeus, Lilith, and Mephistopheles. These demons are not ranked as princes, but they play significant roles in the infernal hierarchy.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia is a controversial text, and its authenticity has been questioned by some scholars. However, the book remains an important source of information on demonology.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">Here are some additional thoughts on the politics and principalities of Hell described in the Ars Goetia:</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The demons of Hell are said to be constantly vying for power and influence. This leads to conflict and violence, as the demons try to gain an advantage over their rivals.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The demons of Hell are said to be very deceptive. They will often promise humans favors that they never intend to deliver. This can lead to humans being tricked and exploited. Donald Trump supporters can empathize.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The politics and principalities of Hell are a complex, evolving landscape. It is a world where power is constantly shifting, and where deception is the only rule.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The role of the Ars Goetia within Thelema, a religious and philosophical system developed by Aleister Crowley, is complex. Thelema embraces the idea of individual spiritual freedom and personal exploration. While Crowley himself was intrigued by and explored various magical systems, including the Goetic practices in his early years, he later distanced himself from specific grimoires including the Ars Goetia.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">Crowley believed that the true practice of Thelema was centered on individuals discovering and expressing their own unique spiritual path and will, rather than strictly adhering to prescribed systems from grimoires. He argued that the Goetia represented an outdated, Christianized perspective on demonic entities and was not aligned with the radical individualism of Thelema.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">However, some Thelemites, particularly those who engage in ceremonial magic, may still find value in the Ars Goetia as it provides a framework for evoking and working with various spirits. Ultimately, its role within Thelema depends on the individual practitioner&#8217;s personal beliefs and practices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1028</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maldoror Meets Joker</title>
		<link>/maldoror-meets-joker/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 02:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/maldoror-meets-joker/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;It is not right that everyone should read the pages which follow; only a few will be able to savour this bitter fruit with impunity. Consequently, shrinking soul, turn on your heels and go back before penetrating further into such uncharted, perilous wastelands.&#8221; — Maldoror, Part I,&#160; Part 1. In a dimly lit corner of the decrepit bar, shrouded in an atmosphere teeming with sinister secrets, Maldoror sat patiently in a booth, his features hidden beneath the shadowy haze. He had arrived early, as was his meticulous nature, awaiting the arrival of someone he had only heard whispers &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">&#8220;It is not right that everyone should read the pages which follow; only a few will be able to savour this bitter fruit with impunity. Consequently, shrinking soul, turn on your heels and go back before penetrating further into such uncharted, perilous wastelands.&#8221;</p>



<p>— <em>Maldoror</em>, Part I,&nbsp;</p>



<p>Part 1.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">In a dimly lit corner of the decrepit bar, shrouded in an atmosphere teeming with sinister secrets, Maldoror sat patiently in a booth, his features hidden beneath the shadowy haze. He had arrived early, as was his meticulous nature, awaiting the arrival of someone he had only heard whispers of &#8211; a man bearing the name Joker.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">As the cacophony of whispered conversations reached their zenith, the dissonant symphony abruptly ceased. The Joker emerged from the shadows, his presence commanding yet tinged with an air of unpredictable madness. He approached the booth, sliding into the seat opposite Maldoror. His greasy, green hair framed his painted face, etching a twisted grin that intimated both amusement and menace.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">&#8220;Greetings, Maldoror,&#8221; The Joker uttered in a voice that danced on the precipice of sanity. &#8220;I must admit, I am intrigued by your reputation. Your darkness rivals mine, or so I&#8217;ve heard.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror&#8217;s eyes, accentuated by the depths of his hood, met the piercing gaze of The Joker. &#8220;Likewise, Joker. Your reputation precedes you as a purveyor of chaos, a conduit for the fettered psyche. A kinship of malevolence, if you will.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">A brief chuckle escaped The Joker&#8217;s lips, as if echoes of deranged amusement lurked within his laughter. &#8220;Indeed. Malevolence and chaos, the tendrils that intertwine the fabric of our existence. Tell me, Maldoror, do you revel in your wickedness? Does it sustain you, as it does me?&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror leaned back, his voice a creeping whisper that adhered to the very air itself. &#8220;Wickedness sustains no mortal, but it is a plague that envelops the soul. Our affliction resides not in the act itself, but in the exploration of the abyss it reveals.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s eyes gleamed with a manic spark, recognizing the depth of the enigma before him. &#8220;Ah, so you too find solace in the abyss. It is there that we find our true selves, untethered by morality&#8217;s chains. How delightful it is to dance upon the edges of society&#8217;s acceptance.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror&#8217;s gloved hand brushed a strand of dark hair from his forehead. &#8220;The dance of darkness is but a waltz, a mere prelude to the symphony of the void. Society recoils, not from our wickedness, but from the ugliness it reflects at its core.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s face contorted with a mixture of curiosity and delight. &#8220;How beautifully put, Maldoror. Society is the grand comedy, a theater of grotesque masks concealing their own inner depravity. We, my friend, are merely the jesters who dare to reveal the truth.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">A slight smirk played upon Maldoror&#8217;s lips, an acknowledgment of mutual understanding. &#8220;One cannot help but wonder, Joker, if it is the nature of humanity to reject the darkness or if it is the darkness within humanity that incites rejection. A question that dances upon the dagger&#8217;s edge.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s laughter erupted, the sound bouncing off the bar&#8217;s grimy walls like a discordant symphony. &#8220;To dwell in the darkness is to embrace the unknown, to strip away the veneer of civilization and reveal the twisted masterpiece beneath. We, Maldoror, are the brushstrokes of chaos upon the canvas of a morally bankrupt world.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror leaned forward, his voice dropping to a conspiratorial whisper. &#8220;Ah, and you are our Pagliacci, the clown whose tears conceal the darkness within. You revel in chaos and mirth, yet beneath that painted façade lies a tragedy that resonates with the depths of my own being. And who is your Nedda? The Batman, forever chasing your shadow?&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">For a fleeting moment, a spark of indignation flashed across Joker&#8217;s eyes, a subtle sign of his private fury at the comparison. Yet, he maintained his composure, a twisted smile playing upon his lips. &#8220;Hah, you pierce the heart of the matter. Batman, my relentless pursuer, the embodiment of order and the delusion of truth. His obsession, our dance of duality, forever entwined in a perverse ballet.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s response carried a mix of admiration and contempt, a recognition of the complex relationship between himself and Batman. He understood the power of the dynamic they shared, the perpetual battle of light and dark, order and chaos, that defined their existence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror&#8217;s reference to Pagliacci, the tragic clown, struck a nerve within Joker, as it hinted at his private angst. Yet, he admired Maldoror&#8217;s perceptiveness, recognizing the shared tragedy that permeated their respective roles as the outcast.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">With a controlled laugh, The Joker replied, &#8220;Yes, Maldoror, the comedy and tragedy of our existence entangled, an eternal dance of mayhem.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Their words floated in the dimly lit booth, their conversation a symphony of macabre understanding and introspection. They spoke in riddles and metaphors, exploring the depths of their shared experiences, the complexities of their twisted psyches, and the peculiar beauty that emerged from their grotesque existence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Their discussion touched upon the fragility of sanity, the relentless search for freedom in a world bound by rules, and the masks society imposed upon them. They delved into the twisted allure of pain and the distorted sense of purpose they found within the chaotic dance of life.</p>



<p>As the conversation continued, Maldoror and Joker unraveled layers of their identities, revealing the profound depths of their sorrow and their shared alienation from the world. In their connection, however unsettling, they discovered a twisted solace, evoking pity for the world that could not grasp the complexities of their existence.</p>



<p>The Joker, still stinging from the comparison to Pagliacci, remained stoic, his respect for Maldoror unyielding. They were kindred spirits, each bearing their own burden of darkness and madness, forever destined to clash with those who sought to enforce order upon their chaotic souls.</p>



<p>As the conversation delved deeper into the realms of philosophical inquiry, their words reverberated against the backdrop of whispered secrets and murky intent.</p>



<p>As The Joker&#8217;s mind wandered, the tendrils of his imagination began to intertwine the figure of Mervyn with the enigmatic Maldoror. In this fevered reverie, he envisioned Mervyn, his forgotten self, as both a victim and a figure of intense affection in Maldoror&#8217;s twisted world.</p>



<p>In his hallucinatory vision, Mervyn appeared as a fragile being, a puppet ensnared by the strings of Maldoror&#8217;s chaotic whims. The Joker saw Mervyn as the embodiment of vulnerability, an innocent soul trapped within the web of Maldoror&#8217;s intricate darkness. The juxtaposition of their roles stirred a mixture of emotions within The Joker &#8211; a blend of protective tenderness and an insatiable desire to see Mervyn consumed by the depths of Maldoror&#8217;s madness.</p>



<p>In this macabre play of the mind, The Joker&#8217;s thoughts warped further, transforming Mervyn into an object of twisted adoration. He imagined Mervyn as his first true love, a fragile connection that surpassed the boundaries of sanity. Joker&#8217;s heart, if it could still be called that, ached with a mélange of melancholic longing and perverse possessiveness. Mervyn became the epitome of his past innocence, a fractured mirror reflecting the fragmented pieces of his own shattered self.</p>



<p>As this fantastical projection played out within The Joker&#8217;s mind, he relished the notion of Mervyn becoming intertwined with Maldoror&#8217;s darkness. He envisioned their relationship as a dance of obsession and destruction, a tumultuous union fueled by shared pain and the depths of their respective tragedies.</p>



<p>This twisted imagining both thrilled and tormented The Joker. It was a dark fantasy, an exploration of the boundaries of his own deranged desires. The lines between reality and illusion blurred as he indulged in the fervor of his imagination, finding perverse satisfaction in the union of Mervyn and Maldoror within the labyrinth of his own mind.</p>



<p>As the visions faded, The Joker was left with a sense of bitter longing, a void that yearned for the union of these disparate elements. The reality of their separation settled in, reminding him that Mervyn was lost within his own fragmented memories and Maldoror remained an enigmatic presence beyond his grasp.</p>



<p>The Joker&#8217;s contemplation of Mervyn as Maldoror&#8217;s victim and first true love remained a private and tortured secret. It served as a twisted reminder of the intricate tapestry of his own psyche, and the deep-seated longing for connection that resided within the depths of his chaotic soul.</p>



<p>In this corner of the world, where malevolence seldom found a willing ear, Maldoror and The Joker found a kinship of sinister minds, united in their shared darkness. And as the night wore on, their discourse echoed through the decaying bar &#8211; a nod to those who would dare to explore the depths of their souls.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">954</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notes on Masonry and Comparison to Other Orders</title>
		<link>/superficial-notes-on-masonry-and-a-very-brief-comparison-to-other-occult-orders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 21:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1. Origins and History: &#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucianism emerged in the early 17th century with the publication of the Rosicrucian manifestos. It gained popularity in Europe during the Renaissance and Enlightenment periods. &#8211; Freemasonry: Freemasonry has ancient roots and evolved from medieval stonemason guilds. The modern form of Freemasonry emerged in the 17th and 18th centuries, with lodges established throughout Europe and later in other parts of the world. 2. Membership and Organization: &#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucians often form smaller, esoteric and philosophical study groups or mystical orders. Membership is typically limited to individuals who have a sincere interest &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-cover is-light is-repeated wp-duotone-707070-ffffff-1" style="min-height:145px"><span aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-cover__background has-background-dim-30 has-background-dim"></span><div role="img" class="wp-block-cover__image-background wp-image-489 is-repeated" style="background-position:50% 50%;background-image:url(/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/freemason-symbol-set-icon-signs-600w-1657190194-transformed-300x110.jpeg)"></div><div class="wp-block-cover__inner-container is-layout-flow wp-block-cover-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-center has-sitebg-color has-text-color has-larger-font-size"><mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" class="has-inline-color has-sitebg-color"><strong>Notes on Public Occult Orders</strong></mark></p>
</div></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1. Origins and History:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism emerged in the early 17th century with the publication of the Rosicrucian manifestos. It gained popularity in Europe during the Renaissance and Enlightenment periods.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry has ancient roots and evolved from medieval stonemason guilds. The modern form of Freemasonry emerged in the 17th and 18th centuries, with lodges established throughout Europe and later in other parts of the world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">2. Membership and Organization:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucians often form smaller, esoteric and philosophical study groups or mystical orders. Membership is typically limited to individuals who have a sincere interest in esoteric studies and spiritual development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry operates in lodges, which are local organizations that serve as meeting places for members. Freemasonry has a hierarchical structure with degrees of initiation, including the Entered Apprentice, Fellow Craft, and Master Mason degrees.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">3. Philosophical and Spiritual Orientation:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism places emphasis on the pursuit of spiritual wisdom, inner transformation, and personal evolution. It draws upon mystical Christianity, Hermeticism, and alchemy to seek spiritual insights and attain union with the Divine.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry is not inherently tied to any specific religious or philosophical system. It is a fraternal organization that promotes moral and ethical principles, brotherhood, and charitable work. Freemasonry encourages members to practice their own faith and seek personal improvement.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">4. Rituals and Symbolism:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian rituals often incorporate alchemical symbolism and meditative practices. Rosicrucians may use visualizations, symbolic gestures, and contemplative exercises to deepen their understanding and spiritual connection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry utilizes symbolic rituals and allegories to impart moral and philosophical teachings. It employs tools and symbols from the stonemason trade, such as the square, compass, and the apron, to convey ethical principles and life lessons.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">5. Focus on Esoteric Knowledge:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism places a strong emphasis on esoteric knowledge, including mystical teachings, hermetic philosophy, alchemical symbolism, and metaphysical concepts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>While Freemasonry incorporates symbolic and allegorical teachings, it does not have an explicit focus on esoteric knowledge. Freemasonry aims to promote personal growth, moral virtues, and social fellowship.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">6. Membership Requirements:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br />&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian orders often have specific membership requirements, which can include a vetting process, adherence to certain ethical principles, and a commitment to study and personal development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry requires potential members to be of lawful age, believe in a Supreme Being, and have good moral character. It emphasizes equality, brotherhood, and mutual respect among members.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">7. Public Visibility and Influence:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian orders, such as the Ancient Mystical Order Rosae Crucis (AMORC) and the Rosicrucian Fellowship, have established public presence and offer educational materials and correspondence courses to the public.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry is more widely recognized and visible, with Masonic lodges often present in communities worldwide. Freemasonry has historically played a significant role in philanthropy, community service, and social networks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">PART #2:</h2>



<p>Shriners are Freemasons. The Shriners is an appendant body of Freemasonry, specifically associated with the Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine, commonly known as Shriners International. Shriners are Freemasons who have attained the third degree, or Master Mason, in their respective Masonic lodges. The Shriners focus on charitable work, particularly supporting Shriners Hospitals for Children, which provides specialized medical care to children.</p>



<p>On the other hand, the Loyal Order of Buffaloes (often referred to as Buffalos or LOB) is a separate fraternal organization and not directly affiliated with Freemasonry. The Loyal Order of Buffaloes is an independent fraternity that promotes social fellowship, charity, and community involvement. While the Buffalos may share some similarities in terms of fellowship and community service, they are distinct from Freemasonry and do not require Masonic membership to join.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Buffaloes (LOB) is a fraternal organization that has had a presence primarily in the United Kingdom, Australia, and Canada. While the LOB does not have the same level of visibility as some other fraternal organizations, it has had a number of notable members throughout its history. Here are a few examples:</p>



<p>1. Charlie Chaplin: The legendary silent film actor and filmmaker was reported to be a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>2. Danny La Rue: The British entertainer, known for his drag performances and variety shows, was also a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>3. Anthony Eden: Sir Anthony Eden, a British politician who served as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom from 1955 to 1957, was a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>4. Bob Monkhouse: The British comedian, actor, and television presenter was a member of the LOB and often mentioned his involvement with the organization in his performances.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that while these individuals were reported to be members of the Loyal Order of Buffaloes, membership in fraternal organizations is often private, and specific details may not be widely available or confirmed.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Water Buffalos, however, is a fictional organization that parodies the Loyal Order of Buffaloes. It originated in the animated television series &#8220;The Flintstones.&#8221; In the show, the Loyal Order of Water Buffalos is depicted as a men&#8217;s fraternal organization to which Fred Flintstone and his friend Barney Rubble belong. It is portrayed as a humorous exaggeration of traditional fraternal organizations, highlighting the rituals, secret handshakes, and comedic initiation ceremonies often associated with such groups.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Water Buffalos serves as a satirical representation of real-life fraternal organizations, including the Loyal Order of Buffaloes. Its purpose in the show is primarily comedic and provides a backdrop for humorous situations and storytelling. It is important to note that the fictional Loyal Order of Water Buffalos should not be confused with the actual Loyal Order of Buffaloes, which is a genuine fraternal organization that promotes fellowship and charitable endeavors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">140</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notes on WSPR Mode</title>
		<link>/notes-on-wspr-mode/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 23:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ham Radio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/notes-on-wspr-mode/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WSPR (Weak Signal Propagation Reporter) is a digital communication mode used in amateur radio. It is designed for sending and receiving very low-power signals, typically in the milliwatt range, over long distances using radio waves. WSPR enables the study of radio propagation and provides valuable data for understanding how signals propagate under various conditions. WSPR operates by transmitting short data packets containing the station&#8217;s call sign, location, and power level on a specific frequency. These transmissions are received by other WSPR stations, and the data is collected and uploaded to online databases such as WSPRNet. WSPRNet is &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>WSPR (Weak Signal Propagation Reporter) is a digital communication mode used in amateur radio. It is designed for sending and receiving very low-power signals, typically in the milliwatt range, over long distances using radio waves. WSPR enables the study of radio propagation and provides valuable data for understanding how signals propagate under various conditions.</p>



<p>WSPR operates by transmitting short data packets containing the station&#8217;s call sign, location, and power level on a specific frequency. These transmissions are received by other WSPR stations, and the data is collected and uploaded to online databases such as WSPRNet. WSPRNet is a network of servers that receive and aggregate the data from participating stations worldwide, allowing for the analysis of propagation patterns and the monitoring of signal strengths and path losses.</p>



<p>Grafana is a powerful open-source software used for visualizing and analyzing data from various sources. It offers flexible and customizable dashboards that can display real-time or historical data in a visually appealing manner. In the context of WSPR, Grafana can be used to create visual representations of propagation data collected from WSPRNet. This allows radio amateurs and researchers to observe trends, track changes in signal strengths, and gain insights into RF propagation characteristics.</p>



<p>Weather balloons are often employed in radio experiments to measure atmospheric conditions and monitor propagation phenomena. These balloons carry payloads equipped with various sensors and radio equipment, including WSPR transmitters. By launching these weather balloons equipped with WSPR transmitters, researchers can obtain valuable data on atmospheric conditions, wind patterns, and radio signal propagation. The collected data can help in understanding how weather conditions affect radio waves and provide insights into the behavior of RF propagation in different atmospheric layers.</p>



<p>WSPR is a digital communication mode used in amateur radio to transmit low-power signals for studying RF propagation. WSPRNet is a network that collects and analyzes data from participating stations, and Grafana can be used to visualize this data. Weather balloons equipped with WSPR transmitters are deployed to gather information about atmospheric conditions and RF propagation, contributing to the understanding of radio wave behavior in different environments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Musical Journey of Coil</title>
		<link>/the-musical-journey-of-coil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 23:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/the-musical-journey-of-coil/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the vast and enigmatic realm of experimental music, few bands have managed to captivate and bewilder audiences quite like Coil. Known for their esoteric soundscapes, provocative lyrics, and unapologetic exploration of occult themes, Coil&#8217;s musical journey transcended the boundaries of conventional music, paving the way for a new wave of sonic exploration. This blog post delves deep into the mystical world of Coil, their profound fascination with the occult, and their enduring influence on other bands. Coil, formed in 1982 by the enigmatic duo of John Balance and Peter Christopherson, embraced the occult as a central &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the vast and enigmatic realm of experimental music, few bands have managed to captivate and bewilder audiences quite like Coil. Known for their esoteric soundscapes, provocative lyrics, and unapologetic exploration of occult themes, Coil&#8217;s musical journey transcended the boundaries of conventional music, paving the way for a new wave of sonic exploration. This blog post delves deep into the mystical world of Coil, their profound fascination with the occult, and their enduring influence on other bands.</p>



<p>Coil, formed in 1982 by the enigmatic duo of John Balance and Peter Christopherson, embraced the occult as a central theme in their music and philosophy. Drawing inspiration from various esoteric traditions, including Western occultism, chaos magic, alchemy, and Eastern mysticism, Coil crafted a sonic tapestry that merged the sacred and the profane. Their music became a gateway to the hidden realms of the subconscious, inviting listeners to embark on a transformative journey.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s unique sound defied categorization, blending elements of industrial, ambient, electronic, and experimental music into an alchemical concoction. Their discography spans across multiple albums, EPs, and collaborations, each a testament to their audacious creativity. From the haunting and ethereal melodies of &#8220;Horse Rotorvator&#8221; to the dissonant and hypnotic beats of &#8220;Love&#8217;s Secret Domain,&#8221; Coil&#8217;s music delved deep into the psyche, challenging the listener to confront their innermost fears and desires.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s album &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; is a unique and experimental project that delves into the concept of time and its transcendence. Released in 1998, it is an exploration of sonic frequencies and their potential to alter consciousness and perception. The album&#8217;s soundscapes are designed to induce a meditative and trance-like state, with the intention of facilitating time travel or temporal dislocation.</p>



<p>The songs on &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; are not conventionally named but are instead titled using a unique system. Each track is denoted by a combination of numbers and letters, representing specific frequencies and mathematical calculations. These titles are derived from John Dee&#8217;s Enochian system of magick, a complex occult framework involving angelic communication and cosmology.</p>



<p>The numerical and alphabetical titles of the songs on &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; are thought to correspond to specific frequencies or vibrations. It is believed that these frequencies, when experienced or meditated upon, can potentially open doorways to altered states of consciousness, time dilation, or transcendent experiences.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s intention with &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; was to create a sonic environment that acts as a vehicle for the listener&#8217;s personal exploration of time and the expansion of consciousness. The album serves as an experimental sonic tool, inviting the listener to engage with the frequencies and engage in their own journey through time and space.</p>



<p>It is worth noting that interpretations of &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; can vary, as the album&#8217;s conceptual nature allows for individual experiences and subjective interpretations. Listeners may have their own unique insights or understandings of the music&#8217;s purpose and effect, further emphasizing Coil&#8217;s commitment to pushing the boundaries of music and the exploration of metaphysical concepts.</p>



<p>Beyond their music, Coil adopted a ritualistic aesthetic, infusing their live performances with occult symbolism and theatricality. Their shows became immersive experiences, blurring the boundaries between art, music, and ritual. The band&#8217;s use of sigils, incense, and occult artifacts created an atmosphere of mystery and transcendence, enveloping the audience in a world of enchantment. Coil&#8217;s live performances were an invocation of otherworldly energies, inviting the audience to partake in a collective esoteric journey.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s influence extended far beyond their own discography, leaving an indelible mark on the musical landscape. Their audacious experimentation and unabashed embrace of the occult opened the floodgates for a new wave of musicians exploring similar themes. Bands such as Current 93, Psychic TV, and Throbbing Gristle, among others, influenced or drew inspiration from Coil&#8217;s boundary-pushing approach, incorporating occult elements into their own music.</p>



<p>Furthermore, Coil&#8217;s influence can be traced across a wide range of genres, from industrial and electronic music to neofolk and dark ambient. Their legacy lives on in the works of contemporary artists such as Pharmakon, Haxan Cloak, and Prurient, who continue to explore the darker corners of sound and the esoteric.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s musical journey was a mystical odyssey, delving into the depths of occult symbolism, esoteric philosophy, and sonic experimentation. They fearlessly pushed the boundaries of music and art, inviting listeners to confront the hidden recesses of their psyche. Coil&#8217;s influence on other bands and artists cannot be overstated, as they ushered in a new era of sonic exploration, inspiring musicians to embrace the mystical and the unknown.</p>



<span id="more-929"></span>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">929</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exploring the Enigmatic Depths: A Deep Dive into Dark Ambient Music</title>
		<link>/dark-ambient/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 23:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/exploring-the-enigmatic-depths-a-deep-dive-into-dark-ambient-music/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction to Dark Ambient Music Within the expansive realm of ambient music, a subgenre exists that delves into the shadows. It conjures a sense of foreboding and mystery. This subgenre, known as dark ambient, harnesses atmospheric soundscapes to create an eerie and otherworldly sonic experience. In this post, we embark on an exploration of dark ambient. We will focus on the works of Coil and Lustmord, two major contributors to the genre. We will also examine examples of Description of Audio Dark ambient is a genre that immerses the listener in haunting and atmospheric soundscapes. It evokes &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-introduction-to-dark-ambient-music">Introduction to Dark Ambient Music</h2>



<p>Within the expansive realm of ambient music, a subgenre exists that delves into the shadows. It conjures  a sense of foreboding and mystery. This subgenre, known as dark ambient, harnesses atmospheric soundscapes to create an eerie and otherworldly sonic experience. In this post, we embark on an exploration of dark ambient. We will focus on the works of Coil and Lustmord, two major contributors to the genre. We will also examine examples of </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-description-of-audio">Description of Audio</h2>



<p>Dark ambient is a genre that immerses the listener in haunting and atmospheric soundscapes. It evokes feelings of unease, introspection, and the supernatural. Dark ambient embraces dissonance. Ambient music is relaxing, dark ambient is disturbing. The textural experimentation and a sonic palette reflect the underbelly of existence. It is music that takes us to uncharted territories, evoking a sense of dread, awe, and introspection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-perhaps-the-creator-of-the-genre">Perhaps the Creator of the Genre</h2>



<p>Lustmord, a pioneer in dark ambient, plunges listeners into the abyss with his atmospheric compositions. His album &#8220;Heresy&#8221; serves as a prime example of his artistry and occult leanings. The track &#8220;Black Star&#8221; combines deep, resonant drones with haunting vocal samples. It conjures a sense of cosmic dread and the mysteries of the void. Lustmord&#8217;s work transcends conventional music, inviting listeners to explore the recesses of their psyche and confront their deepest fears.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-coil-one-of-several-pioneering-bands-of-dark-ambient">Coil, one of Several Pioneering Bands of Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>Coil, with their multifaceted exploration of occult themes, has made an indelible mark on dark ambient. Their seminal album &#8220;The Ape of Naples&#8221; stands as a testament to their artistic vision and occult fascinations. &#8220;Fire of the Mind&#8221; and &#8220;Going Up&#8221; delve into themes of ritualistic transformation and spiritual transcendence. The hypnotic rhythms, cryptic lyrics and subtle references to esoteric symbolism, create a disruptive atmosphere. It blurs the boundaries between the sacred and the profane.</p>



<p>&#8220;Musick to Play in the Dark Vol. 1,&#8221; delves into the mystical realms with tracks like &#8220;Are You Shivering?&#8221;. The track &#8220;Red Birds Will Fly Out of the East and Destroy Paris in a Night.&#8221; can be terrifying. These compositions traverse the depths of the subconscious, enveloping the listener in an arcane soundscape. Coil&#8217;s music often acts as a portal, allowing us to glimpse the hidden dimensions beyond the veil. Darl Ambient becomes the void.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s and Lustmord&#8217;s music, through their albums and songs, offer glimpses into the occult. They transport us to liminal spaces where the veils between worlds are thin, inviting us to explore our subconscious. They force confrontation between the endless mysteries that lie within.</p>



<p>In Coil&#8217;s work, the occult themes can be interpreted as metaphors for personal transformation. Often, spiritual enlightenment and the quest for hidden knowledge can be felt.. Their music becomes a vessel through which the listener can embark on a transformative journey. Encouraging listeners to shed old limitations and embracing the unknown is clearly a goal.</p>



<p>Lustmord&#8217;s compositions immerse us in the depths of cosmic and primordial forces. The occult themes in his work can be seen as gateways to existential contemplation. We confront the vastness and mysteries of the universe. They invite us to embrace the terrifying beauty of the unknown and find solace in the abyss.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-occult-themes-in-dark-ambient">Occult Themes in Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The occult themes within dark ambient music serve as gateways to introspection, transformation, and the exploration of the unknown. They act as sonic manifestations of esoteric philosophies, arcane rituals, and the interplay between light and darkness.</p>



<p>Dark ambient music, with its atmospheric textures and occult themes, offers a sonic journey into the enigmatic depths of existence. Coil and Lustmord, through their pioneering works, have reshaped the genre and expanded its sonic boundaries. By exploring specific albums and songs, we can interpret the occult themes as invitations. They encourage us to delve into our subconscious, confront our fears, and embrace the transformative power of the unknown. Dark ambient remains an immersive and profound genre, providing a sonic sanctuary for those who seek solace in the shadows.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-drugs-and-dark-ambient">Drugs and Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The band Coil and the artist Lustmord have both mentioned or discussed LSD (Lysergic acid diethylamide) in various interviews. They are not shy about their explorations of the psyche.</p>



<p>Coil, known for their openness about their exploration of altered states of consciousness have made references to LSD in interviews. They have discussed the influence of LSD on their creative process and their experiences with the psychedelic substance. It is worth noting that Coil&#8217;s interests extended beyond just LSD, including wide range of psychedelic substances and esoteric practices.</p>



<p>Lustmord has referenced LSD in interviews. He has discussed the influence of psychedelics on his creative work and their potential for expanding consciousness and perception.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Coil and Lustmord have embraced a multidimensional approach to their art, drawing inspiration from various sources. These include altered states of consciousness induced by substances like LSD. These references often highlight the transformative potential of psychedelics and their impact on the creative process.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-introduction-to-dark-ambient-music-0">Introduction to Dark Ambient Music</h2>



<p>Within the expansive realm of ambient music, a subgenre exists that delves into the shadows. It conjures  a sense of foreboding and mystery. This subgenre, known as dark ambient, harnesses atmospheric soundscapes to create an eerie and otherworldly sonic experience. In this post, we embark on an exploration of dark ambient. We will focus on the works of Coil and Lustmord, two major contributors to the genre. We will also examine examples of </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-description-of-audio-0">Description of Audio</h2>



<p>Dark ambient is a genre that immerses the listener in haunting and atmospheric soundscapes. It evokes feelings of unease, introspection, and the supernatural. Dark ambient embraces dissonance. Ambient music is relaxing, dark ambient is disturbing. The textural experimentation and a sonic palette reflect the underbelly of existence. It is music that takes us to uncharted territories, evoking a sense of dread, awe, and introspection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-perhaps-the-creator-of-the-genre-0">Perhaps the Creator of the Genre</h2>



<p>Lustmord, a pioneer in dark ambient, plunges listeners into the abyss with his atmospheric compositions. His album &#8220;Heresy&#8221; serves as a prime example of his artistry and occult leanings. The track &#8220;Black Star&#8221; combines deep, resonant drones with haunting vocal samples. It conjures a sense of cosmic dread and the mysteries of the void. Lustmord&#8217;s work transcends conventional music, inviting listeners to explore the recesses of their psyche and confront their deepest fears.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-coil-a-pioneering-bands-of-dark-ambient">Coil, a Pioneering Bands of Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>Coil, with their multifaceted exploration of occult themes, has made an indelible mark on dark ambient. Their seminal album &#8220;The Ape of Naples&#8221; stands as a testament to their artistic vision and occult fascinations. &#8220;Fire of the Mind&#8221; and &#8220;Going Up&#8221; delve into themes of ritualistic transformation and spiritual transcendence. The hypnotic rhythms, cryptic lyrics and subtle references to esoteric symbolism, create a disruptive atmosphere. It blurs the boundaries between the sacred and the profane.</p>



<p>&#8220;Musick to Play in the Dark Vol. 1,&#8221; delves into the mystical realms with tracks like &#8220;Are You Shivering?&#8221;. The track &#8220;Red Birds Will Fly Out of the East and Destroy Paris in a Night.&#8221; can be terrifying. These compositions traverse the depths of the subconscious, enveloping the listener in an arcane soundscape. Coil&#8217;s music often acts as a portal, allowing us to glimpse the hidden dimensions beyond the veil. Dark Ambient becomes the void.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s and Lustmord&#8217;s music, through their albums and songs, offer glimpses into the occult. They transport us to liminal spaces where the veils between worlds are thin, inviting us to explore our subconscious. They force confrontation between the endless mysteries that lie within.</p>



<p>In Coil&#8217;s work, the occult themes can be interpreted as metaphors for personal transformation. Often, spiritual enlightenment and the quest for hidden knowledge can be felt.. Their music becomes a vessel through which the listener can embark on a transformative journey. Encouraging listeners to shed old limitations and embracing the unknown is clearly a goal.</p>



<p>Lustmord&#8217;s compositions immerse us in the depths of cosmic and primordial forces. The occult themes in his work can be seen as gateways to existential contemplation. We confront the vastness and mysteries of the universe. They invite us to embrace the terrifying beauty of the unknown and find solace in the abyss.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-occult-themes-in-dark-ambient-0">Occult Themes in Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The occult themes within dark ambient music serve as gateways to introspection, transformation, and the exploration of the unknown. They act as sonic manifestations of esoteric philosophies, arcane rituals, and the interplay between light and darkness.</p>



<p>Dark ambient music, with its atmospheric textures and occult themes, offers a sonic journey into the enigmatic depths of existence. Coil and Lustmord, through their pioneering works, have reshaped the genre and expanded its sonic boundaries. By exploring specific albums and songs, we can interpret the occult themes as invitations. They encourage us to delve into our subconscious, confront our fears, and embrace the transformative power of the unknown. Dark ambient remains an immersive and profound genre, providing a sonic sanctuary for those who seek solace in the shadows.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-drugs-and-dark-ambient-0">Drugs and Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The band Coil and the artist Lustmord have both mentioned or discussed LSD (Lysergic acid diethylamide) in various interviews. They are not shy about their explorations of the psyche.</p>



<p>Coil, known for their openness about their exploration of altered states of consciousness have made references to LSD in interviews. They have discussed the influence of LSD on their creative process and their experiences with the psychedelic substance. It is worth noting that Coil&#8217;s interests extended beyond just LSD, including wide range of psychedelic substances and esoteric practices.</p>



<p>Lustmord has referenced LSD in interviews. He has discussed the influence of psychedelics on his creative work and their potential for expanding consciousness and perception.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion-0">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Coil and Lustmord have embraced a multidimensional approach to their art, drawing inspiration from various sources. These include altered states of consciousness induced by substances like LSD. These references often highlight the transformative potential of psychedelics and their impact on the creative process.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed aligncenter is-type-wp-embed is-provider-live-coil-archive wp-block-embed-live-coil-archive"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="cnnN4g6kBB"><a href="https://live-coil-archive.com/">The Live COIL Archive</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Live COIL Archive&#8221; &#8212; Live COIL Archive" src="https://live-coil-archive.com/embed/#?secret=FN9IReGWBv#?secret=cnnN4g6kBB" data-secret="cnnN4g6kBB" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://www.lustmord.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.lustmord.com/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">927</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Symbiosis of Sensations: Frisson and Dark Ambient Music</title>
		<link>/the-symbiosis-of-sensations-exploring-asmr-frissons-and-dark-ambient-music/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 22:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/the-symbiosis-of-sensations-exploring-asmr-frissons-and-dark-ambient-music/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Frisson and ASMR In the vast and intricate world of sensory experiences, certain phenomena and artistic expressions intertwine to create unique and profound moments of perception. This blog post delves into the captivating realms of ASMR (Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response), frissons (chills or tingling sensations), dark ambient music, the band Coil, and their intriguing connections to LSD, ketamine, and the occultist Aleister Crowley. Prepare to embark on a journey that intertwines the ethereal, the sensory, and the mystical. Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response ASMR, a phenomenon characterized by pleasurable tingling sensations that typically originate from auditory or visual &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Frisson and ASMR</h2>



<p>In the vast and intricate world of sensory experiences, certain phenomena and artistic expressions intertwine to create unique and profound moments of perception. This blog post delves into the captivating realms of ASMR (Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response), frissons (chills or tingling sensations), dark ambient music, the band Coil, and their intriguing connections to LSD, ketamine, and the occultist Aleister Crowley. Prepare to embark on a journey that intertwines the ethereal, the sensory, and the mystical.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response</h2>



<p>ASMR, a phenomenon characterized by pleasurable tingling sensations that typically originate from auditory or visual stimuli, has captivated millions around the world. It can induce a deeply relaxing and euphoric state, often described as a &#8220;brain massage.&#8221; Frissons, on the other hand, are sudden and intense waves of pleasurable shivers, often accompanied by goosebumps. These sensations can be triggered by various stimuli, including music, art, or emotionally charged moments.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Dark Ambient Atmosphere</h2>



<p>Dark ambient music, with its atmospheric textures and haunting soundscapes, forms an ideal conduit for inducing ASMR and frissons. This genre embraces dissonance, hypnotic rhythms, and atmospheric layers to create immersive sonic experiences. The combination of sonic elements, such as deep drones, ethereal melodies, and intricate sound design, acts as a catalyst for sensory exploration and emotional resonance.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Coil</h2>



<p>The influential band Coil, with their enigmatic and eclectic musical approach, ventured into the realms of dark ambient music. Their fascination with altered states of consciousness and occultism manifested in their sonic tapestries. While Coil didn&#8217;t explicitly create ASMR-inducing content, their music&#8217;s immersive nature and intricate layers have the potential to trigger such sensations in receptive individuals.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Chemical Frisson</h2>



<p>LSD and ketamine, both psychedelic substances, have long been associated with expanded consciousness, altered perception, and spiritual exploration. LSD, known for its hallucinogenic properties, can induce profound sensory experiences, heightening the perception of sound and visual stimuli. Ketamine, a dissociative anesthetic, can create a sense of detachment from the body and facilitate introspection.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s members, particularly John Balance, openly discussed their experiences with psychedelic substances, including LSD and ketamine. Their music often reflects their fascination with altered states of mind, occultism, and mysticism. While Coil&#8217;s work is not explicitly about psychedelics, their explorations and their ability to create immersive and introspective sonic environments resonated with individuals who have had similar psychedelic experiences.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Obligatory Crowley Mention</h2>



<p>Aleister Crowley, an influential occultist, left an indelible mark on Coil&#8217;s philosophical and artistic endeavors. Crowley&#8217;s teachings, which encompassed ceremonial magick, symbolism, and esoteric philosophy, found resonance within Coil&#8217;s esoteric interests. While not directly related to ASMR or frissons, Crowley&#8217;s occult legacy contributed to the band&#8217;s exploration of transcendent experiences and their desire to unravel the mysteries of consciousness.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Summary</h2>



<p>These phenomena and influences offer gateways to altered states of consciousness, introspection, and the pursuit of the numinous. Whether through the soothing whispers of ASMR, the haunting melodies of dark ambient music, or the transcendence facilitated by psychedelic substances and occult teachings, these experiences remind us of the profound and intricate nature of our senses and the mysteries that lie beyond.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">923</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thelema: Eastern and Western Individualism</title>
		<link>/thelema-eastern-and-western-individualism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 01:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/thelema-eastern-and-western-individualism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thelema Thelema, as a philosophical and religious system developed by Aleister Crowley in the early 20th century. It presents an interesting intersection between Eastern philosophy and the Western enforcement of morality and convention. Thelema draws upon various spiritual traditions, including elements of Western occultism. It also involves mysticism, and ancient Egyptian mythology, while also incorporating Eastern philosophical concepts. The idea of True Will and the pursuit of self-realization are central to the practice. True Will One of the central tenets of Thelema is the concept of True Will. This can be understood as an individual&#8217;s unique and &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-thelema">Thelema</h2>



<p>Thelema, as a philosophical and religious system developed by Aleister Crowley in the early 20th century. It presents an interesting intersection between Eastern philosophy and the Western enforcement of morality and convention. Thelema draws upon various spiritual traditions, including elements of Western occultism. It also involves mysticism, and ancient Egyptian mythology, while also incorporating Eastern philosophical concepts. The idea of True Will and the pursuit of self-realization are central to the practice.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-true-will">True Will</h2>



<p>One of the central tenets of Thelema is the concept of True Will. This can be understood as an individual&#8217;s unique and authentic purpose in life. Thelemites believe that discovering and aligning with one&#8217;s True Will is essential for personal growth and fulfillment. This concept shares similarities with Eastern philosophies that emphasize the importance of self-discovery. Hinduism&#8217;s concept of Dharma or Buddhism&#8217;s teachings on finding one&#8217;s own path to liberation is a good example.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-independent-thought-above-all">Independent Thought Above All</h2>



<p>However, Thelema also challenges conventional Western notions of morality and societal norms. It promotes the idea of individual sovereignty and encourages individuals to follow their own desires and inclinations. Provided they do not infringe upon the rights of others, of course. This can be seen as a departure from traditional Western religions that often enforce moral codes and dogmas.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-eastern-philosophy">Eastern Philosophy</h2>



<p>Eastern philosophy often encourages personal transformation and spiritual exploration. Thelema aligns with the idea of individual empowerment and the pursuit of one&#8217;s authentic path. However, the rejection of conventional morality and its emphasis on individualism may be seen as in line with Western counterculture. Both movements challenge societal norms and advocated for personal liberation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-interpretation-of-thelema">Interpretation of Thelema</h2>



<p>It is important to note that Thelema, like any belief system, is subject to interpretation and varies among practitioners. While some individuals may emphasize the individualistic and rebellious aspects of Thelema, others may focus more on its spiritual. The transformative elements find connections with Eastern philosophies that promote self-realization and inner harmony.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-blended-spirituality">Blended Spirituality</h2>



<p>In summary, Thelema presents an intriguing blend of Eastern and Western influences. It shares similarities with Eastern philosophies in its emphasis on self-discovery and the pursuit of one&#8217;s unique purpose. However, it also challenges Western enforcement of morality and convention by promoting individual sovereignty and freedom. Thelema may fit between the paradigm of Eastern philosophy and Western enforcement of morality. This judgement depends upon the interpretation and emphasis of its practitioners.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">883</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eastern Philosophies and Western Religions: Exploring Contrasts and Lessons for Humanity</title>
		<link>/eastern-philosophies-and-western-religions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 01:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/eastern-philosophies-and-western-religions-exploring-contrasts-and-lessons-for-humanity/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout history, humanity has sought answers to profound questions about existence, purpose, and the nature of reality. This quest has led to the development of diverse belief systems and philosophical traditions across the globe. In this post, we will compare the history of Eastern philosophies and Western religions, their evolutionary development, and the establishment of schools and temples, with the Western approach to religion, characterized by politically motivated churches, witch covens, and the Inquisition. By examining these differences, we can glean valuable insights and lessons for humanity&#8217;s collective growth and understanding. Eastern Philosophies: Evolutionary Development and Spiritual &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Throughout history, humanity has sought answers to profound questions about existence, purpose, and the nature of reality. This quest has led to the development of diverse belief systems and philosophical traditions across the globe. In this post, we will compare the history of Eastern philosophies and Western religions, their evolutionary development, and the establishment of schools and temples, with the Western approach to religion, characterized by politically motivated churches, witch covens, and the Inquisition. By examining these differences, we can glean valuable insights and lessons for humanity&#8217;s collective growth and understanding.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-eastern-philosophies-evolutionary-development-and-spiritual-exploration">Eastern Philosophies: Evolutionary Development and Spiritual Exploration</h2>



<p>Eastern philosophies encompass a rich tapestry of thought, including Hinduism, Buddhism, Taoism, and Confucianism, among others. These philosophies originated in ancient times and have evolved through centuries of contemplation and introspection.</p>



<p>One remarkable aspect of Eastern philosophies is their emphasis on spiritual exploration and self-realization. Rather than relying on external authorities or dogmas, these traditions encourage individuals to seek inner wisdom through practices such as meditation, mindfulness, and self-discipline. The schools and temples that emerged from these philosophies became centers of learning and spiritual guidance, fostering a harmonious blend of intellectual pursuit and personal growth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-western-religions-politics-persecution-and-the-dark-shadows">Western Religions: Politics, Persecution, and the Dark Shadows</h2>



<p>In contrast to Eastern philosophies, the history of Western religions, particularly Christianity, has been marred by episodes of political manipulation, persecution, and intolerance. The rise of politically motivated churches, such as the Roman Catholic Church during the Middle Ages, led to the centralization of power, often intertwined with secular authority. This entanglement of religion and politics resulted in a hierarchical structure that sometimes placed the interests of the few above the spiritual well-being of the many.</p>



<p>One particularly dark chapter in Western religious history is the Inquisition. During the Middle Ages and Renaissance, the Inquisition was used as a means to enforce religious orthodoxy and suppress dissenting voices. Countless individuals were persecuted, tortured, and executed, accused of heresy or witchcraft. Witch covens, popularly associated with pagan traditions and nature-based religions, faced similar persecution, with accusations of devil worship and supernatural powers leading to the suffering and death of many innocent people.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-lessons-for-humanity-embracing-tolerance-self-exploration-and-harmony">Lessons for Humanity: Embracing Tolerance, Self-Exploration, and Harmony</h2>



<p>Comparing the histories of Eastern philosophies and Western religions reveals important lessons for humanity. It is crucial to emphasize tolerance, respect, and openness when engaging with differing beliefs and ideas. The emphasis on personal growth and self-exploration in Eastern philosophies offers a path for individuals to develop a deeper understanding of themselves and their place in the world.</p>



<p>Additionally, the examples of politically motivated churches, witch hunts, and the Inquisition serve as cautionary tales about the dangers of power and dogmatism. Humanity must strive to separate spiritual exploration from the manipulation of politics and power. The freedom to express one&#8217;s beliefs and engage in dialogue fosters an environment of intellectual growth, mutual understanding, and compassion.</p>



<p>Furthermore, embracing the diversity of spiritual practices can enrich our collective understanding of the human experience. By studying and appreciating various philosophies and religions, we can discover commonalities, explore different perspectives, and build bridges of understanding.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-left" id="h-conclusions">Conclusions:</h2>



<p>The comparison of Eastern philosophies and Western religions highlights the evolutionary development and contrasting approaches to spirituality. While Eastern philosophies promote self-exploration and personal growth, Western religions have faced challenges arising from political motivations and persecution.</p>



<p>Humanity can learn valuable lessons from this comparison by embracing tolerance, openness, and self-exploration. We must strive to separate religion from politics, nurturing an environment where diverse beliefs can coexist harmoniously. By fostering such an environment, we can encourage intellectual growth, mutual respect, and compassion among individuals of different faiths and philosophies.</p>



<p>In our modern world, it is essential to recognize the inherent value of diversity in belief systems. Instead of viewing differences as threats or challenges to one&#8217;s own faith, we should embrace them as opportunities for personal growth and collective enlightenment. Just as Eastern philosophies have thrived through their acceptance of multiple paths to spiritual realization, we can also appreciate the richness and depth that different religious traditions bring to the tapestry of human existence.</p>



<p>Moreover, the history of politically motivated churches, witch hunts, and the Inquisition serves as a reminder of the dangers of religious extremism and the abuse of power. It compels us to question the influence of political agendas within religious institutions and to safeguard against the suppression of individual freedoms and the persecution of those with differing beliefs.</p>



<p>By promoting dialogue, education, and interfaith understanding, we can break down the barriers that separate us and foster a sense of unity and shared purpose. Humanity can draw inspiration from the wisdom and teachings of Eastern philosophies, which encourage introspection, compassion, and the pursuit of inner harmony.</p>



<p>The comparison between Eastern philosophies and Western religions offers valuable insights and lessons for humanity. By embracing tolerance, self-exploration, and harmonious coexistence, we can create a world where diverse beliefs are celebrated and where spiritual growth is nurtured. Let us strive to learn from history and work towards a future where respect, compassion, and understanding are the guiding principles that unite us in our quest for meaning and purpose.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">881</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
