<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Fiction &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/fiction/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 01:02:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Fiction &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">222527107</site>	<item>
		<title>Maldoror Meets Joker</title>
		<link>/maldoror-meets-joker/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 02:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/maldoror-meets-joker/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;It is not right that everyone should read the pages which follow; only a few will be able to savour this bitter fruit with impunity. Consequently, shrinking soul, turn on your heels and go back before penetrating further into such uncharted, perilous wastelands.&#8221; — Maldoror, Part I,&#160; Part 1. In a dimly lit corner of the decrepit bar, shrouded in an atmosphere teeming with sinister secrets, Maldoror sat patiently in a booth, his features hidden beneath the shadowy haze. He had arrived early, as was his meticulous nature, awaiting the arrival of someone he had only heard whispers &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">&#8220;It is not right that everyone should read the pages which follow; only a few will be able to savour this bitter fruit with impunity. Consequently, shrinking soul, turn on your heels and go back before penetrating further into such uncharted, perilous wastelands.&#8221;</p>



<p>— <em>Maldoror</em>, Part I,&nbsp;</p>



<p>Part 1.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">In a dimly lit corner of the decrepit bar, shrouded in an atmosphere teeming with sinister secrets, Maldoror sat patiently in a booth, his features hidden beneath the shadowy haze. He had arrived early, as was his meticulous nature, awaiting the arrival of someone he had only heard whispers of &#8211; a man bearing the name Joker.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">As the cacophony of whispered conversations reached their zenith, the dissonant symphony abruptly ceased. The Joker emerged from the shadows, his presence commanding yet tinged with an air of unpredictable madness. He approached the booth, sliding into the seat opposite Maldoror. His greasy, green hair framed his painted face, etching a twisted grin that intimated both amusement and menace.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">&#8220;Greetings, Maldoror,&#8221; The Joker uttered in a voice that danced on the precipice of sanity. &#8220;I must admit, I am intrigued by your reputation. Your darkness rivals mine, or so I&#8217;ve heard.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror&#8217;s eyes, accentuated by the depths of his hood, met the piercing gaze of The Joker. &#8220;Likewise, Joker. Your reputation precedes you as a purveyor of chaos, a conduit for the fettered psyche. A kinship of malevolence, if you will.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">A brief chuckle escaped The Joker&#8217;s lips, as if echoes of deranged amusement lurked within his laughter. &#8220;Indeed. Malevolence and chaos, the tendrils that intertwine the fabric of our existence. Tell me, Maldoror, do you revel in your wickedness? Does it sustain you, as it does me?&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror leaned back, his voice a creeping whisper that adhered to the very air itself. &#8220;Wickedness sustains no mortal, but it is a plague that envelops the soul. Our affliction resides not in the act itself, but in the exploration of the abyss it reveals.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s eyes gleamed with a manic spark, recognizing the depth of the enigma before him. &#8220;Ah, so you too find solace in the abyss. It is there that we find our true selves, untethered by morality&#8217;s chains. How delightful it is to dance upon the edges of society&#8217;s acceptance.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror&#8217;s gloved hand brushed a strand of dark hair from his forehead. &#8220;The dance of darkness is but a waltz, a mere prelude to the symphony of the void. Society recoils, not from our wickedness, but from the ugliness it reflects at its core.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s face contorted with a mixture of curiosity and delight. &#8220;How beautifully put, Maldoror. Society is the grand comedy, a theater of grotesque masks concealing their own inner depravity. We, my friend, are merely the jesters who dare to reveal the truth.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">A slight smirk played upon Maldoror&#8217;s lips, an acknowledgment of mutual understanding. &#8220;One cannot help but wonder, Joker, if it is the nature of humanity to reject the darkness or if it is the darkness within humanity that incites rejection. A question that dances upon the dagger&#8217;s edge.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s laughter erupted, the sound bouncing off the bar&#8217;s grimy walls like a discordant symphony. &#8220;To dwell in the darkness is to embrace the unknown, to strip away the veneer of civilization and reveal the twisted masterpiece beneath. We, Maldoror, are the brushstrokes of chaos upon the canvas of a morally bankrupt world.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror leaned forward, his voice dropping to a conspiratorial whisper. &#8220;Ah, and you are our Pagliacci, the clown whose tears conceal the darkness within. You revel in chaos and mirth, yet beneath that painted façade lies a tragedy that resonates with the depths of my own being. And who is your Nedda? The Batman, forever chasing your shadow?&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">For a fleeting moment, a spark of indignation flashed across Joker&#8217;s eyes, a subtle sign of his private fury at the comparison. Yet, he maintained his composure, a twisted smile playing upon his lips. &#8220;Hah, you pierce the heart of the matter. Batman, my relentless pursuer, the embodiment of order and the delusion of truth. His obsession, our dance of duality, forever entwined in a perverse ballet.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s response carried a mix of admiration and contempt, a recognition of the complex relationship between himself and Batman. He understood the power of the dynamic they shared, the perpetual battle of light and dark, order and chaos, that defined their existence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror&#8217;s reference to Pagliacci, the tragic clown, struck a nerve within Joker, as it hinted at his private angst. Yet, he admired Maldoror&#8217;s perceptiveness, recognizing the shared tragedy that permeated their respective roles as the outcast.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">With a controlled laugh, The Joker replied, &#8220;Yes, Maldoror, the comedy and tragedy of our existence entangled, an eternal dance of mayhem.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Their words floated in the dimly lit booth, their conversation a symphony of macabre understanding and introspection. They spoke in riddles and metaphors, exploring the depths of their shared experiences, the complexities of their twisted psyches, and the peculiar beauty that emerged from their grotesque existence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Their discussion touched upon the fragility of sanity, the relentless search for freedom in a world bound by rules, and the masks society imposed upon them. They delved into the twisted allure of pain and the distorted sense of purpose they found within the chaotic dance of life.</p>



<p>As the conversation continued, Maldoror and Joker unraveled layers of their identities, revealing the profound depths of their sorrow and their shared alienation from the world. In their connection, however unsettling, they discovered a twisted solace, evoking pity for the world that could not grasp the complexities of their existence.</p>



<p>The Joker, still stinging from the comparison to Pagliacci, remained stoic, his respect for Maldoror unyielding. They were kindred spirits, each bearing their own burden of darkness and madness, forever destined to clash with those who sought to enforce order upon their chaotic souls.</p>



<p>As the conversation delved deeper into the realms of philosophical inquiry, their words reverberated against the backdrop of whispered secrets and murky intent.</p>



<p>As The Joker&#8217;s mind wandered, the tendrils of his imagination began to intertwine the figure of Mervyn with the enigmatic Maldoror. In this fevered reverie, he envisioned Mervyn, his forgotten self, as both a victim and a figure of intense affection in Maldoror&#8217;s twisted world.</p>



<p>In his hallucinatory vision, Mervyn appeared as a fragile being, a puppet ensnared by the strings of Maldoror&#8217;s chaotic whims. The Joker saw Mervyn as the embodiment of vulnerability, an innocent soul trapped within the web of Maldoror&#8217;s intricate darkness. The juxtaposition of their roles stirred a mixture of emotions within The Joker &#8211; a blend of protective tenderness and an insatiable desire to see Mervyn consumed by the depths of Maldoror&#8217;s madness.</p>



<p>In this macabre play of the mind, The Joker&#8217;s thoughts warped further, transforming Mervyn into an object of twisted adoration. He imagined Mervyn as his first true love, a fragile connection that surpassed the boundaries of sanity. Joker&#8217;s heart, if it could still be called that, ached with a mélange of melancholic longing and perverse possessiveness. Mervyn became the epitome of his past innocence, a fractured mirror reflecting the fragmented pieces of his own shattered self.</p>



<p>As this fantastical projection played out within The Joker&#8217;s mind, he relished the notion of Mervyn becoming intertwined with Maldoror&#8217;s darkness. He envisioned their relationship as a dance of obsession and destruction, a tumultuous union fueled by shared pain and the depths of their respective tragedies.</p>



<p>This twisted imagining both thrilled and tormented The Joker. It was a dark fantasy, an exploration of the boundaries of his own deranged desires. The lines between reality and illusion blurred as he indulged in the fervor of his imagination, finding perverse satisfaction in the union of Mervyn and Maldoror within the labyrinth of his own mind.</p>



<p>As the visions faded, The Joker was left with a sense of bitter longing, a void that yearned for the union of these disparate elements. The reality of their separation settled in, reminding him that Mervyn was lost within his own fragmented memories and Maldoror remained an enigmatic presence beyond his grasp.</p>



<p>The Joker&#8217;s contemplation of Mervyn as Maldoror&#8217;s victim and first true love remained a private and tortured secret. It served as a twisted reminder of the intricate tapestry of his own psyche, and the deep-seated longing for connection that resided within the depths of his chaotic soul.</p>



<p>In this corner of the world, where malevolence seldom found a willing ear, Maldoror and The Joker found a kinship of sinister minds, united in their shared darkness. And as the night wore on, their discourse echoed through the decaying bar &#8211; a nod to those who would dare to explore the depths of their souls.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">954</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
