<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Humor &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/humor/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:54:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Humor &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Notes on Masonry and Comparison to Other Orders</title>
		<link>/superficial-notes-on-masonry-and-a-very-brief-comparison-to-other-occult-orders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 21:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1. Origins and History: &#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucianism emerged in the early 17th century with the publication of the Rosicrucian manifestos. It gained popularity in Europe during the Renaissance and Enlightenment periods. &#8211; Freemasonry: Freemasonry has ancient roots and evolved from medieval stonemason guilds. The modern form of Freemasonry emerged in the 17th and 18th centuries, with lodges established throughout Europe and later in other parts of the world. 2. Membership and Organization: &#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucians often form smaller, esoteric and philosophical study groups or mystical orders. Membership is typically limited to individuals who have a sincere interest &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-cover is-light is-repeated wp-duotone-707070-ffffff-1" style="min-height:145px"><span aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-cover__background has-background-dim-30 has-background-dim"></span><div role="img" class="wp-block-cover__image-background wp-image-489 is-repeated" style="background-position:50% 50%;background-image:url(/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/freemason-symbol-set-icon-signs-600w-1657190194-transformed-300x110.jpeg)"></div><div class="wp-block-cover__inner-container is-layout-flow wp-block-cover-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-center has-sitebg-color has-text-color has-larger-font-size"><mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" class="has-inline-color has-sitebg-color"><strong>Notes on Public Occult Orders</strong></mark></p>
</div></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1. Origins and History:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism emerged in the early 17th century with the publication of the Rosicrucian manifestos. It gained popularity in Europe during the Renaissance and Enlightenment periods.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry has ancient roots and evolved from medieval stonemason guilds. The modern form of Freemasonry emerged in the 17th and 18th centuries, with lodges established throughout Europe and later in other parts of the world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">2. Membership and Organization:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucians often form smaller, esoteric and philosophical study groups or mystical orders. Membership is typically limited to individuals who have a sincere interest in esoteric studies and spiritual development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry operates in lodges, which are local organizations that serve as meeting places for members. Freemasonry has a hierarchical structure with degrees of initiation, including the Entered Apprentice, Fellow Craft, and Master Mason degrees.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">3. Philosophical and Spiritual Orientation:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism places emphasis on the pursuit of spiritual wisdom, inner transformation, and personal evolution. It draws upon mystical Christianity, Hermeticism, and alchemy to seek spiritual insights and attain union with the Divine.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry is not inherently tied to any specific religious or philosophical system. It is a fraternal organization that promotes moral and ethical principles, brotherhood, and charitable work. Freemasonry encourages members to practice their own faith and seek personal improvement.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">4. Rituals and Symbolism:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian rituals often incorporate alchemical symbolism and meditative practices. Rosicrucians may use visualizations, symbolic gestures, and contemplative exercises to deepen their understanding and spiritual connection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry utilizes symbolic rituals and allegories to impart moral and philosophical teachings. It employs tools and symbols from the stonemason trade, such as the square, compass, and the apron, to convey ethical principles and life lessons.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">5. Focus on Esoteric Knowledge:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism places a strong emphasis on esoteric knowledge, including mystical teachings, hermetic philosophy, alchemical symbolism, and metaphysical concepts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>While Freemasonry incorporates symbolic and allegorical teachings, it does not have an explicit focus on esoteric knowledge. Freemasonry aims to promote personal growth, moral virtues, and social fellowship.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">6. Membership Requirements:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br />&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian orders often have specific membership requirements, which can include a vetting process, adherence to certain ethical principles, and a commitment to study and personal development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry requires potential members to be of lawful age, believe in a Supreme Being, and have good moral character. It emphasizes equality, brotherhood, and mutual respect among members.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">7. Public Visibility and Influence:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian orders, such as the Ancient Mystical Order Rosae Crucis (AMORC) and the Rosicrucian Fellowship, have established public presence and offer educational materials and correspondence courses to the public.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry is more widely recognized and visible, with Masonic lodges often present in communities worldwide. Freemasonry has historically played a significant role in philanthropy, community service, and social networks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">PART #2:</h2>



<p>Shriners are Freemasons. The Shriners is an appendant body of Freemasonry, specifically associated with the Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine, commonly known as Shriners International. Shriners are Freemasons who have attained the third degree, or Master Mason, in their respective Masonic lodges. The Shriners focus on charitable work, particularly supporting Shriners Hospitals for Children, which provides specialized medical care to children.</p>



<p>On the other hand, the Loyal Order of Buffaloes (often referred to as Buffalos or LOB) is a separate fraternal organization and not directly affiliated with Freemasonry. The Loyal Order of Buffaloes is an independent fraternity that promotes social fellowship, charity, and community involvement. While the Buffalos may share some similarities in terms of fellowship and community service, they are distinct from Freemasonry and do not require Masonic membership to join.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Buffaloes (LOB) is a fraternal organization that has had a presence primarily in the United Kingdom, Australia, and Canada. While the LOB does not have the same level of visibility as some other fraternal organizations, it has had a number of notable members throughout its history. Here are a few examples:</p>



<p>1. Charlie Chaplin: The legendary silent film actor and filmmaker was reported to be a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>2. Danny La Rue: The British entertainer, known for his drag performances and variety shows, was also a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>3. Anthony Eden: Sir Anthony Eden, a British politician who served as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom from 1955 to 1957, was a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>4. Bob Monkhouse: The British comedian, actor, and television presenter was a member of the LOB and often mentioned his involvement with the organization in his performances.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that while these individuals were reported to be members of the Loyal Order of Buffaloes, membership in fraternal organizations is often private, and specific details may not be widely available or confirmed.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Water Buffalos, however, is a fictional organization that parodies the Loyal Order of Buffaloes. It originated in the animated television series &#8220;The Flintstones.&#8221; In the show, the Loyal Order of Water Buffalos is depicted as a men&#8217;s fraternal organization to which Fred Flintstone and his friend Barney Rubble belong. It is portrayed as a humorous exaggeration of traditional fraternal organizations, highlighting the rituals, secret handshakes, and comedic initiation ceremonies often associated with such groups.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Water Buffalos serves as a satirical representation of real-life fraternal organizations, including the Loyal Order of Buffaloes. Its purpose in the show is primarily comedic and provides a backdrop for humorous situations and storytelling. It is important to note that the fictional Loyal Order of Water Buffalos should not be confused with the actual Loyal Order of Buffaloes, which is a genuine fraternal organization that promotes fellowship and charitable endeavors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Power of Parody Religions: Finding Kinship and Healing Through Satire</title>
		<link>/parody-religions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 19:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self Help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=68</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Parody: The Healing Voice of No Reason Parody religions challenge conventional norms, and offer unique perspectives on spirituality. In a world dominated by mainstream religions, this is necessary.. They are satirical religions that seem unconventional or even nonsensical. However, they serve the profound purpose of giving shelter to those needing it. They offer solace, community, and a sense of belonging to those who find themselves at odds with traditional religious institutions. In this post, we will explore how these groups can be socially healthy, offering a haven for those who need it. . The Church of the &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-parody-the-healing-voice-of-no-reason">Parody: The Healing Voice of No Reason</h2>



<p>Parody religions challenge conventional norms, and offer unique perspectives on spirituality. In a world dominated by mainstream religions, this is necessary.. They are satirical religions that seem unconventional or even nonsensical. However, they serve the profound purpose of giving shelter to those needing it. They offer solace, community, and a sense of belonging to those who find themselves at odds with traditional religious institutions. In this post, we will explore how these groups can be socially healthy, offering a haven for those who need it. .</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-church-of-the-subgenius-embracing-absurdity-as-a-path-to-liberation">The Church of the SubGenius: Embracing Absurdity as a Path to Liberation</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Church of the SubGenius, founded in the 1980s, thrives on the idea of embracing absurdity. By blending elements of conspiracy theories, science fiction, and humor, it presents itself as a parody of religious dogma. It appears nonsensical on the surface, the Church of the SubGenius encourages followers to question authority. It promotes satire, silliness and a joking sense of arrogance as virtues. As they, reject societal norms, and find personal liberation. In a society that often expects conformity, the SubGenius movement offers an outlet for the alienated and distrustful. .</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Within the Church of the SubGenius, the concepts of the Xists, JR &#8220;Bob&#8221; Dobbs, and Slack play significant roles. Let&#8217;s explore each of these elements:</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-xists">The Xists</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong> </strong>The Xists are extraterrestrial beings depicted in the teachings of the Church of the SubGenius. According to the church&#8217;s mythology, the Xists are a race of alien overlords who plan to enslave humanity. They represent a satirical critique of conspiracy theories, parodies of apocalyptic prophecies, and the fear of external control.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Church of the SubGenius uses the concept of the Xists to explore themes of individual sovereignty. They represent skepticism towards authority, and the subversion of mainstream beliefs. The Xists serve as a fictional construct that encourages followers to question societal norms and reject oppressive systems.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-jr-bob-dobbs">JR &#8220;Bob&#8221; Dobbs</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">JR &#8220;Bob&#8221; Dobbs is the iconic figurehead and self-proclaimed prophet of the Church of the SubGenius. Often depicted as a mysterious salesman with a pipe and a wide-brimmed hat, Dobbs embodies the spirit of the trickster. He is a sly character who challenges established norms and promotes individual freedom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Dobbs represents a satirical take on religious leaders and charismatic figures. The Church of the SubGenius uses the persona of Dobbs to encourage followers to find their own path to enlightenment. Bob encourages and embraces absurdity, and seeks personal liberation. The character of JR &#8220;Bob&#8221; Dobbs serves as a symbol of the pursuit of &#8220;Slack.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-slack">Slack</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Slack is a central concept in the teachings of the Church of the SubGenius. It is a state of being characterized by personal fulfillment, satisfaction, and freedom from oppressive forces. Slack represents an individual&#8217;s ability to break free from societal expectations, finding purpose. Through Slack, one can live a life of enjoyment and fulfillment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-summary-of-the-church-of-the-subgenius">Summary of the Church of the Subgenius</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Church of the SubGenius sees Slack as a valuable resource that mainstream society seeks to suppress and control. Through humor and satire, the church encourages its followers to seek and embrace Slack by rejecting conformity and questioning authority. Embracing their unique quirks and desires, and becoming individuals who think for themselves.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Church of the SubGenius uses the concepts of the Xists, JR &#8220;Bob&#8221; Dobbs, and Slack to challenge societal norms. They question authority, and promote personal liberation. These elements serve as satirical devices that encourage followers to find their own path. They teach us to reject oppressive systems, and embrace the absurdity of existence.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-large-font-size" id="h-pastafarianism-a-delicious-take-on-satire-and-freedom-of-expression"><strong>Pastafarianism: A Delicious Take on Satire and Freedom of Expression</strong></h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Pastafarianism, symbolized by the Flying Spaghetti Monster, emerged as a response to the teaching of intelligent design in schools. It uses satire to criticize the encroachment of religious beliefs into public education. The Church of the Flying Spaghetti Monster may seem whimsical. Symbolized by a pirate regalia and reverence for pasta, but beneath the humorous façade lies a powerful message. The promotion of scientific literacy, secularism, and the right to express one&#8217;s beliefs in unconventional ways. Pastafarianism has been successful in challenging the privileging of certain religious beliefs. They successfully highlighting the importance of separation between church and state.</p>



<p>Discordianism: Embracing Chaos and Illuminating the Absurdities of Life</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Discordianism, inspired by the Principia Discordia, is a parody religion that revels in chaos and embraces absurdity. With their playful approach to spirituality, Discordians reject dogma and instead celebrate randomness, humor, and self-expression. The Principia Discordia outlines the &#8220;5 Suggestions&#8221;. These encourage individuals to find humor in life, question authority, and celebrate the absurdities that permeate our existence. By challenging the seriousness and rigidity often associated with traditional religions, Discordianism fosters an environment of camaraderie and self-discovery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-discordianism-the-beginning">Discordianism: The Beginning</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">According to the Principia Discordia, the story of how the Golden Apple fell is a central myth within Discordianism. What follows is a summary of the tale as described in the Principia Discordia. In the beginning, there was chaos, represented by the goddess Eris, the Greek goddess of strife and discord. Eris, known as Discordia in Discordianism, was not invited to the wedding of Peleus and Thetis. Thetis was a mortal and a sea nymph. Feeling slighted, Eris decided to disrupt the festivities. She threw a golden apple into the midst of the goddesses attending the wedding.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-jealousy">The Jealousy</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The apple was inscribed with the words &#8220;To the Fairest,&#8221;. This lead to a dispute among the goddesses as each claimed the title for herself. The three primary contenders for the apple were Hera, Athena, and Aphrodite. Unable to resolve the argument, they sought the judgment of Paris, a mortal prince.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">In return for his decision, each goddess offered Paris a bribe. Hera promised him power and riches. Athena offered him wisdom and victory in battle. Aphrodite tempted him with the love of the most beautiful woman in the world, Helen of Troy. Paris, swayed by Aphrodite&#8217;s offer, awarded her the golden apple.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-result">The Result</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">This act sparked the Trojan War, a legendary conflict in Greek mythology. The story of the Golden Apple falling symbolizes the chaos and discord that can arise from small acts or decisions. They can set into motion significant consequences. In Discordianism, the story of the Golden Apple falling should be interpreted metaphorically. It represents the disruptive power of discord and the recognition that chaos and disorder are integral parts of existence. Embracing the chaos and discord, Discordians find liberation and meaning in the absurdity of life.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-sacred-text">The Sacred Text</h2>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The &#8220;Discordian Bible&#8221;, Principia Discordia, has in place of ten commandments, five suggestions, known collectively as the Pentabarf. The Pentabarf was, according to Discordian legend, discovered by the hermit Apostle Zarathud in the Fifth Year of The Caterpillar. He found them carved in gilded stone, while building a sun deck for his cave. Their importance was lost, because they were written in a mysterious cypher. However, after 10 weeks &amp; 11 hours of intensive scrutiny he discerned that the message. It could only be read by standing on his head and viewing it upside down. It read:</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-know-ye-this-o-man-of-faith">KNOW YE THIS O MAN OF FAITH!</h2>



<p class="has-large-font-size"><strong>I</strong> &#8211; There is no Goddess but Goddess and She is Your Goddess. There is no Erisian Movement but The Erisian Movement and it is The Erisian Movement. And every Golden Apple Corps is the beloved home of a Golden Worm.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong>II</strong> &#8211; A Discordian Shall Always use the Official Discordian Document Numbering System.</p>



<p><strong>III</strong> &#8211; A Discordian is Required during his early Illumination to Go Off Alone &amp; Partake Joyously of a Hot Dog on a Friday. This Devotive Ceremony to Remonstrate against the popular Paganisms of the Day: of Catholic Christendom (no meat on Friday), of Judaism (no meat of Pork), of Hindic Peoples (no meat of Beef), of Buddhists (no meat of animal), and of Discordians (no Hot Dog Buns).</p>



<p><strong>IV</strong> &#8211; A Discordian shall Partake of No Hot Dog Buns, for Such was the Solace of Our Goddess when She was Confronted with The Original Snub.</p>



<p><strong>V</strong> &#8211; A Discordian is Prohibited of Believing what he reads.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-it-is-so-written-so-be-it-hail-discordia-prosecutors-will-be-transgressicuted">IT IS SO WRITTEN! SO BE IT. HAIL DISCORDIA! PROSECUTORS WILL BE TRANSGRESSICUTED.</h2>



<p>__________________________________________________________________________________________</p>



<p>The metaphor in this text, as in the book, is as clear as it is beautiful. It means:</p>



<p><strong>I</strong> &#8211; This commandment asserts the primacy of the individual&#8217;s personal connection with the divine. It states that there is no specific goddess or deity to worship. Each individual must find their own understanding of the divine. Their definition is valid and must be honored. This promotes a sense of personal sovereignty and encourages followers to define their own spiritual beliefs.</p>



<p><strong>II</strong> &#8211; This commandment humorously states that Discordians should use the Official Discordian Document Numbering System. It reflects the playful and irreverent nature of Discordianism, emphasizing the importance of embracing absurdity and disregarding conventional numbering systems.</p>



<p><strong>III</strong> &#8211; This commandment instructs Discordians, during their early spiritual journey or &#8220;Illumination. A devotional ceremony of joyously partaking in a hot dog on a Friday. The ceremony contrasts with the dietary restrictions or taboos found in various religions. It highlighs the satirical nature of Discordianism and its rejection of rigid belief systems.</p>



<p><strong>IV</strong> &#8211; This commandment extends from the previous one, stating that Discordians should not partake of hot dog buns. The reason given is a reference to the &#8220;Original Snub,&#8221; a humorous event involving the goddess Eris. Through it, we honor the lie of Eris (Discordia) and a hot dog bun. The No Hot Dog Bun highlights the nonsensical and satirical nature of Discordian practices.</p>



<p><strong>V</strong> &#8211; This commandment prohibits Discordians from blindly believing everything they read. It promotes a skeptical and critical approach to information, encouraging followers to question, analyze, and discern the truth for themselves. It reflects the emphasis on individual thinking and personal responsibility within Discordianism.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-contradiction-is-valid">Contradiction is Valid</h2>



<p>These suggestions serve as a playful and satirical framework for navigating life, embracing chaos. They challenge conventional thinking, while playfully emphasizes the ever-changing and contradictory nature of existence. Discordians must embrace the fluidity of their beliefs and opinions. They recognize that consistency can sometimes stifle growth and creativity. By embracing contradiction, Discordians invite a more flexible and open-minded approach to life. This allows for the exploration of diverse perspectives and ideas. Discordianism embraces absurdity and nonconformity, and symbolizes the celebration of individuality, encouraging followers to express themselves freely and authentically.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-healing-power-of-parody-religions-finding-kinship-and-belonging-and-a-safe-space-for-nonconformists">The Healing Power of Parody Religions: Finding Kinship and Belonging and<strong> a Safe Space for Nonconformists</strong></h2>



<p>Parody religions provide a refuge for individuals who feel alienated or marginalized by mainstream religious institutions. They offer a sense of community, and acceptance to those who may not fit neatly into societal or religious molds.  By embracing humor and irreverence, these movements create spaces where people can express themselves without fear.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-satire-as-catharsis"><strong>Satire as Catharsis</strong></h2>



<p>Parody religions are a cathartic release for individuals who have been hurt or disillusioned by religious dogma. Through satire and absurdity, followers can find solace and healing. They allow us to reclaim autonomy and find humor in the institutions that may have caused us pain or confusion.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-fostering-creativity-and-critical-thinking"><strong>Fostering Creativity and Critical Thinking</strong></h2>



<p>Parody religions encourage followers to think critically, question established beliefs, and challenge the status quo. By satirizing religious and societal norms, these movements inspire creative and independent thinking. They allow individuals to explore alternative perspectives and expand their intellectual horizons. The freedom to question and challenge authority within parody religions promotes a culture of intellectual curiosity and fosters personal growth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-building-supportive-communities"><strong>Building Supportive Communities</strong></h2>



<p>Parody religions create tight-knit communities where individuals can find support, empathy, and understanding. By gathering like-minded people who share a similar sense of humor and skepticism, these movements form social networks. These networks that provide emotional support and camaraderie for the misfits &#8211; who are often the best people.. In a world where many struggle to find acceptance, parody religions offer a space where people can form meaningful connections. They give us an opportunity to forge lifelong friendships, outside the realm of conformity.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-challenging-religious-privilege-and-promoting-tolerance"><strong>Challenging Religious Privilege and Promoting Tolerance</strong></h2>



<p>Parody religions serve as a powerful tool for challenging religious privilege and promoting religious tolerance. By parodying established religion and presenting themselves as equally valid, they highlight the arbitrary nature of religious beliefs. This satirical approach prompts important conversations about the boundaries of religious freedom. They underline the need for separation of church and state, and respect and inclusively towards diverse belief systems.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion</h2>



<p>In closing, these parody religions may initially seem frivolous or absurd, but they offer solace, community, and a sense of belonging. By embracing humor, satire, and irreverence, these movements offer an alternative path for spiritual exploration, personal liberation, and critical thinking. Through their inclusive and supportive communities, parody religions provide a haven for nonconformists, fostering kinship and acceptance. In a world that often demands conformity, these movements remind us of the importance of individuality. They highlight the inherent subjectivity and relativity of truth, emphasizing that individual interpretations and experiences shape our understanding of reality. By embracing a multitude of beliefs, they promote tolerance and inclusivity, encouraging others to respect diverse viewpoints.</p>



<p>The Suggestions of Discordianism, like the philosophy behind many parody religions, must be taken with humor and irony. They serve as a reminder to challenge rigid thinking, embrace chaos, and find joy in the absurdities of life. Through these playful suggestions, we can create a framework that celebrates individuality, critical thinking, and the liberation of the mind. These core principles embrace absurdity, skepticism, and the challenging of established beliefs. They do so by using humor and satire as tools for personal liberation and subversion of societal norms. And the Goddess knows, we need more subversion of the norm.</p>


<p>[serious-slider id=44]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Divine Felines: Cats in Ancient Egypt, the Black Death, Witchcraft, and Aleister Crowley&#8217;s Fascination</title>
		<link>/the-divine-felines-cats-in-ancient-egypt-the-black-death-witchcraft-and-aleister-crowleys-fascination/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 16:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pets]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cats have held a special place in human history, often associated with mysticism, magic, and divine powers. From their revered status in ancient Egypt to their role during the Black Death, as well as their connection to witchcraft and occultism, the captivating allure of these enigmatic creatures has transcended time. Furthermore, the opinions of influential figures such as Aleister Crowley have shed light on their significance and symbolism. 1. Cats: The Divine Beings of Ancient Egypt: In ancient Egypt, cats were regarded as sacred creatures and were revered as manifestations of various deities, notably Bastet, the goddess &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Cats have held a special place in human history, often associated with mysticism, magic, and divine powers. From their revered status in ancient Egypt to their role during the Black Death, as well as their connection to witchcraft and occultism, the captivating allure of these enigmatic creatures has transcended time. Furthermore, the opinions of influential figures such as Aleister Crowley have shed light on their significance and symbolism.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>1. Cats: The Divine Beings of Ancient Egypt:</strong></p>



<p><br>In ancient Egypt, cats were regarded as sacred creatures and were revered as manifestations of various deities, notably Bastet, the goddess of protection, fertility, and home. They were highly regarded, often mummified, and buried with their owners to accompany them in the afterlife. Killing a cat, even accidentally, was considered sacrilegious and a grave offense.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>2. Cats: The Unsung Heroes of the Black Death:</strong></p>



<p><br>During the devastating period of the Black Death in Europe, cats played a crucial role in curbing the spread of the disease. As carriers of fleas, which were the primary vectors for the plague, cats instinctively hunted and eliminated rodents, particularly rats, which were responsible for harboring these fleas. Their valiant efforts inadvertently protected humans and helped save countless lives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>3. Cats and Witchcraft: A Feline Connection:</strong></p>



<p><br>Unfortunately, the association between cats and witchcraft arose during the Middle Ages. Cats&#8217; nocturnal habits, enigmatic behaviors, and their independent nature led them to be linked with witchcraft and dark practices. These associations led to cats being persecuted and killed during the infamous witch hunts, as they were seen as familiars or companions to witches.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>4. Aleister Crowley&#8217;s Opinion on Cats:</strong></p>



<p><br>Aleister Crowley, a renowned occultist and key figure in the esoteric tradition of the 20th century, had varied opinions on cats. While he did not explicitly express his views on cats in his writings, he did reference feline symbolism and imagery in his magical system known as Thelema. Crowley often associated cats with independence, sexuality, mystery, and the exploration of the deeper aspects of human consciousness.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>5. Cats in Modern Occultism:</strong></p>



<p><br>Cats continue to be intertwined with occultism and modern spiritual practices. Many practitioners of witchcraft, Wicca, and various pagan traditions perceive cats as spiritual allies and possessors of arcane knowledge. Their grace, stealth, and aloof yet intuitive nature make them potent symbols of esoteric exploration and the mysteries of the unconscious mind.<br>From their divine status in ancient Egypt to their instrumental role during the Black Death and subsequent association with witchcraft, cats have garnered an everlasting allure, representing the enigmatic but aloof character. Their mysterious nature has attracted the fascination of figures like Aleister Crowley, who saw in them a reflection of human sexuality and untamed spiritual power. As we continue to explore the realms of occultism, cats remain present, intertwined with symbolism and embodying the indomitable spirit of magic and mystery.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ham Radio and Contemporary Occultism: Exploring Overlapping Realms</title>
		<link>/ham-radio-and-contemporary-occultism-exploring-overlapping-realms/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 15:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ham Radio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=99</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The realms of ham radio and contemporary occultism, particularly Thelema, may at first seem disconnected, but upon closer examination, intriguing overlaps emerge. Both pursuits share common threads of exploration, experimentation, and a fascination with hidden knowledge. Let&#8217;s delve into how these seemingly distinct realms can intersect and how practitioners of ham radio and Thelema can find common ground. 1. Communication and Connection: One of the primary functions of ham radio is communication, enabling operators to connect with fellow enthusiasts around the world. Similarly, contemporary occultism, including Thelema, emphasizes the pursuit of communication with forces beyond the mundane &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The realms of ham radio and contemporary occultism, particularly Thelema, may at first seem disconnected, but upon closer examination, intriguing overlaps emerge. Both pursuits share common threads of exploration, experimentation, and a fascination with hidden knowledge. Let&#8217;s delve into how these seemingly distinct realms can intersect and how practitioners of ham radio and Thelema can find common ground.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>1. Communication and Connection:</strong></p>



<p><br>One of the primary functions of ham radio is communication, enabling operators to connect with fellow enthusiasts around the world. Similarly, contemporary occultism, including Thelema, emphasizes the pursuit of communication with forces beyond the mundane realm. In Thelema, practitioners seek to establish contact with their Holy Guardian Angel or other spiritual entities through ritual, meditation, and divination. Both ham radio and Thelema involve reaching out, making connections, and exploring realms beyond the ordinary.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>2. Symbolism and Codes:</strong></p>



<p><br>Ham radio operates with its own set of symbols and codes, such as Morse code, phonetic alphabets, and abbreviations. Similarly, occult traditions employ symbolic systems and codes to represent concepts, energies, and hidden truths. Thelema, for example, incorporates a complex symbolism based on numerology, astrology, and Egyptian mythology. Both ham radio and Thelema engage in the use of symbolic languages to convey meaning and communicate on deeper levels.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>3. Technical Skill and Mastery:</strong></p>



<p><br>Operating ham radio equipment requires technical knowledge, proficiency in radio technology, and the ability to navigate the intricacies of frequencies, modulation, and propagation. In a parallel vein, practitioners of Thelema often dedicate themselves to the mastery of ceremonial magick, ritual practices, and esoteric systems. Both pursuits demand a commitment to study, practice, and refinement of skills to achieve desired outcomes.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>4. Exploration and Experimentation:</strong></p>



<p><br>Ham radio enthusiasts are known for their spirit of exploration, pushing the boundaries of communication technology, and experimenting with new techniques and equipment. Similarly, practitioners of Thelema engage in personal exploration, seeking to unlock hidden potentials, expand consciousness, and explore mystical realms. Both pursuits encourage curiosity, open-mindedness, and a willingness to venture into uncharted territories.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>5. Community and Fraternity:</strong></p>



<p><br>Ham radio has a strong sense of community, with operators forming networks, clubs, and associations to share knowledge, experiences, and camaraderie. Similarly, occult communities, including Thelema, foster a sense of fraternity, where like-minded individuals come together to exchange ideas, support one another&#8217;s spiritual journeys, and collaborate on rituals or magical workings. Both realms offer opportunities for networking, mentoring, and forming meaningful connections with others who share similar interests and passions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>6. Radio as a Medium for Magickal Practice:</strong></p>



<p><br>Some practitioners of contemporary occultism have explored the use of radio as a medium for magickal practice. They utilize the radio waves and frequencies as conduits for energy, intent, and communication with spiritual entities. This practice aligns with the concept of harnessing natural forces and manipulating energies that is central to many occult traditions.</p>



<p>Ham radio and contemporary occultism, particularly Thelema, may appear disparate at first glance, they possess intriguing areas of overlap. Both pursuits involve communication, symbolism, exploration, technical skill, and a sense of community. They share a fascination with hidden knowledge, seeking connections beyond the mundane. By recognizing and exploring these commonalities, ham radio hobbyists&nbsp; and practitioners of Thelema can find opportunities for inspiration, cross-pollination of ideas, and a deeper understanding of the power of communication and exploration in their respective realms.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ham Radio and Psychedelic Drugs</title>
		<link>/ham-radio-and-psychedelic-drugs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 15:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ham Radio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=82</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Overlap of Psychedelic Drugs and Ham Radio: Exploring Inner and Outer Frontiers The realms of psychedelic drugs and ham radio might seem vastly different at first glance, but beneath the surface, intriguing connections can be found. Both pursuits involve exploration, altered states of consciousness, and the quest for connection—albeit through different means. Let&#8217;s delve into how psychedelic experiences and ham radio can overlap and intersect, revealing unique perspectives on human consciousness and communication. 1. Exploration of Consciousness: Psychedelic substances have long been associated with expanded states of consciousness, opening doors to profound insights, mystical experiences, and &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Overlap of Psychedelic Drugs and Ham Radio: Exploring Inner and Outer Frontiers</p>



<p>The realms of psychedelic drugs and ham radio might seem vastly different at first glance, but beneath the surface, intriguing connections can be found. Both pursuits involve exploration, altered states of consciousness, and the quest for connection—albeit through different means. Let&#8217;s delve into how psychedelic experiences and ham radio can overlap and intersect, revealing unique perspectives on human consciousness and communication.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>1. Exploration of Consciousness:</strong></p>



<p><br>Psychedelic substances have long been associated with expanded states of consciousness, opening doors to profound insights, mystical experiences, and altered perceptions of reality. Similarly, ham radio enthusiasts embark on a journey of exploration—exploring the boundaries of communication, pushing technical limits, and connecting with individuals across vast distances. Both realms share a common theme of venturing into uncharted territories and expanding the boundaries of human experience.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>2. Connection and Community:</strong></p>



<p><br>One of the remarkable aspects of ham radio is the sense of community it fosters. Operators come together, exchange knowledge, and form networks of communication across geographic boundaries. Similarly, the use of psychedelic drugs often facilitates a deep sense of connection, empathy, and shared experiences, creating a community of individuals who seek to explore the depths of consciousness. In both realms, participants find support, camaraderie, and shared understanding among like-minded individuals.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>3. Breaking Barriers and Limitations:</strong></p>



<p><br>Ham radio breaks down barriers of distance, allowing communication between people who might otherwise be separated by vast geographical expanses. Similarly, psychedelic experiences can dissolve barriers of perception, providing glimpses into expanded realities and interconnectedness. Both pursuits challenge conventional limitations and offer a glimpse into the vast potential of human connection and consciousness.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>4. Technological and Inner Exploration:</strong></p>



<p><br>Ham radio is an exploration of technology, involving the mastery of equipment, understanding of frequencies, and navigation of complex systems. Psychedelic experiences, on the other hand, offer inner exploration, providing insights into the workings of the mind, the nature of perception, and the interconnectedness of all things. Both realms engage in a form of exploration—outer or technological in the case of ham radio, and inner or psychological in the case of psychedelics.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>5. Artistic Expression and Creativity:</strong></p>



<p><br>Both psychedelic experiences and ham radio can ignite creativity and artistic expression. Many artists and musicians have drawn inspiration from their psychedelic journeys, creating works that convey ineffable experiences and transcendental insights. Similarly, ham radio operators often develop creative ways to communicate, experimenting with antennas, modes, and technology to express themselves through the medium of radio waves.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>6. Unconventional Perspectives:</strong></p>



<p><br>Both realms offer unconventional perspectives on the world. Psychedelic experiences can challenge societal norms, expand consciousness, and provide alternative viewpoints on reality. Similarly, ham radio operators often approach communication and technology from a non-mainstream perspective, challenging traditional modes of connection and finding innovative ways to bridge gaps.</p>



<p>It is important to note that the use of psychedelic substances is subject to legal restrictions in many jurisdictions. Prioritizing personal safety, adhering to legal guidelines, and being aware of potential risks and responsible use are essential considerations for anyone exploring psychedelic substances.</p>



<p>The overlap between psychedelic drugs and ham radio may not be immediately apparent, but upon closer examination, intriguing connections emerge. Both realms involve exploration, connection, and breaking barriers—whether through expanding consciousness or spanning geographic distances. By recognizing these intersections, individuals can gain unique insights into the depths of human experience, the nature of communication, and the vast potential of consciousness exploration.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
