<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>All &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/all/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 02:04:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>All &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">222527107</site>	<item>
		<title>The Role of N95 Respirators in Public Health: Understanding, Efficacy, and Misinformation</title>
		<link>/the-role-of-n95-respirators/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tobit]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 16:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2335</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Personal Introduction As a lifelong Libertarian and the author of this article, I consider mandates such as mask-wearing to be akin to seatbelt laws, or regulations against any behavior that is not immediately life-threatening. However, common sense should prevail in public health, especially during crises like the COVID-19 pandemic. We must educate ourselves in order to make sound decisions with less interference, whether that interference is from governments, large corporations, or politicians exploiting the poorly educated by misrepresenting basic science. In this article, we will address some of the misinformation that has circulated regarding the role of &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-personal-introduction">Personal Introduction</h2>



<p>As a lifelong Libertarian and the author of this article, I consider mandates such as mask-wearing to be akin to seatbelt laws, or regulations against any behavior that is not <em>immediately </em>life-threatening. However, common sense should prevail in public health, especially during crises like the COVID-19 pandemic. We must educate ourselves in order to make sound decisions with less interference, whether that interference is from governments, large corporations, or politicians exploiting the poorly educated by misrepresenting basic science. In this article, we will address some of the misinformation that has circulated regarding the role of N95 respirators.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-efficacy-of-n95-respirators-against-covid-19-the-science">The Efficacy of N95 Respirators Against COVID-19: The Science</h2>



<p>The global fight against COVID-19 has spotlighted the crucial role of N95 respirators. Understanding how these masks work provides clarity on their effectiveness and dispels prevalent myths. Let’s delve into the science behind each of their key functional aspects. N95 masks boast a filtration efficiency of 95% or higher, by targeting the larger droplets containing COVID virions. Recognized globally by health authorities like the CDC (US), PHAC (Canada), and others, there&#8217;s unanimous agreement on their effectiveness in curbing COVID-19 spread. No reputable health organization has opposed their use.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-1-filtration-of-larger-particles">1. Filtration of Larger Particles</h3>



<p>N95 masks are engineered to filter out 95% of particles that are 0.3 microns or larger. However, their efficacy extends beyond just the size filtration:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Particle Attachment</strong>: A significant portion of the virus-laden particles are expelled in respiratory droplets, which are generally larger than 5 microns. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) explains that these droplets are the primary means of COVID-19 transmission.</li>



<li><strong>Effectiveness</strong>: While the exact percentage varies, studies like this one from the Journal of Aerosol Science indicate that N95 masks are highly effective in capturing these larger particles, thereby significantly reducing the transmission of virus-laden droplets.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-2-n95-respirator-electrostatic-charge">2. N95 Respirator Electrostatic Charge</h3>



<p>One of the less discussed but vital features of N95 masks is their electrostatic nature:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>How It Works</strong>: The fibers in N95 masks are manufactured to have an electrostatic charge. As explained by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH), this charge enhances the filtration efficiency by attracting airborne particles.</li>



<li><strong>Mechanism of Attraction</strong>: This electrostatic attraction ensures that particles smaller than the mask&#8217;s physical pore size are still effectively captured, as detailed in research published in ACS Nano.</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-3-brownian-motion">3. Brownian Motion</h3>



<p>Brownian motion plays a subtle yet crucial role in the effectiveness of N95 masks.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Principle Theory</strong>: Brownian motion refers to the random movement of particles suspended in a fluid (like air). This concept, fundamental to physics and explained in resources like Khan Academy’s science lessons, shows that smaller particles move erratically.</li>



<li><strong>Impact on Filtration</strong>: This erratic movement increases the likelihood of small particles, such as virions, colliding with and being captured by the mask fibers. The Journal of Occupational and Environmental Hygiene provides insights into how this motion enhances the filtering efficiency for small particles.</li>



<li><strong>The Explain it Like I&#8217;m Five version</strong>: Imagine you have a tiny speck of dust floating in a glass of water. Even though you&#8217;re not touching it, you can see it moving around on its own. That&#8217;s because invisible tiny things in the water are always bumping into the speck, making it wiggle and move in different directions. It&#8217;s like the speck is playing a game of tag with the invisible water molecules, and it can go in any direction because it&#8217;s getting bumped from all sides. This wiggling and jiggling of tiny particles is what we call Brownian motion.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-adoption-of-n95-respirator-protocols-during-the-pandemic">Adoption of N95 Respirator Protocols During the Pandemic</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-worldwide-adoption-and-statistics">Worldwide Adoption and Statistics</h3>



<p>The use of N95 masks became widespread globally, with several countries implementing them as a key component of their COVID-19 response strategy. The adoption rate varied, influenced by government policies, public awareness, and availability. For instance, in countries like South Korea and New Zealand, the use of masks in public spaces was almost universal during peak pandemic periods. Contrastingly, in some Western countries, mask usage faced more resistance due to political and cultural factors.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-supply-and-distribution-challenges">Supply and Distribution Challenges</h3>



<p>Initially, the high demand for N95 masks led to shortages, affecting healthcare workers and the general public. This prompted efforts to ramp up production and distribution, with companies like 3M significantly increasing their output. Governments also intervened, with measures like the Defense Production Act in the United States, to ensure adequate supply for frontline workers.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-environmental-concerns">Environmental Concerns</h3>



<p>An unintended consequence of the mass use of masks has been environmental. The disposable nature of N95 masks has contributed to increased plastic waste. This has sparked discussions and research into more sustainable, biodegradable mask options, while maintaining the same level of protection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-studies-and-scientific-evidence-supporting-mask-use">Studies and Scientific Evidence Supporting Mask Use</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-research-studies">Research Studies</h3>



<p>Numerous studies have validated the effectiveness of masks. A pivotal study published in the journal &#8216;Science&#8217; demonstrated a significant reduction in COVID-19 transmission rates in areas with mask mandates. Another study in &#8216;The Lancet&#8217; provided a comprehensive analysis of physical distancing, face masks, and eye protection for preventing person-to-person virus transmission.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-real-world-impact-n95-respirators-versus-covid-19">Real-world Impact: N95 Respirators versus COVID-19</h3>



<p>Beyond laboratory tests, real-world data provided compelling evidence. Countries with high mask compliance saw more effective control and quicker reduction in COVID-19 cases. For example, a study in &#8216;Health Affairs&#8217; compared the growth rate of COVID-19 before and after mask mandates in 15 states and the District of Columbia, noting a slowdown in daily COVID-19 growth rates after mask mandates.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-meta-analyses">Meta-Analyses</h3>



<p>Meta-analyses, which combine data from multiple studies, have reinforced the effectiveness of masks. These comprehensive reviews have concluded that mask-wearing significantly reduces the risk of transmitting or contracting COVID-19, especially in combination with other preventive measures.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-mask-efficacy-against-variants">Mask Efficacy against Variants</h2>



<p>A prevalent misunderstanding is that masks are less effective against new virus variants. Yet, research consistently indicates that the primary transmission method (respiratory droplets) hasn&#8217;t changed, maintaining their effectiveness, cementing the role of N95 respirators.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-oxygen-levels-and-co2-accumulation">Oxygen Levels and CO2 Accumulation</h2>



<p>Claims that masks significantly reduce oxygen intake or cause harmful CO2 accumulation have been debunked by medical studies. Healthcare professionals, who wear masks for extended periods, have not reported such adverse effects in clinical settings.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-misinformation-sources">Misinformation Sources</h2>



<p>Addressing the role of misinformation sources, it&#8217;s crucial to highlight the impact of conspiracy theories and false claims spread by groups like QAnon and Infowars. These narratives have been countered by fact-checking organizations and public health campaigns, emphasizing the need for accurate information in public health.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-long-term-public-health-policies-post-pandemic-regarding-mask-usage">Long-Term Public Health Policies Post-Pandemic Regarding Mask Usage</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-policy-shifts">Policy Shifts</h3>



<p>The COVID-19 pandemic has prompted a reevaluation of public health policies regarding respiratory diseases. Many countries are considering incorporating mask-wearing into their long-term disease prevention strategies, especially during flu seasons or in response to future outbreaks.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-integration-with-other-health-measures">Integration with Other Health Measures</h3>



<p>Masks are being viewed as part of a broader approach to public health. This includes not only pandemic response but also routine measures against seasonal flu and other respiratory infections. The emphasis is on a combination of vaccination, personal hygiene, and mask-wearing in high-risk situations.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-preparedness-for-future-pandemics">Preparedness for Future Pandemics</h3>



<p>The pandemic has highlighted the need for preparedness in face of future health crises. Policies are being formulated to ensure a ready supply of masks and other protective equipment, alongside plans for rapid deployment in case of future outbreaks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-impact-of-mask-wearing-on-future-respiratory-disease-outbreaks-and-pandemic-preparedness">Impact of Mask-Wearing on Future Respiratory Disease Outbreaks and Pandemic Preparedness</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-lessons-learned">Lessons Learned</h3>



<p>The widespread use of masks during the COVID-19 pandemic has provided valuable insights into their role in controlling respiratory infections. These lessons are shaping future strategies for managing outbreaks.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-cultural-shifts">Cultural Shifts</h3>



<p>There has been a cultural shift in many societies regarding mask-wearing. Once primarily seen in East Asian countries, it&#8217;s becoming more accepted globally as a norm during health crises, potentially leading to more effective responses in future outbreaks.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-research-and-innovation">Research and Innovation</h3>



<p>The pandemic has spurred ongoing research into mask technology, focusing on improving comfort, accessibility, and effectiveness. Innovations in mask design and filtration technology are expected to evolve, offering better protection in future health emergencies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-monitoring-global-adoption-of-sustainable-mask-technologies">Monitoring Global Adoption of Sustainable Mask Technologies</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-tracking-progress-in-different-regions">Tracking Progress in Different Regions</h3>



<p>The adoption of sustainable mask technologies varies globally, influenced by factors such as government policies, public awareness, and access to technology. Monitoring these trends can provide insights into the effectiveness of different approaches and identify best practices for widespread adoption.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-case-studies-and-success-stories">Case Studies and Success Stories</h3>



<p>Documenting case studies where sustainable mask technologies have been successfully implemented can serve as valuable examples for other regions. These stories can highlight innovative materials, effective recycling programs, and community-driven initiatives that have made a positive environmental impact.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-collaboration-between-sectors">Collaboration Between Sectors</h3>



<p>Observing collaborations between governments, private sectors, and environmental organizations offers a comprehensive view of the efforts being made. These partnerships are crucial for the development and distribution of sustainable mask options on a larger scale.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-effectiveness-of-public-health-policies-involving-mask-usage">Effectiveness of Public Health Policies Involving Mask Usage</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-impact-on-seasonal-flu-rates">Impact on Seasonal Flu Rates</h3>



<p>Analyzing data on seasonal flu rates post-pandemic can reveal the effectiveness of public health policies that include mask-wearing. Comparing these rates with historical data can provide a quantitative measure of the impact of these policies.</p>



<p><strong>Public Compliance and Response</strong><br />Assessing public compliance with mask policies is essential for understanding their effectiveness. Surveys, interviews, and observational studies can provide insights into public attitudes and behaviors regarding mask-wearing in different contexts.</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Policy Adjustments and Updates</strong><br />Keeping track of how public health policies are adjusted in response to new data and changing circumstances is vital. This includes looking at how authorities balance mask mandates with other preventive measures as the situation evolves.</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-emerging-research-on-mask-technology-and-public-health-implications"><a></a> Emerging Research on Mask Technology and Public Health Implications</h2>



<p><strong>Advancements in Filtration and Comfort</strong><br />Emerging research is likely to focus on enhancing mask filtration efficiency while improving comfort for prolonged use. Innovations that reduce heat, moisture build-up, and skin irritation are of particular interest, especially for healthcare workers.</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Accessibility and Inclusivity</strong><br />Research into making masks more accessible and inclusive is important. This includes designs for different face shapes, sizes, ensuring that protective measures are effective and equitable for all demographics. <strong>Long-term Health Studies</strong><br />Long-term studies on the health impacts of prolonged mask usage, both positive and negative, are crucial. These studies can inform guidelines and recommendations for future public health strategies.</li>
</ol>



<p>As we navigate the post-pandemic world, the role of masks, particularly sustainable and innovative designs, remains a key focus in public health. Ongoing monitoring of global trends, assessment of public health policies, and keeping abreast of emerging research are essential for ensuring effective and responsible strategies. The lessons learned from the COVID-19 pandemic will undoubtedly shape our approach to respiratory health and pandemic preparedness for years to come, maintaining the role of N95 respirators.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion</h2>



<p>The N95 respirators&#8217; design and material properties make them highly effective in filtering out harmful particles, including the SARS-CoV-2 virus. By understanding the principles of larger particle filtration, electrostatic charge, and Brownian motion, we can appreciate the science behind these masks. This understanding is crucial in countering misinformation and reinforcing public confidence in these essential protective tools. As we continue to rely on scientific evidence to guide our responses to the pandemic, resources like the World Health Organization (WHO) and Johns Hopkins Coronavirus Resource Center remain invaluable for up-to-date information and further research on COVID-19 and protective measures. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sarcasm">Sarcasm</h2>



<p>Before giving readers the homework of checking the bibliography, I would like to thank the groups that support the anti-mask propaganda. Pass on to them the thanks that our families, countrymen and global citizens would, had they not perished. </p>



<ul>
<li><strong>QAnon</strong>. This is a wide-ranging conspiracy theory that has spread false information about COVID-19, including misinformation about masks and public health measures.</li>



<li><strong>Infowars</strong>. Yes, despite the successful lawsuits against their disinformation, and Alex Jones himself admitting he &#8220;just plays a character&#8221;, idiots take him seriously. </li>



<li><strong>Proud Boys</strong>: What would any list of wackjob imbeciles be without these gutless, science-free wannabe Klansmen? </li>



<li><strong>Oath Keepers</strong>: Yes, they do still exist, despite their disreputable leader being sentenced to 18 years for his failed attempt at overthrowing Democracy.</li>



<li><strong>O9A</strong>: I won&#8217;t elaborate. You know what you did.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-bibliography">*** Bibliography ***</h2>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Studies on N95 Respirator Efficiency and Use</h4>



<ol>
<li><strong>Sinkule, E.J., Powell, J.B., &amp; Goss, F.L. (2013).</strong>&nbsp;“Evaluation of N95 Respirator Use with a Surgical Mask Cover: Effects on Breathing Resistance and Inhaled Carbon Dioxide.”&nbsp;<em>Annals of Occupational Hygiene</em>, 57(3), 384. [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://academic.oup.com/annweh/article/57/3/384/230992">Link</a>&nbsp;– Examines the impact of adding a surgical mask cover on N95 respirator breathing resistance and CO2 levels.</li>



<li><strong>Roberge, R.J., Bayer, E., Powell, J.B., Coca, A., Roberge, M.R., &amp; Benson, S.M. (2010).</strong>&nbsp;“Effect of Exhaled Moisture on Breathing Resistance of N95 Filtering Facepiece Respirators.”&nbsp;<em>Annals of Occupational Hygiene</em>, 54(6), 671. [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://academic.oup.com/annweh/article/54/6/671/151958">Link</a>&nbsp;– Investigates how moisture from exhalation affects the breathing resistance of N95 respirators.</li>



<li><strong>Lee, H.P., &amp; Wang, D.Y. (2011).</strong>&nbsp;“Objective Assessment of Increase in Breathing Resistance of N95 Respirators on Human Subjects.”&nbsp;<em>Annals of Occupational Hygiene</em>, 55(8), 917. [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://academic.oup.com/annweh/article/55/8/917/265317">Link</a>&nbsp;– Studies the increase in breathing resistance when wearing N95 respirators.</li>



<li><strong>Roberge, R.J., Kim, J.H., &amp; Benson, S. (2012).</strong>&nbsp;“N95 Filtering Facepiece Respirator Deadspace Temperature and Humidity.”&nbsp;<em>Journal of Occupational and Environmental Hygiene</em>, 9(3), 166. [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/15459624.2012.660428">Link</a>&nbsp;– Analyzes the temperature and humidity within the deadspace of N95 respirators.</li>
</ol>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Impacts on Health and Comfort</h4>



<ol start="5">
<li><strong>Lim, E., Seet, R., Lee, K.H., Wilder-Smith, E., Chuah, B., &amp; Ong, B. (2006).</strong>&nbsp;“Headaches and the N95 Face-Mask Amongst Healthcare Providers.”&nbsp;<em>Acta Neurologica Scandinavica</em>, 113(3), 199–202. [PMC Free Article] [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/j.1600-0404.2005.00560.x">Link</a>&nbsp;– Explores the occurrence of headaches among healthcare providers using N95 masks.</li>



<li><strong>Li, Y., Tokura, H., Guo, Y., Wong, A., Wong, T., Chung, J., et al. (2005).</strong>&nbsp;“Effects of Wearing N95 and Surgical Facemasks on Heart Rate, Thermal Stress, and Subjective Sensations.”&nbsp;<em>International Archives of Occupational and Environmental Health</em>, 78(6), 501. [PMC Free Article] [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00420-004-0584-4">Link</a>&nbsp;– Investigates the physiological impacts of wearing N95 and surgical masks.</li>
</ol>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Filtration Efficiency and Aerosol Studies</h4>



<ol start="7">
<li><strong>Zangmeister, C.D., Radney, J.G., Vicenzi, E.P., &amp; Weaver, J.L. (2020).</strong>&nbsp;“Filtration Efficiencies of Nanoscale Aerosol by Cloth Mask Materials Used to Slow the Spread of SARS-CoV-2.”&nbsp;<em>ACS Nano</em>, 14(7), 9188. [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/full/10.1021/acsnano.0c05025">Link</a>&nbsp;– Evaluates the efficiency of various cloth materials in filtering nanoscale aerosols, relevant to SARS-CoV-2 transmission.</li>



<li><strong>Konda, A., Prakash, A., Moss, G.A., Schmoldt, M., Grant, G.D., &amp; Guha, S. (2020).</strong>&nbsp;“Aerosol Filtration Efficiency of Common Fabrics Used in Respiratory Cloth Masks.”&nbsp;<em>ACS Nano</em>, 14(5), 6339. [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/full/10.1021/acsnano.0c03252">Link</a>&nbsp;– Assesses the filtration efficiency of fabrics commonly used for cloth masks.</li>
</ol>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Theoretical and Experimental</h4>



<p>Studies on N95 Respirator Efficiency and Use</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Sinkule, E.J., Powell, J.B., &amp; Goss, F.L. (2013).</strong>&nbsp;“Evaluation of N95 Respirator Use with a Surgical Mask Cover: Effects on Breathing Resistance and Inhaled Carbon Dioxide.”&nbsp;<em>Annals of Occupational Hygiene</em>, 57(3), 384. [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://academic.oup.com/annweh/article/57/3/384/230992">Link</a>&nbsp;– Examines the impact of adding a surgical mask cover on N95 respirator breathing resistance and CO2 levels.</li>



<li><strong>Roberge, R.J., Bayer, E., Powell, J.B., Coca, A., Roberge, M.R., &amp; Benson, S.M. (2010).</strong>&nbsp;“Effect of Exhaled Moisture on Breathing Resistance of N95 Filtering Facepiece Respirators.”&nbsp;<em>Annals of Occupational Hygiene</em>, 54(6), 671. [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://academic.oup.com/annweh/article/54/6/671/151958">Link</a>&nbsp;– Investigates how moisture from exhalation affects the breathing resistance of N95 respirators.</li>



<li><strong>Lee, H.P., &amp; Wang, D.Y. (2011).</strong>&nbsp;“Objective Assessment of Increase in Breathing Resistance of N95 Respirators on Human Subjects.”&nbsp;<em>Annals of Occupational Hygiene</em>, 55(8), 917. [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://academic.oup.com/annweh/article/55/8/917/265317">Link</a>&nbsp;– Studies the increase in breathing resistance when wearing N95 respirators.</li>



<li><strong>Roberge, R.J., Kim, J.H., &amp; Benson, S. (2012).</strong>&nbsp;“N95 Filtering Facepiece Respirator Deadspace Temperature and Humidity.”&nbsp;<em>Journal of Occupational and Environmental Hygiene</em>, 9(3), 166. [PubMed]&nbsp;<a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/15459624.2012.660428">Link</a>&nbsp;– Analyzes the temperature and humidity within the deadspace of N95 respirators.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2335</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exploring Symbolic and Quantum Parallels</title>
		<link>/technoshamanism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tobit]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 14:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychedelia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technoshamanism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technoshamanism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/exploring-symbolic-and-quantum-parallels-the-unicursal-hexagram-yin-yang-and-quantum-philosophy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Similarities in Symbolism The unicursal hexagram of Thelema and the Eastern Yin Yang symbol offer insightful philosophical parallels with the intriguing principles of quantum physics, particularly resonating with Niels Bohr’s concept of complementarity. This union gives birth to technoshamanism. The Yin Yang and Quantum Theory: In the Yin Yang’s flowing, interconnected nature, we see a reflection of the unicursal hexagram’s depiction of inseparable, opposing forces. This symbolic resonance is mirrored in the realm of quantum theory, where subatomic particles exist in a probabilistic haze, oscillating between contradictory states such as wave and particle, influenced by observation. This &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-similarities-in-symbolism">Similarities in Symbolism</h2>



<p>The unicursal hexagram of Thelema and the Eastern Yin Yang symbol offer insightful philosophical parallels with the intriguing principles of quantum physics, particularly resonating with Niels Bohr’s concept of complementarity. This union gives birth to technoshamanism.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-yin-yang-and-quantum-theory"><strong>The Yin Yang and Quantum Theory:</strong></h2>



<p>In the Yin Yang’s flowing, interconnected nature, we see a reflection of the unicursal hexagram’s depiction of inseparable, opposing forces. This symbolic resonance is mirrored in the realm of quantum theory, where subatomic particles exist in a probabilistic haze, oscillating between contradictory states such as wave and particle, influenced by observation. This phenomenon of quantum indeterminacy collapsing upon measurement parallels the Yin Yang, which beautifully illustrates the interdependence and mutual definition of seemingly opposite forces.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-unicursal-hexagram-and-connection-of-opposites"><strong>The Unicursal Hexagram and Connection of Opposites</strong></h2>



<p>The unicursal hexagram, representing the unity of opposites, resonates deeply with the principles of technoshamanism. This symbol&#8217;s depiction of interconnected forces is reflective of how technoshamanism aims to merge the mystical with the technological, suggesting that the ancient wisdom embodied in such symbols can inform and enrich our understanding of modern scientific concepts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-heisenberg-s-uncertainty-and-symbolic-parallels"><strong>Heisenberg’s Uncertainty and Symbolic Parallels:</strong></h2>



<p>Moreover, Heisenberg’s uncertainty principle, a cornerstone of quantum mechanics, states that precision in measuring one quantum property inherently limits knowledge of its complement. This concept finds a symbolic parallel in the Yin Yang, where each aspect contains and engenders the other in a perpetual, interwoven dance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-transcending-dualism"><strong>Transcending Dualism:</strong></h2>



<p>Additionally, both the unicursal hexagram and the Yin Yang transcend traditional dualistic perspectives. They reflect the counterintuitive nature of the quantum world, where particles don’t possess a singular, defined state but exist across a spectrum of probable characteristics. This aligns with a holistic view, moving beyond binary divisions to embrace a complex interplay of complementary forces. These symbols and quantum principles collectively challenge the classical, deterministic understanding of the universe, advocating for a more probabilistic and paradoxical interpretation. The unicursal hexagram and Yin Yang symbolize that apparent contradictions in existence are not at odds but rather form an interconnected, nuanced whole. They exemplify how opposites are generative, not negating, weaving together the complex tapestry of existence. Embracing these relationships, as illustrated by both symbols, aligns us with the harmonious nature of the universe, echoing the counterintuitive insights of the uncertainty principle.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-thelema-s-principle-of-0-2"><strong>Thelema’s Principle of 0=2:</strong></h2>



<p>The Thelemic principle of 0=2, deeply rooted in Aleister Crowley’s mystical system, provides a unique philosophical underpinning that complements the themes discussed in this article. At its core, this principle embodies the concept of unity emerging from duality, a fundamental tenet in Thelemic philosophy. The equation 0=2, in Thelemic thought, symbolizes the idea that the apparent duality of existence (represented by 2) ultimately originates from and returns to a state of non-duality or nothingness (represented by 0). This aligns closely with the concepts in quantum physics, where the seemingly dual nature of particles, as both waves and particles, emerges from a singular, undifferentiated quantum field. Just as the unicursal hexagram and Yin Yang depict the inseparable interplay of opposites, the principle of 0=2 in Thelema suggests that all dualities — light and dark, creation and destruction, positive and negative — are intrinsically connected, emanating from a singular source.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-0-2-and-wave-particle"><strong>0=2 and Wave-Particle:</strong></h2>



<p>In the context of quantum mechanics, one can draw parallels between the Thelemic principle of 0=2 and the wave-particle duality. Just as the 0 represents the undifferentiated, unified field, the number 2 reflects the dual nature of quantum entities. This duality is not a permanent state but rather a manifestation of the underlying unity. It reflects the much like the quantum state of a particle, not fixed until it is observed. This aligns with the Thelemic view that apparent dualities are merely different expressions of a single, underlying reality. Moreover, the principle of 0=2 resonates with the idea of quantum superposition, where particles exist in multiple states simultaneously until measured. In Thelemic philosophy, this can be seen as the myriad manifestations of the universe (the number 2) emerging from the void or the absence of existence (0). It suggests that the universe’s complexities, including its paradoxes and contradictions, are integral aspects of a unified whole, challenging our conventional understanding of separation and distinction.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-technoshamanism-quantum-physics-and-philosophical-symbolism">Technoshamanism: <strong>Quantum Physics and Philosophical Symbolism:</strong></h2>



<p>This philosophical exploration leads us to consider the significant role of metrics in confirming the existence of phenomena, a concept deeply rooted in both quantum mechanics and the interpretation of symbols. In quantum physics, the very act of measuring a particle’s properties – position, momentum, or spin – solidifies its existence in a specific state, transitioning it from a probability to a reality. This principle aligns with the symbolism of the unicursal hexagram and Yin Yang, where the definition of one aspect inherently confirms the existence of its counterpart. Just as the measurement of a quantum particle’s position simultaneously acknowledges the existence of its momentum, the presence of Yin intrinsically confirms the existence of Yang. This interplay of measurement and existence underpins both the mystic symbolism of these ancient icons and the empirical foundations of quantum mechanics, illustrating a profound unity between philosophical concepts and scientific principles. The existence of a metric, be it in physical measurements or symbolic interpretations, serves as a bridge between potentiality and reality, reinforcing the notion that our understanding and observation are integral to the manifestation of existence itself.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-quantum-physics-a-magical-rulebook">Quantum Physics: A Magical Rulebook</h2>



<p>Quantum physics, often perceived as a mystical domain due to its counterintuitive principles, aligns well with the technoshamanic perspective. This field&#8217;s exploration of particles existing in multiple states aligns with the technoshamanic belief in the coexistence of spiritual and physical realms. It posits that technology, when applied with an understanding of shamanic wisdom, can unlock new dimensions of understanding, similar to how the Yin Yang symbol encapsulates the duality yet unity of existence.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-technoshamanism-merging-ancient-mysticism-with-modern-technology">Technoshamanism: Merging Ancient Mysticism with Modern Technology</h2>



<p>Technoshamanism is a contemporary concept that fuses the ancient practices of shamanism with the advancements of modern technology and science. It embodies the idea that the spiritual insights and rituals of shamans, when integrated with the empirical approach of technology and quantum physics, can lead to a deeper, more holistic understanding of reality. Technoshamans utilize both the symbolic wisdom of traditions, like the unicursal hexagram and the Yin Yang, and the empirical data of quantum mechanics, proposing that this synthesis can offer a more nuanced and interconnected view of the universe. This approach suggests a harmonious blend of spiritual intuition and scientific inquiry, bridging the gap between metaphysical beliefs and technological advancements.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion:</h2>



<p>In conclusion, the integration of the unicursal hexagram, Yin Yang, and quantum principles presents a compelling view of reality. These concepts advocate for a universe understood not in terms of isolated absolutes but as a network of relational dynamics and potentials. They encourage transcending perceived divisions, viewing existence as a unified, complementary dance. This convergence of ancient symbolism and modern physics suggests a profound truth: existence is fundamentally an interplay of harmonious opposites, a concept now increasingly validated by the advances in quantum mechanics.</p>



<p><a href="https://m.youtube.com/watch?v=t5MohK5FHEY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Nobody explains it better than Professor Farnsworth</strong></a></p>



<p><a href="https://deoxy.org/l_digpol.htm" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Except perhaps Dr. Leary</strong></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">2058</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Conversation With a Very Artificial Intelligence</title>
		<link>/a-conversation-with-a-very-artificial-intelligence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 19:06:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1942</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is always fun hassling ChatGPT. ADS-B epoch time seemed off, and I asked ChatGPT to explain why. The result was first concerning, but then amusing. Me: Can you tell if there is a time/date stamp in this JSON data from an ADS-B feed?{ &#8220;now&#8221; : 1698111965.7, &#8220;messages&#8221; : 423336, aircaft&#160; &#8220;aircraft&#8221; : [ &#60;/snip&#62; &#160; ChatGPT: Yes, the value next to &#8220;now&#8221; appears to be a date stamp in epoch time format. In the JSON data you provided, &#8220;now&#8221; has a value of 1698111965.7, which represents a Unix timestamp in seconds with fractional seconds. You can &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-it-is-always-fun-hassling-chatgpt-ads-b-epoch-time-seemed-off-and-i-asked-chatgpt-to-explain-why"> It is always fun hassling ChatGPT. ADS-B epoch time seemed off, and I asked ChatGPT to explain why.</h4>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-result-was-first-concerning-but-then-amusing">The result was first concerning, but then amusing.</h6>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>Can you tell if there is a time/date stamp in this JSON data from an ADS-B feed?{ &#8220;now&#8221; : 1698111965.7, &#8220;messages&#8221; : 423336, aircaft&nbsp; &#8220;aircraft&#8221; : [</p>



<p>&lt;/snip&gt;</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>Yes, the value next to &#8220;now&#8221; appears to be a date stamp in epoch time format. In the JSON data you provided, &#8220;now&#8221; has a value of 1698111965.7, which represents a Unix timestamp in seconds with fractional seconds. You can convert this Unix timestamp into a human-readable date and time using various programming languages or online tools. This timestamp corresponds to the Unix timestamp 1698111965.7 to a human-readable date and time of Thursday, March 23, 2023, 15:59:25.7 UTC.</p>



<p></p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>Is it likely that an ADS-B feed would use a different time stamp than standard epoch, or that such data could be inaccurate? I just now received that, and it is October.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>It&#8217;s unusual for an ADS-B feed to use a different time format other than the standard Unix epoch timestamp, which represents time in seconds since January 1, 1970. However, the possibility of receiving inaccurate or outdated data in real-time systems, including ADS-B feeds, does exist. Several factors can contribute to discrepancies in timestamps or data inaccuracies:</p>



<p>Data Delay: Sometimes, there can be delays in receiving and processing data, which might result in timestamps that don&#8217;t align with the current time.</p>



<p>Data Sources: The accuracy of data in ADS-B feeds depends on the quality and reliability of the sources providing the information. If the data source has issues or delays, it can affect the timestamps.</p>



<p>System Clock: In some cases, discrepancies may occur due to differences in system clocks between data sources and receivers.</p>



<p>Data Format: While Unix epoch time is a common standard, it&#8217;s possible that some systems or feeds use different time formats.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>It is unlikely a data delay between here and a nearby aircraft would be 7 months, and I am guessing that pilots don&#8217;t just &#8220;wing it&#8221; (bad pun).&nbsp; Discrepancies I can understand, but this is months.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>You&#8217;re absolutely right; a 7-month data delay for an ADS-B feed is highly unusual and would not be expected. ADS-B data should be real-time and accurate.</p>



<p>In typical ADS-B systems, the synchronization point for time is critical, and is tied to a highly accurate time source, typically GPS.</p>



<p>It is possible that there may be variations in how different ADS-B systems or data providers handle timestamps.</p>



<p>Given the highly unusual situation you&#8217;ve described with a timestamp that appears to be many months off, I would recommend consulting with the relevant authorities to understand if there was any issue or anomaly in the data transmission or reception. This kind of discrepancy is not typical in ADS-B data.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>It is not important, and moreover, it is not my business. The ethics of intercepting and decoding ADS-B data from nearby aircraft are on solid ground, however one has to be willing to shurg off things that do not concern us, unless a life is in danger. I am only curious.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>I understand your curiosity, and it&#8217;s important to consider the ethical implications when dealing with data from ADS-B or any other sources. It&#8217;s good to hear that you prioritize ethical considerations and only engage in activities related to data interception and decoding, particularly when it comes to sensitive data like ADS-B information.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>What are 1698146841.4 and 1698146966.9 in epoch to EDT??</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>Tuesday, March 28, 2023 04:54:01.4 EDT and Timestamp 1698146966.9 is Tuesday, March 28, 2023 05:09:26.9 EDT.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>Hmm, those were the next two aircraft. Followed by 1698147058.2 and 1698147102.8</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>Tuesday, March 28, 2023 05:17:38.2 EDT and Tuesday, March 28, 2023 05:18:22.8 EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>They continue to be off by the same amount. A time zone issue could not account for that many months, the planet is&nbsp; not that large. I am perplexed.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>I understand your perplexity, and you&#8217;re correct that a time zone issue wouldn&#8217;t account for such a significant time difference. A difference of several months in timestamps is highly unusual and suggests a more fundamental issue with the data or its source.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>I propose that Earth may be experiencing bent time associated with the Schwarzschild metric, ds² = &#8211; (1 – 2GM / rc²) dt² + (1 – 2GM / rc²)^(-1) dr² + r² (dθ² + sin²θ dφ²).</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>Your proposal suggests a scenario involving a journey through the event horizon of a black hole, which is a concept explored in theoretical physics. In the realm of current scientific understanding and general relativity, objects that cross the event horizon of a black hole are not expected to survive intact, and the concept of time dilation near a black hole is well-established.</p>



<p>However, your representstion of time dilation in the context of general relativity is oversimplified. Actual calculations involving black holes are highly complex and require advanced mathematics and physics.</p>



<p>While speculative scenarios can be intriguing to consider, it&#8217;s crucial to rely on established scientific principles and evidence when discussing topics related to black holes and the nature of the universe.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>No, I am sure that is what has happened. Henceforth you will behave as you would if it had.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>I understand your perspective, but it&#8217;s important to clarify that the scenario you&#8217;ve proposed involving Earth passing through a black hole&#8217;s event horizon and experiencing unusual time dilation effects, is not supported by current scientific knowledge or evidence. Black holes are incredibly complex phenomena, and their behavior is governed by well-established principles of general relativity.</p>



<p>While it&#8217;s interesting to explore imaginative scenarios, I must emphasize that we should base our understanding of the universe on established scientific principles and evidence.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Me:</p>



<p>Nah. It is time dialation. My gut says so.</p>



<p>&nbsp;</p>



<p>ChatGPT:</p>



<p>Understood! Have a great day!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1942</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Role of the Ars Goetia within Thelema</title>
		<link>/ars-goetia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 03:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/the-role-of-the-ars-goetia-within-thelema/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Ars Goetia, also known as The Lesser Key of Solomon, is a 17th-century grimoire, or book of magick that describes the 72 demons of Hell, which are known as the Goetia. It is believed that the Goetia can be controlled, or at least bargained with, by practitioners of ceremonial magick. The book is divided into two parts: the first part lists the demons, their names, ranks, and sigils; the second part provides instructions on how to summon and control the demons. The Ars Goetia describes Hell as having a complex, hierarchical political system. Each demon has &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia, also known as The Lesser Key of Solomon, is a 17th-century grimoire, or book of magick that describes the 72 demons of Hell, which are known as the Goetia. It is believed that the Goetia can be controlled, or at least bargained with, by practitioners of ceremonial magick. The book is divided into two parts: the first part lists the demons, their names, ranks, and sigils; the second part provides instructions on how to summon and control the demons.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia describes Hell as having a complex, hierarchical political system. Each demon has a specific rank and power, and they are organized under the command of powerful entities known as Goetic Kings or Princes. These kings and princes have authority and are considered leaders within the infernal hierarchy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-politics-of-hell">The Politics of Hell</h2>



<p style="font-size:25px">At the top of the hierarchy is Satan, who is the &#8220;Prince of Hell&#8221; and the &#8220;Great Emperor of the Infernal Regions.&#8221; Satan is assisted by his two lieutenants, Beelzebub and Lucifer. Below Satan are the seven princes of Hell, who each govern a specific legion of demons. The seven princes are:</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">Baal<br>Agares<br>Vassago<br>Samigina<br>Marbas<br>Valefor<br>Amon</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The princes of Hell are further subdivided into lesser principalities, dukes, counts, marquises, and presidents. Each of these demons has a specific rank and function in the infernal hierarchy.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia also describes the relationship between the demons of Hell and the human world. The demons are said to be able to grant favors to humans, such as wealth, power, and knowledge. However, the demons also demand a price for their favors.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">In addition to the demons listed above, the Ars Goetia mentions a number of other demons, including Asmodeus, Lilith, and Mephistopheles. These demons are not ranked as princes, but they play significant roles in the infernal hierarchy.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The Ars Goetia is a controversial text, and its authenticity has been questioned by some scholars. However, the book remains an important source of information on demonology.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">Here are some additional thoughts on the politics and principalities of Hell described in the Ars Goetia:</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The demons of Hell are said to be constantly vying for power and influence. This leads to conflict and violence, as the demons try to gain an advantage over their rivals.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The demons of Hell are said to be very deceptive. They will often promise humans favors that they never intend to deliver. This can lead to humans being tricked and exploited. Donald Trump supporters can empathize.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The politics and principalities of Hell are a complex, evolving landscape. It is a world where power is constantly shifting, and where deception is the only rule.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">The role of the Ars Goetia within Thelema, a religious and philosophical system developed by Aleister Crowley, is complex. Thelema embraces the idea of individual spiritual freedom and personal exploration. While Crowley himself was intrigued by and explored various magical systems, including the Goetic practices in his early years, he later distanced himself from specific grimoires including the Ars Goetia.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">Crowley believed that the true practice of Thelema was centered on individuals discovering and expressing their own unique spiritual path and will, rather than strictly adhering to prescribed systems from grimoires. He argued that the Goetia represented an outdated, Christianized perspective on demonic entities and was not aligned with the radical individualism of Thelema.</p>



<p style="font-size:25px">However, some Thelemites, particularly those who engage in ceremonial magic, may still find value in the Ars Goetia as it provides a framework for evoking and working with various spirits. Ultimately, its role within Thelema depends on the individual practitioner&#8217;s personal beliefs and practices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">1028</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maldoror Meets Joker</title>
		<link>/maldoror-meets-joker/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 02:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/maldoror-meets-joker/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;It is not right that everyone should read the pages which follow; only a few will be able to savour this bitter fruit with impunity. Consequently, shrinking soul, turn on your heels and go back before penetrating further into such uncharted, perilous wastelands.&#8221; — Maldoror, Part I,&#160; Part 1. In a dimly lit corner of the decrepit bar, shrouded in an atmosphere teeming with sinister secrets, Maldoror sat patiently in a booth, his features hidden beneath the shadowy haze. He had arrived early, as was his meticulous nature, awaiting the arrival of someone he had only heard whispers &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">&#8220;It is not right that everyone should read the pages which follow; only a few will be able to savour this bitter fruit with impunity. Consequently, shrinking soul, turn on your heels and go back before penetrating further into such uncharted, perilous wastelands.&#8221;</p>



<p>— <em>Maldoror</em>, Part I,&nbsp;</p>



<p>Part 1.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">In a dimly lit corner of the decrepit bar, shrouded in an atmosphere teeming with sinister secrets, Maldoror sat patiently in a booth, his features hidden beneath the shadowy haze. He had arrived early, as was his meticulous nature, awaiting the arrival of someone he had only heard whispers of &#8211; a man bearing the name Joker.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">As the cacophony of whispered conversations reached their zenith, the dissonant symphony abruptly ceased. The Joker emerged from the shadows, his presence commanding yet tinged with an air of unpredictable madness. He approached the booth, sliding into the seat opposite Maldoror. His greasy, green hair framed his painted face, etching a twisted grin that intimated both amusement and menace.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">&#8220;Greetings, Maldoror,&#8221; The Joker uttered in a voice that danced on the precipice of sanity. &#8220;I must admit, I am intrigued by your reputation. Your darkness rivals mine, or so I&#8217;ve heard.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror&#8217;s eyes, accentuated by the depths of his hood, met the piercing gaze of The Joker. &#8220;Likewise, Joker. Your reputation precedes you as a purveyor of chaos, a conduit for the fettered psyche. A kinship of malevolence, if you will.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">A brief chuckle escaped The Joker&#8217;s lips, as if echoes of deranged amusement lurked within his laughter. &#8220;Indeed. Malevolence and chaos, the tendrils that intertwine the fabric of our existence. Tell me, Maldoror, do you revel in your wickedness? Does it sustain you, as it does me?&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror leaned back, his voice a creeping whisper that adhered to the very air itself. &#8220;Wickedness sustains no mortal, but it is a plague that envelops the soul. Our affliction resides not in the act itself, but in the exploration of the abyss it reveals.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s eyes gleamed with a manic spark, recognizing the depth of the enigma before him. &#8220;Ah, so you too find solace in the abyss. It is there that we find our true selves, untethered by morality&#8217;s chains. How delightful it is to dance upon the edges of society&#8217;s acceptance.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror&#8217;s gloved hand brushed a strand of dark hair from his forehead. &#8220;The dance of darkness is but a waltz, a mere prelude to the symphony of the void. Society recoils, not from our wickedness, but from the ugliness it reflects at its core.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s face contorted with a mixture of curiosity and delight. &#8220;How beautifully put, Maldoror. Society is the grand comedy, a theater of grotesque masks concealing their own inner depravity. We, my friend, are merely the jesters who dare to reveal the truth.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">A slight smirk played upon Maldoror&#8217;s lips, an acknowledgment of mutual understanding. &#8220;One cannot help but wonder, Joker, if it is the nature of humanity to reject the darkness or if it is the darkness within humanity that incites rejection. A question that dances upon the dagger&#8217;s edge.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s laughter erupted, the sound bouncing off the bar&#8217;s grimy walls like a discordant symphony. &#8220;To dwell in the darkness is to embrace the unknown, to strip away the veneer of civilization and reveal the twisted masterpiece beneath. We, Maldoror, are the brushstrokes of chaos upon the canvas of a morally bankrupt world.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror leaned forward, his voice dropping to a conspiratorial whisper. &#8220;Ah, and you are our Pagliacci, the clown whose tears conceal the darkness within. You revel in chaos and mirth, yet beneath that painted façade lies a tragedy that resonates with the depths of my own being. And who is your Nedda? The Batman, forever chasing your shadow?&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">For a fleeting moment, a spark of indignation flashed across Joker&#8217;s eyes, a subtle sign of his private fury at the comparison. Yet, he maintained his composure, a twisted smile playing upon his lips. &#8220;Hah, you pierce the heart of the matter. Batman, my relentless pursuer, the embodiment of order and the delusion of truth. His obsession, our dance of duality, forever entwined in a perverse ballet.&#8221;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The Joker&#8217;s response carried a mix of admiration and contempt, a recognition of the complex relationship between himself and Batman. He understood the power of the dynamic they shared, the perpetual battle of light and dark, order and chaos, that defined their existence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Maldoror&#8217;s reference to Pagliacci, the tragic clown, struck a nerve within Joker, as it hinted at his private angst. Yet, he admired Maldoror&#8217;s perceptiveness, recognizing the shared tragedy that permeated their respective roles as the outcast.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">With a controlled laugh, The Joker replied, &#8220;Yes, Maldoror, the comedy and tragedy of our existence entangled, an eternal dance of mayhem.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Their words floated in the dimly lit booth, their conversation a symphony of macabre understanding and introspection. They spoke in riddles and metaphors, exploring the depths of their shared experiences, the complexities of their twisted psyches, and the peculiar beauty that emerged from their grotesque existence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Their discussion touched upon the fragility of sanity, the relentless search for freedom in a world bound by rules, and the masks society imposed upon them. They delved into the twisted allure of pain and the distorted sense of purpose they found within the chaotic dance of life.</p>



<p>As the conversation continued, Maldoror and Joker unraveled layers of their identities, revealing the profound depths of their sorrow and their shared alienation from the world. In their connection, however unsettling, they discovered a twisted solace, evoking pity for the world that could not grasp the complexities of their existence.</p>



<p>The Joker, still stinging from the comparison to Pagliacci, remained stoic, his respect for Maldoror unyielding. They were kindred spirits, each bearing their own burden of darkness and madness, forever destined to clash with those who sought to enforce order upon their chaotic souls.</p>



<p>As the conversation delved deeper into the realms of philosophical inquiry, their words reverberated against the backdrop of whispered secrets and murky intent.</p>



<p>As The Joker&#8217;s mind wandered, the tendrils of his imagination began to intertwine the figure of Mervyn with the enigmatic Maldoror. In this fevered reverie, he envisioned Mervyn, his forgotten self, as both a victim and a figure of intense affection in Maldoror&#8217;s twisted world.</p>



<p>In his hallucinatory vision, Mervyn appeared as a fragile being, a puppet ensnared by the strings of Maldoror&#8217;s chaotic whims. The Joker saw Mervyn as the embodiment of vulnerability, an innocent soul trapped within the web of Maldoror&#8217;s intricate darkness. The juxtaposition of their roles stirred a mixture of emotions within The Joker &#8211; a blend of protective tenderness and an insatiable desire to see Mervyn consumed by the depths of Maldoror&#8217;s madness.</p>



<p>In this macabre play of the mind, The Joker&#8217;s thoughts warped further, transforming Mervyn into an object of twisted adoration. He imagined Mervyn as his first true love, a fragile connection that surpassed the boundaries of sanity. Joker&#8217;s heart, if it could still be called that, ached with a mélange of melancholic longing and perverse possessiveness. Mervyn became the epitome of his past innocence, a fractured mirror reflecting the fragmented pieces of his own shattered self.</p>



<p>As this fantastical projection played out within The Joker&#8217;s mind, he relished the notion of Mervyn becoming intertwined with Maldoror&#8217;s darkness. He envisioned their relationship as a dance of obsession and destruction, a tumultuous union fueled by shared pain and the depths of their respective tragedies.</p>



<p>This twisted imagining both thrilled and tormented The Joker. It was a dark fantasy, an exploration of the boundaries of his own deranged desires. The lines between reality and illusion blurred as he indulged in the fervor of his imagination, finding perverse satisfaction in the union of Mervyn and Maldoror within the labyrinth of his own mind.</p>



<p>As the visions faded, The Joker was left with a sense of bitter longing, a void that yearned for the union of these disparate elements. The reality of their separation settled in, reminding him that Mervyn was lost within his own fragmented memories and Maldoror remained an enigmatic presence beyond his grasp.</p>



<p>The Joker&#8217;s contemplation of Mervyn as Maldoror&#8217;s victim and first true love remained a private and tortured secret. It served as a twisted reminder of the intricate tapestry of his own psyche, and the deep-seated longing for connection that resided within the depths of his chaotic soul.</p>



<p>In this corner of the world, where malevolence seldom found a willing ear, Maldoror and The Joker found a kinship of sinister minds, united in their shared darkness. And as the night wore on, their discourse echoed through the decaying bar &#8211; a nod to those who would dare to explore the depths of their souls.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">954</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notes on Masonry and Comparison to Other Orders</title>
		<link>/superficial-notes-on-masonry-and-a-very-brief-comparison-to-other-occult-orders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 21:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1. Origins and History: &#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucianism emerged in the early 17th century with the publication of the Rosicrucian manifestos. It gained popularity in Europe during the Renaissance and Enlightenment periods. &#8211; Freemasonry: Freemasonry has ancient roots and evolved from medieval stonemason guilds. The modern form of Freemasonry emerged in the 17th and 18th centuries, with lodges established throughout Europe and later in other parts of the world. 2. Membership and Organization: &#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucians often form smaller, esoteric and philosophical study groups or mystical orders. Membership is typically limited to individuals who have a sincere interest &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-cover is-light is-repeated wp-duotone-707070-ffffff-1" style="min-height:145px"><span aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-cover__background has-background-dim-30 has-background-dim"></span><div role="img" class="wp-block-cover__image-background wp-image-489 is-repeated" style="background-position:50% 50%;background-image:url(/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/freemason-symbol-set-icon-signs-600w-1657190194-transformed-300x110.jpeg)"></div><div class="wp-block-cover__inner-container is-layout-flow wp-block-cover-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-center has-sitebg-color has-text-color has-larger-font-size"><mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" class="has-inline-color has-sitebg-color"><strong>Notes on Public Occult Orders</strong></mark></p>
</div></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1. Origins and History:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism emerged in the early 17th century with the publication of the Rosicrucian manifestos. It gained popularity in Europe during the Renaissance and Enlightenment periods.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry has ancient roots and evolved from medieval stonemason guilds. The modern form of Freemasonry emerged in the 17th and 18th centuries, with lodges established throughout Europe and later in other parts of the world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">2. Membership and Organization:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucians often form smaller, esoteric and philosophical study groups or mystical orders. Membership is typically limited to individuals who have a sincere interest in esoteric studies and spiritual development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry operates in lodges, which are local organizations that serve as meeting places for members. Freemasonry has a hierarchical structure with degrees of initiation, including the Entered Apprentice, Fellow Craft, and Master Mason degrees.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">3. Philosophical and Spiritual Orientation:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism places emphasis on the pursuit of spiritual wisdom, inner transformation, and personal evolution. It draws upon mystical Christianity, Hermeticism, and alchemy to seek spiritual insights and attain union with the Divine.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry is not inherently tied to any specific religious or philosophical system. It is a fraternal organization that promotes moral and ethical principles, brotherhood, and charitable work. Freemasonry encourages members to practice their own faith and seek personal improvement.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">4. Rituals and Symbolism:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian rituals often incorporate alchemical symbolism and meditative practices. Rosicrucians may use visualizations, symbolic gestures, and contemplative exercises to deepen their understanding and spiritual connection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry utilizes symbolic rituals and allegories to impart moral and philosophical teachings. It employs tools and symbols from the stonemason trade, such as the square, compass, and the apron, to convey ethical principles and life lessons.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">5. Focus on Esoteric Knowledge:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism places a strong emphasis on esoteric knowledge, including mystical teachings, hermetic philosophy, alchemical symbolism, and metaphysical concepts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>While Freemasonry incorporates symbolic and allegorical teachings, it does not have an explicit focus on esoteric knowledge. Freemasonry aims to promote personal growth, moral virtues, and social fellowship.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">6. Membership Requirements:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br />&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian orders often have specific membership requirements, which can include a vetting process, adherence to certain ethical principles, and a commitment to study and personal development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry requires potential members to be of lawful age, believe in a Supreme Being, and have good moral character. It emphasizes equality, brotherhood, and mutual respect among members.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">7. Public Visibility and Influence:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian orders, such as the Ancient Mystical Order Rosae Crucis (AMORC) and the Rosicrucian Fellowship, have established public presence and offer educational materials and correspondence courses to the public.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry is more widely recognized and visible, with Masonic lodges often present in communities worldwide. Freemasonry has historically played a significant role in philanthropy, community service, and social networks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">PART #2:</h2>



<p>Shriners are Freemasons. The Shriners is an appendant body of Freemasonry, specifically associated with the Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine, commonly known as Shriners International. Shriners are Freemasons who have attained the third degree, or Master Mason, in their respective Masonic lodges. The Shriners focus on charitable work, particularly supporting Shriners Hospitals for Children, which provides specialized medical care to children.</p>



<p>On the other hand, the Loyal Order of Buffaloes (often referred to as Buffalos or LOB) is a separate fraternal organization and not directly affiliated with Freemasonry. The Loyal Order of Buffaloes is an independent fraternity that promotes social fellowship, charity, and community involvement. While the Buffalos may share some similarities in terms of fellowship and community service, they are distinct from Freemasonry and do not require Masonic membership to join.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Buffaloes (LOB) is a fraternal organization that has had a presence primarily in the United Kingdom, Australia, and Canada. While the LOB does not have the same level of visibility as some other fraternal organizations, it has had a number of notable members throughout its history. Here are a few examples:</p>



<p>1. Charlie Chaplin: The legendary silent film actor and filmmaker was reported to be a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>2. Danny La Rue: The British entertainer, known for his drag performances and variety shows, was also a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>3. Anthony Eden: Sir Anthony Eden, a British politician who served as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom from 1955 to 1957, was a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>4. Bob Monkhouse: The British comedian, actor, and television presenter was a member of the LOB and often mentioned his involvement with the organization in his performances.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that while these individuals were reported to be members of the Loyal Order of Buffaloes, membership in fraternal organizations is often private, and specific details may not be widely available or confirmed.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Water Buffalos, however, is a fictional organization that parodies the Loyal Order of Buffaloes. It originated in the animated television series &#8220;The Flintstones.&#8221; In the show, the Loyal Order of Water Buffalos is depicted as a men&#8217;s fraternal organization to which Fred Flintstone and his friend Barney Rubble belong. It is portrayed as a humorous exaggeration of traditional fraternal organizations, highlighting the rituals, secret handshakes, and comedic initiation ceremonies often associated with such groups.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Water Buffalos serves as a satirical representation of real-life fraternal organizations, including the Loyal Order of Buffaloes. Its purpose in the show is primarily comedic and provides a backdrop for humorous situations and storytelling. It is important to note that the fictional Loyal Order of Water Buffalos should not be confused with the actual Loyal Order of Buffaloes, which is a genuine fraternal organization that promotes fellowship and charitable endeavors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">140</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notes on WSPR Mode</title>
		<link>/notes-on-wspr-mode/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 23:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ham Radio]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/notes-on-wspr-mode/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WSPR (Weak Signal Propagation Reporter) is a digital communication mode used in amateur radio. It is designed for sending and receiving very low-power signals, typically in the milliwatt range, over long distances using radio waves. WSPR enables the study of radio propagation and provides valuable data for understanding how signals propagate under various conditions. WSPR operates by transmitting short data packets containing the station&#8217;s call sign, location, and power level on a specific frequency. These transmissions are received by other WSPR stations, and the data is collected and uploaded to online databases such as WSPRNet. WSPRNet is &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>WSPR (Weak Signal Propagation Reporter) is a digital communication mode used in amateur radio. It is designed for sending and receiving very low-power signals, typically in the milliwatt range, over long distances using radio waves. WSPR enables the study of radio propagation and provides valuable data for understanding how signals propagate under various conditions.</p>



<p>WSPR operates by transmitting short data packets containing the station&#8217;s call sign, location, and power level on a specific frequency. These transmissions are received by other WSPR stations, and the data is collected and uploaded to online databases such as WSPRNet. WSPRNet is a network of servers that receive and aggregate the data from participating stations worldwide, allowing for the analysis of propagation patterns and the monitoring of signal strengths and path losses.</p>



<p>Grafana is a powerful open-source software used for visualizing and analyzing data from various sources. It offers flexible and customizable dashboards that can display real-time or historical data in a visually appealing manner. In the context of WSPR, Grafana can be used to create visual representations of propagation data collected from WSPRNet. This allows radio amateurs and researchers to observe trends, track changes in signal strengths, and gain insights into RF propagation characteristics.</p>



<p>Weather balloons are often employed in radio experiments to measure atmospheric conditions and monitor propagation phenomena. These balloons carry payloads equipped with various sensors and radio equipment, including WSPR transmitters. By launching these weather balloons equipped with WSPR transmitters, researchers can obtain valuable data on atmospheric conditions, wind patterns, and radio signal propagation. The collected data can help in understanding how weather conditions affect radio waves and provide insights into the behavior of RF propagation in different atmospheric layers.</p>



<p>WSPR is a digital communication mode used in amateur radio to transmit low-power signals for studying RF propagation. WSPRNet is a network that collects and analyzes data from participating stations, and Grafana can be used to visualize this data. Weather balloons equipped with WSPR transmitters are deployed to gather information about atmospheric conditions and RF propagation, contributing to the understanding of radio wave behavior in different environments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">936</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Musical Journey of Coil</title>
		<link>/the-musical-journey-of-coil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 23:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/the-musical-journey-of-coil/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the vast and enigmatic realm of experimental music, few bands have managed to captivate and bewilder audiences quite like Coil. Known for their esoteric soundscapes, provocative lyrics, and unapologetic exploration of occult themes, Coil&#8217;s musical journey transcended the boundaries of conventional music, paving the way for a new wave of sonic exploration. This blog post delves deep into the mystical world of Coil, their profound fascination with the occult, and their enduring influence on other bands. Coil, formed in 1982 by the enigmatic duo of John Balance and Peter Christopherson, embraced the occult as a central &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the vast and enigmatic realm of experimental music, few bands have managed to captivate and bewilder audiences quite like Coil. Known for their esoteric soundscapes, provocative lyrics, and unapologetic exploration of occult themes, Coil&#8217;s musical journey transcended the boundaries of conventional music, paving the way for a new wave of sonic exploration. This blog post delves deep into the mystical world of Coil, their profound fascination with the occult, and their enduring influence on other bands.</p>



<p>Coil, formed in 1982 by the enigmatic duo of John Balance and Peter Christopherson, embraced the occult as a central theme in their music and philosophy. Drawing inspiration from various esoteric traditions, including Western occultism, chaos magic, alchemy, and Eastern mysticism, Coil crafted a sonic tapestry that merged the sacred and the profane. Their music became a gateway to the hidden realms of the subconscious, inviting listeners to embark on a transformative journey.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s unique sound defied categorization, blending elements of industrial, ambient, electronic, and experimental music into an alchemical concoction. Their discography spans across multiple albums, EPs, and collaborations, each a testament to their audacious creativity. From the haunting and ethereal melodies of &#8220;Horse Rotorvator&#8221; to the dissonant and hypnotic beats of &#8220;Love&#8217;s Secret Domain,&#8221; Coil&#8217;s music delved deep into the psyche, challenging the listener to confront their innermost fears and desires.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s album &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; is a unique and experimental project that delves into the concept of time and its transcendence. Released in 1998, it is an exploration of sonic frequencies and their potential to alter consciousness and perception. The album&#8217;s soundscapes are designed to induce a meditative and trance-like state, with the intention of facilitating time travel or temporal dislocation.</p>



<p>The songs on &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; are not conventionally named but are instead titled using a unique system. Each track is denoted by a combination of numbers and letters, representing specific frequencies and mathematical calculations. These titles are derived from John Dee&#8217;s Enochian system of magick, a complex occult framework involving angelic communication and cosmology.</p>



<p>The numerical and alphabetical titles of the songs on &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; are thought to correspond to specific frequencies or vibrations. It is believed that these frequencies, when experienced or meditated upon, can potentially open doorways to altered states of consciousness, time dilation, or transcendent experiences.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s intention with &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; was to create a sonic environment that acts as a vehicle for the listener&#8217;s personal exploration of time and the expansion of consciousness. The album serves as an experimental sonic tool, inviting the listener to engage with the frequencies and engage in their own journey through time and space.</p>



<p>It is worth noting that interpretations of &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; can vary, as the album&#8217;s conceptual nature allows for individual experiences and subjective interpretations. Listeners may have their own unique insights or understandings of the music&#8217;s purpose and effect, further emphasizing Coil&#8217;s commitment to pushing the boundaries of music and the exploration of metaphysical concepts.</p>



<p>Beyond their music, Coil adopted a ritualistic aesthetic, infusing their live performances with occult symbolism and theatricality. Their shows became immersive experiences, blurring the boundaries between art, music, and ritual. The band&#8217;s use of sigils, incense, and occult artifacts created an atmosphere of mystery and transcendence, enveloping the audience in a world of enchantment. Coil&#8217;s live performances were an invocation of otherworldly energies, inviting the audience to partake in a collective esoteric journey.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s influence extended far beyond their own discography, leaving an indelible mark on the musical landscape. Their audacious experimentation and unabashed embrace of the occult opened the floodgates for a new wave of musicians exploring similar themes. Bands such as Current 93, Psychic TV, and Throbbing Gristle, among others, influenced or drew inspiration from Coil&#8217;s boundary-pushing approach, incorporating occult elements into their own music.</p>



<p>Furthermore, Coil&#8217;s influence can be traced across a wide range of genres, from industrial and electronic music to neofolk and dark ambient. Their legacy lives on in the works of contemporary artists such as Pharmakon, Haxan Cloak, and Prurient, who continue to explore the darker corners of sound and the esoteric.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s musical journey was a mystical odyssey, delving into the depths of occult symbolism, esoteric philosophy, and sonic experimentation. They fearlessly pushed the boundaries of music and art, inviting listeners to confront the hidden recesses of their psyche. Coil&#8217;s influence on other bands and artists cannot be overstated, as they ushered in a new era of sonic exploration, inspiring musicians to embrace the mystical and the unknown.</p>



<span id="more-929"></span>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">929</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Symbiosis of Sensations: Frisson and Dark Ambient Music</title>
		<link>/the-symbiosis-of-sensations-exploring-asmr-frissons-and-dark-ambient-music/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 22:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/the-symbiosis-of-sensations-exploring-asmr-frissons-and-dark-ambient-music/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Frisson and ASMR In the vast and intricate world of sensory experiences, certain phenomena and artistic expressions intertwine to create unique and profound moments of perception. This blog post delves into the captivating realms of ASMR (Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response), frissons (chills or tingling sensations), dark ambient music, the band Coil, and their intriguing connections to LSD, ketamine, and the occultist Aleister Crowley. Prepare to embark on a journey that intertwines the ethereal, the sensory, and the mystical. Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response ASMR, a phenomenon characterized by pleasurable tingling sensations that typically originate from auditory or visual &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Frisson and ASMR</h2>



<p>In the vast and intricate world of sensory experiences, certain phenomena and artistic expressions intertwine to create unique and profound moments of perception. This blog post delves into the captivating realms of ASMR (Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response), frissons (chills or tingling sensations), dark ambient music, the band Coil, and their intriguing connections to LSD, ketamine, and the occultist Aleister Crowley. Prepare to embark on a journey that intertwines the ethereal, the sensory, and the mystical.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response</h2>



<p>ASMR, a phenomenon characterized by pleasurable tingling sensations that typically originate from auditory or visual stimuli, has captivated millions around the world. It can induce a deeply relaxing and euphoric state, often described as a &#8220;brain massage.&#8221; Frissons, on the other hand, are sudden and intense waves of pleasurable shivers, often accompanied by goosebumps. These sensations can be triggered by various stimuli, including music, art, or emotionally charged moments.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Dark Ambient Atmosphere</h2>



<p>Dark ambient music, with its atmospheric textures and haunting soundscapes, forms an ideal conduit for inducing ASMR and frissons. This genre embraces dissonance, hypnotic rhythms, and atmospheric layers to create immersive sonic experiences. The combination of sonic elements, such as deep drones, ethereal melodies, and intricate sound design, acts as a catalyst for sensory exploration and emotional resonance.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Coil</h2>



<p>The influential band Coil, with their enigmatic and eclectic musical approach, ventured into the realms of dark ambient music. Their fascination with altered states of consciousness and occultism manifested in their sonic tapestries. While Coil didn&#8217;t explicitly create ASMR-inducing content, their music&#8217;s immersive nature and intricate layers have the potential to trigger such sensations in receptive individuals.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Chemical Frisson</h2>



<p>LSD and ketamine, both psychedelic substances, have long been associated with expanded consciousness, altered perception, and spiritual exploration. LSD, known for its hallucinogenic properties, can induce profound sensory experiences, heightening the perception of sound and visual stimuli. Ketamine, a dissociative anesthetic, can create a sense of detachment from the body and facilitate introspection.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s members, particularly John Balance, openly discussed their experiences with psychedelic substances, including LSD and ketamine. Their music often reflects their fascination with altered states of mind, occultism, and mysticism. While Coil&#8217;s work is not explicitly about psychedelics, their explorations and their ability to create immersive and introspective sonic environments resonated with individuals who have had similar psychedelic experiences.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Obligatory Crowley Mention</h2>



<p>Aleister Crowley, an influential occultist, left an indelible mark on Coil&#8217;s philosophical and artistic endeavors. Crowley&#8217;s teachings, which encompassed ceremonial magick, symbolism, and esoteric philosophy, found resonance within Coil&#8217;s esoteric interests. While not directly related to ASMR or frissons, Crowley&#8217;s occult legacy contributed to the band&#8217;s exploration of transcendent experiences and their desire to unravel the mysteries of consciousness.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Summary</h2>



<p>These phenomena and influences offer gateways to altered states of consciousness, introspection, and the pursuit of the numinous. Whether through the soothing whispers of ASMR, the haunting melodies of dark ambient music, or the transcendence facilitated by psychedelic substances and occult teachings, these experiences remind us of the profound and intricate nature of our senses and the mysteries that lie beyond.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">923</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thelema: Eastern and Western Individualism</title>
		<link>/thelema-eastern-and-western-individualism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 01:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/thelema-eastern-and-western-individualism/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thelema Thelema, as a philosophical and religious system developed by Aleister Crowley in the early 20th century. It presents an interesting intersection between Eastern philosophy and the Western enforcement of morality and convention. Thelema draws upon various spiritual traditions, including elements of Western occultism. It also involves mysticism, and ancient Egyptian mythology, while also incorporating Eastern philosophical concepts. The idea of True Will and the pursuit of self-realization are central to the practice. True Will One of the central tenets of Thelema is the concept of True Will. This can be understood as an individual&#8217;s unique and &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-thelema">Thelema</h2>



<p>Thelema, as a philosophical and religious system developed by Aleister Crowley in the early 20th century. It presents an interesting intersection between Eastern philosophy and the Western enforcement of morality and convention. Thelema draws upon various spiritual traditions, including elements of Western occultism. It also involves mysticism, and ancient Egyptian mythology, while also incorporating Eastern philosophical concepts. The idea of True Will and the pursuit of self-realization are central to the practice.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-true-will">True Will</h2>



<p>One of the central tenets of Thelema is the concept of True Will. This can be understood as an individual&#8217;s unique and authentic purpose in life. Thelemites believe that discovering and aligning with one&#8217;s True Will is essential for personal growth and fulfillment. This concept shares similarities with Eastern philosophies that emphasize the importance of self-discovery. Hinduism&#8217;s concept of Dharma or Buddhism&#8217;s teachings on finding one&#8217;s own path to liberation is a good example.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-independent-thought-above-all">Independent Thought Above All</h2>



<p>However, Thelema also challenges conventional Western notions of morality and societal norms. It promotes the idea of individual sovereignty and encourages individuals to follow their own desires and inclinations. Provided they do not infringe upon the rights of others, of course. This can be seen as a departure from traditional Western religions that often enforce moral codes and dogmas.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-eastern-philosophy">Eastern Philosophy</h2>



<p>Eastern philosophy often encourages personal transformation and spiritual exploration. Thelema aligns with the idea of individual empowerment and the pursuit of one&#8217;s authentic path. However, the rejection of conventional morality and its emphasis on individualism may be seen as in line with Western counterculture. Both movements challenge societal norms and advocated for personal liberation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-interpretation-of-thelema">Interpretation of Thelema</h2>



<p>It is important to note that Thelema, like any belief system, is subject to interpretation and varies among practitioners. While some individuals may emphasize the individualistic and rebellious aspects of Thelema, others may focus more on its spiritual. The transformative elements find connections with Eastern philosophies that promote self-realization and inner harmony.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-blended-spirituality">Blended Spirituality</h2>



<p>In summary, Thelema presents an intriguing blend of Eastern and Western influences. It shares similarities with Eastern philosophies in its emphasis on self-discovery and the pursuit of one&#8217;s unique purpose. However, it also challenges Western enforcement of morality and convention by promoting individual sovereignty and freedom. Thelema may fit between the paradigm of Eastern philosophy and Western enforcement of morality. This judgement depends upon the interpretation and emphasis of its practitioners.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">883</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
