<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Music &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/music/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 01:41:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Music &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Musical Journey of Coil</title>
		<link>/the-musical-journey-of-coil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 23:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/the-musical-journey-of-coil/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the vast and enigmatic realm of experimental music, few bands have managed to captivate and bewilder audiences quite like Coil. Known for their esoteric soundscapes, provocative lyrics, and unapologetic exploration of occult themes, Coil&#8217;s musical journey transcended the boundaries of conventional music, paving the way for a new wave of sonic exploration. This blog post delves deep into the mystical world of Coil, their profound fascination with the occult, and their enduring influence on other bands. Coil, formed in 1982 by the enigmatic duo of John Balance and Peter Christopherson, embraced the occult as a central &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the vast and enigmatic realm of experimental music, few bands have managed to captivate and bewilder audiences quite like Coil. Known for their esoteric soundscapes, provocative lyrics, and unapologetic exploration of occult themes, Coil&#8217;s musical journey transcended the boundaries of conventional music, paving the way for a new wave of sonic exploration. This blog post delves deep into the mystical world of Coil, their profound fascination with the occult, and their enduring influence on other bands.</p>



<p>Coil, formed in 1982 by the enigmatic duo of John Balance and Peter Christopherson, embraced the occult as a central theme in their music and philosophy. Drawing inspiration from various esoteric traditions, including Western occultism, chaos magic, alchemy, and Eastern mysticism, Coil crafted a sonic tapestry that merged the sacred and the profane. Their music became a gateway to the hidden realms of the subconscious, inviting listeners to embark on a transformative journey.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s unique sound defied categorization, blending elements of industrial, ambient, electronic, and experimental music into an alchemical concoction. Their discography spans across multiple albums, EPs, and collaborations, each a testament to their audacious creativity. From the haunting and ethereal melodies of &#8220;Horse Rotorvator&#8221; to the dissonant and hypnotic beats of &#8220;Love&#8217;s Secret Domain,&#8221; Coil&#8217;s music delved deep into the psyche, challenging the listener to confront their innermost fears and desires.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s album &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; is a unique and experimental project that delves into the concept of time and its transcendence. Released in 1998, it is an exploration of sonic frequencies and their potential to alter consciousness and perception. The album&#8217;s soundscapes are designed to induce a meditative and trance-like state, with the intention of facilitating time travel or temporal dislocation.</p>



<p>The songs on &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; are not conventionally named but are instead titled using a unique system. Each track is denoted by a combination of numbers and letters, representing specific frequencies and mathematical calculations. These titles are derived from John Dee&#8217;s Enochian system of magick, a complex occult framework involving angelic communication and cosmology.</p>



<p>The numerical and alphabetical titles of the songs on &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; are thought to correspond to specific frequencies or vibrations. It is believed that these frequencies, when experienced or meditated upon, can potentially open doorways to altered states of consciousness, time dilation, or transcendent experiences.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s intention with &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; was to create a sonic environment that acts as a vehicle for the listener&#8217;s personal exploration of time and the expansion of consciousness. The album serves as an experimental sonic tool, inviting the listener to engage with the frequencies and engage in their own journey through time and space.</p>



<p>It is worth noting that interpretations of &#8220;Time Machines&#8221; can vary, as the album&#8217;s conceptual nature allows for individual experiences and subjective interpretations. Listeners may have their own unique insights or understandings of the music&#8217;s purpose and effect, further emphasizing Coil&#8217;s commitment to pushing the boundaries of music and the exploration of metaphysical concepts.</p>



<p>Beyond their music, Coil adopted a ritualistic aesthetic, infusing their live performances with occult symbolism and theatricality. Their shows became immersive experiences, blurring the boundaries between art, music, and ritual. The band&#8217;s use of sigils, incense, and occult artifacts created an atmosphere of mystery and transcendence, enveloping the audience in a world of enchantment. Coil&#8217;s live performances were an invocation of otherworldly energies, inviting the audience to partake in a collective esoteric journey.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s influence extended far beyond their own discography, leaving an indelible mark on the musical landscape. Their audacious experimentation and unabashed embrace of the occult opened the floodgates for a new wave of musicians exploring similar themes. Bands such as Current 93, Psychic TV, and Throbbing Gristle, among others, influenced or drew inspiration from Coil&#8217;s boundary-pushing approach, incorporating occult elements into their own music.</p>



<p>Furthermore, Coil&#8217;s influence can be traced across a wide range of genres, from industrial and electronic music to neofolk and dark ambient. Their legacy lives on in the works of contemporary artists such as Pharmakon, Haxan Cloak, and Prurient, who continue to explore the darker corners of sound and the esoteric.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s musical journey was a mystical odyssey, delving into the depths of occult symbolism, esoteric philosophy, and sonic experimentation. They fearlessly pushed the boundaries of music and art, inviting listeners to confront the hidden recesses of their psyche. Coil&#8217;s influence on other bands and artists cannot be overstated, as they ushered in a new era of sonic exploration, inspiring musicians to embrace the mystical and the unknown.</p>



<span id="more-929"></span>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exploring the Enigmatic Depths: A Deep Dive into Dark Ambient Music</title>
		<link>/dark-ambient/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 23:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/exploring-the-enigmatic-depths-a-deep-dive-into-dark-ambient-music/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction to Dark Ambient Music Within the expansive realm of ambient music, a subgenre exists that delves into the shadows. It conjures a sense of foreboding and mystery. This subgenre, known as dark ambient, harnesses atmospheric soundscapes to create an eerie and otherworldly sonic experience. In this post, we embark on an exploration of dark ambient. We will focus on the works of Coil and Lustmord, two major contributors to the genre. We will also examine examples of Description of Audio Dark ambient is a genre that immerses the listener in haunting and atmospheric soundscapes. It evokes &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-introduction-to-dark-ambient-music">Introduction to Dark Ambient Music</h2>



<p>Within the expansive realm of ambient music, a subgenre exists that delves into the shadows. It conjures  a sense of foreboding and mystery. This subgenre, known as dark ambient, harnesses atmospheric soundscapes to create an eerie and otherworldly sonic experience. In this post, we embark on an exploration of dark ambient. We will focus on the works of Coil and Lustmord, two major contributors to the genre. We will also examine examples of </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-description-of-audio">Description of Audio</h2>



<p>Dark ambient is a genre that immerses the listener in haunting and atmospheric soundscapes. It evokes feelings of unease, introspection, and the supernatural. Dark ambient embraces dissonance. Ambient music is relaxing, dark ambient is disturbing. The textural experimentation and a sonic palette reflect the underbelly of existence. It is music that takes us to uncharted territories, evoking a sense of dread, awe, and introspection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-perhaps-the-creator-of-the-genre">Perhaps the Creator of the Genre</h2>



<p>Lustmord, a pioneer in dark ambient, plunges listeners into the abyss with his atmospheric compositions. His album &#8220;Heresy&#8221; serves as a prime example of his artistry and occult leanings. The track &#8220;Black Star&#8221; combines deep, resonant drones with haunting vocal samples. It conjures a sense of cosmic dread and the mysteries of the void. Lustmord&#8217;s work transcends conventional music, inviting listeners to explore the recesses of their psyche and confront their deepest fears.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-coil-one-of-several-pioneering-bands-of-dark-ambient">Coil, one of Several Pioneering Bands of Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>Coil, with their multifaceted exploration of occult themes, has made an indelible mark on dark ambient. Their seminal album &#8220;The Ape of Naples&#8221; stands as a testament to their artistic vision and occult fascinations. &#8220;Fire of the Mind&#8221; and &#8220;Going Up&#8221; delve into themes of ritualistic transformation and spiritual transcendence. The hypnotic rhythms, cryptic lyrics and subtle references to esoteric symbolism, create a disruptive atmosphere. It blurs the boundaries between the sacred and the profane.</p>



<p>&#8220;Musick to Play in the Dark Vol. 1,&#8221; delves into the mystical realms with tracks like &#8220;Are You Shivering?&#8221;. The track &#8220;Red Birds Will Fly Out of the East and Destroy Paris in a Night.&#8221; can be terrifying. These compositions traverse the depths of the subconscious, enveloping the listener in an arcane soundscape. Coil&#8217;s music often acts as a portal, allowing us to glimpse the hidden dimensions beyond the veil. Darl Ambient becomes the void.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s and Lustmord&#8217;s music, through their albums and songs, offer glimpses into the occult. They transport us to liminal spaces where the veils between worlds are thin, inviting us to explore our subconscious. They force confrontation between the endless mysteries that lie within.</p>



<p>In Coil&#8217;s work, the occult themes can be interpreted as metaphors for personal transformation. Often, spiritual enlightenment and the quest for hidden knowledge can be felt.. Their music becomes a vessel through which the listener can embark on a transformative journey. Encouraging listeners to shed old limitations and embracing the unknown is clearly a goal.</p>



<p>Lustmord&#8217;s compositions immerse us in the depths of cosmic and primordial forces. The occult themes in his work can be seen as gateways to existential contemplation. We confront the vastness and mysteries of the universe. They invite us to embrace the terrifying beauty of the unknown and find solace in the abyss.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-occult-themes-in-dark-ambient">Occult Themes in Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The occult themes within dark ambient music serve as gateways to introspection, transformation, and the exploration of the unknown. They act as sonic manifestations of esoteric philosophies, arcane rituals, and the interplay between light and darkness.</p>



<p>Dark ambient music, with its atmospheric textures and occult themes, offers a sonic journey into the enigmatic depths of existence. Coil and Lustmord, through their pioneering works, have reshaped the genre and expanded its sonic boundaries. By exploring specific albums and songs, we can interpret the occult themes as invitations. They encourage us to delve into our subconscious, confront our fears, and embrace the transformative power of the unknown. Dark ambient remains an immersive and profound genre, providing a sonic sanctuary for those who seek solace in the shadows.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-drugs-and-dark-ambient">Drugs and Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The band Coil and the artist Lustmord have both mentioned or discussed LSD (Lysergic acid diethylamide) in various interviews. They are not shy about their explorations of the psyche.</p>



<p>Coil, known for their openness about their exploration of altered states of consciousness have made references to LSD in interviews. They have discussed the influence of LSD on their creative process and their experiences with the psychedelic substance. It is worth noting that Coil&#8217;s interests extended beyond just LSD, including wide range of psychedelic substances and esoteric practices.</p>



<p>Lustmord has referenced LSD in interviews. He has discussed the influence of psychedelics on his creative work and their potential for expanding consciousness and perception.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Coil and Lustmord have embraced a multidimensional approach to their art, drawing inspiration from various sources. These include altered states of consciousness induced by substances like LSD. These references often highlight the transformative potential of psychedelics and their impact on the creative process.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-introduction-to-dark-ambient-music-0">Introduction to Dark Ambient Music</h2>



<p>Within the expansive realm of ambient music, a subgenre exists that delves into the shadows. It conjures  a sense of foreboding and mystery. This subgenre, known as dark ambient, harnesses atmospheric soundscapes to create an eerie and otherworldly sonic experience. In this post, we embark on an exploration of dark ambient. We will focus on the works of Coil and Lustmord, two major contributors to the genre. We will also examine examples of </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-description-of-audio-0">Description of Audio</h2>



<p>Dark ambient is a genre that immerses the listener in haunting and atmospheric soundscapes. It evokes feelings of unease, introspection, and the supernatural. Dark ambient embraces dissonance. Ambient music is relaxing, dark ambient is disturbing. The textural experimentation and a sonic palette reflect the underbelly of existence. It is music that takes us to uncharted territories, evoking a sense of dread, awe, and introspection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-perhaps-the-creator-of-the-genre-0">Perhaps the Creator of the Genre</h2>



<p>Lustmord, a pioneer in dark ambient, plunges listeners into the abyss with his atmospheric compositions. His album &#8220;Heresy&#8221; serves as a prime example of his artistry and occult leanings. The track &#8220;Black Star&#8221; combines deep, resonant drones with haunting vocal samples. It conjures a sense of cosmic dread and the mysteries of the void. Lustmord&#8217;s work transcends conventional music, inviting listeners to explore the recesses of their psyche and confront their deepest fears.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-coil-a-pioneering-bands-of-dark-ambient">Coil, a Pioneering Bands of Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>Coil, with their multifaceted exploration of occult themes, has made an indelible mark on dark ambient. Their seminal album &#8220;The Ape of Naples&#8221; stands as a testament to their artistic vision and occult fascinations. &#8220;Fire of the Mind&#8221; and &#8220;Going Up&#8221; delve into themes of ritualistic transformation and spiritual transcendence. The hypnotic rhythms, cryptic lyrics and subtle references to esoteric symbolism, create a disruptive atmosphere. It blurs the boundaries between the sacred and the profane.</p>



<p>&#8220;Musick to Play in the Dark Vol. 1,&#8221; delves into the mystical realms with tracks like &#8220;Are You Shivering?&#8221;. The track &#8220;Red Birds Will Fly Out of the East and Destroy Paris in a Night.&#8221; can be terrifying. These compositions traverse the depths of the subconscious, enveloping the listener in an arcane soundscape. Coil&#8217;s music often acts as a portal, allowing us to glimpse the hidden dimensions beyond the veil. Dark Ambient becomes the void.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s and Lustmord&#8217;s music, through their albums and songs, offer glimpses into the occult. They transport us to liminal spaces where the veils between worlds are thin, inviting us to explore our subconscious. They force confrontation between the endless mysteries that lie within.</p>



<p>In Coil&#8217;s work, the occult themes can be interpreted as metaphors for personal transformation. Often, spiritual enlightenment and the quest for hidden knowledge can be felt.. Their music becomes a vessel through which the listener can embark on a transformative journey. Encouraging listeners to shed old limitations and embracing the unknown is clearly a goal.</p>



<p>Lustmord&#8217;s compositions immerse us in the depths of cosmic and primordial forces. The occult themes in his work can be seen as gateways to existential contemplation. We confront the vastness and mysteries of the universe. They invite us to embrace the terrifying beauty of the unknown and find solace in the abyss.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-occult-themes-in-dark-ambient-0">Occult Themes in Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The occult themes within dark ambient music serve as gateways to introspection, transformation, and the exploration of the unknown. They act as sonic manifestations of esoteric philosophies, arcane rituals, and the interplay between light and darkness.</p>



<p>Dark ambient music, with its atmospheric textures and occult themes, offers a sonic journey into the enigmatic depths of existence. Coil and Lustmord, through their pioneering works, have reshaped the genre and expanded its sonic boundaries. By exploring specific albums and songs, we can interpret the occult themes as invitations. They encourage us to delve into our subconscious, confront our fears, and embrace the transformative power of the unknown. Dark ambient remains an immersive and profound genre, providing a sonic sanctuary for those who seek solace in the shadows.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-drugs-and-dark-ambient-0">Drugs and Dark Ambient</h2>



<p>The band Coil and the artist Lustmord have both mentioned or discussed LSD (Lysergic acid diethylamide) in various interviews. They are not shy about their explorations of the psyche.</p>



<p>Coil, known for their openness about their exploration of altered states of consciousness have made references to LSD in interviews. They have discussed the influence of LSD on their creative process and their experiences with the psychedelic substance. It is worth noting that Coil&#8217;s interests extended beyond just LSD, including wide range of psychedelic substances and esoteric practices.</p>



<p>Lustmord has referenced LSD in interviews. He has discussed the influence of psychedelics on his creative work and their potential for expanding consciousness and perception.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion-0">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Coil and Lustmord have embraced a multidimensional approach to their art, drawing inspiration from various sources. These include altered states of consciousness induced by substances like LSD. These references often highlight the transformative potential of psychedelics and their impact on the creative process.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed aligncenter is-type-wp-embed is-provider-live-coil-archive wp-block-embed-live-coil-archive"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="b2Q0jw8l3L"><a href="https://live-coil-archive.com/">The Live COIL Archive</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;The Live COIL Archive&#8221; &#8212; Live COIL Archive" src="https://live-coil-archive.com/embed/#?secret=4SZ4bnEejR#?secret=b2Q0jw8l3L" data-secret="b2Q0jw8l3L" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://www.lustmord.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.lustmord.com/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Symbiosis of Sensations: Frisson and Dark Ambient Music</title>
		<link>/the-symbiosis-of-sensations-exploring-asmr-frissons-and-dark-ambient-music/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 22:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/the-symbiosis-of-sensations-exploring-asmr-frissons-and-dark-ambient-music/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Frisson and ASMR In the vast and intricate world of sensory experiences, certain phenomena and artistic expressions intertwine to create unique and profound moments of perception. This blog post delves into the captivating realms of ASMR (Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response), frissons (chills or tingling sensations), dark ambient music, the band Coil, and their intriguing connections to LSD, ketamine, and the occultist Aleister Crowley. Prepare to embark on a journey that intertwines the ethereal, the sensory, and the mystical. Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response ASMR, a phenomenon characterized by pleasurable tingling sensations that typically originate from auditory or visual &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Frisson and ASMR</h2>



<p>In the vast and intricate world of sensory experiences, certain phenomena and artistic expressions intertwine to create unique and profound moments of perception. This blog post delves into the captivating realms of ASMR (Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response), frissons (chills or tingling sensations), dark ambient music, the band Coil, and their intriguing connections to LSD, ketamine, and the occultist Aleister Crowley. Prepare to embark on a journey that intertwines the ethereal, the sensory, and the mystical.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response</h2>



<p>ASMR, a phenomenon characterized by pleasurable tingling sensations that typically originate from auditory or visual stimuli, has captivated millions around the world. It can induce a deeply relaxing and euphoric state, often described as a &#8220;brain massage.&#8221; Frissons, on the other hand, are sudden and intense waves of pleasurable shivers, often accompanied by goosebumps. These sensations can be triggered by various stimuli, including music, art, or emotionally charged moments.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Dark Ambient Atmosphere</h2>



<p>Dark ambient music, with its atmospheric textures and haunting soundscapes, forms an ideal conduit for inducing ASMR and frissons. This genre embraces dissonance, hypnotic rhythms, and atmospheric layers to create immersive sonic experiences. The combination of sonic elements, such as deep drones, ethereal melodies, and intricate sound design, acts as a catalyst for sensory exploration and emotional resonance.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Coil</h2>



<p>The influential band Coil, with their enigmatic and eclectic musical approach, ventured into the realms of dark ambient music. Their fascination with altered states of consciousness and occultism manifested in their sonic tapestries. While Coil didn&#8217;t explicitly create ASMR-inducing content, their music&#8217;s immersive nature and intricate layers have the potential to trigger such sensations in receptive individuals.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Chemical Frisson</h2>



<p>LSD and ketamine, both psychedelic substances, have long been associated with expanded consciousness, altered perception, and spiritual exploration. LSD, known for its hallucinogenic properties, can induce profound sensory experiences, heightening the perception of sound and visual stimuli. Ketamine, a dissociative anesthetic, can create a sense of detachment from the body and facilitate introspection.</p>



<p>Coil&#8217;s members, particularly John Balance, openly discussed their experiences with psychedelic substances, including LSD and ketamine. Their music often reflects their fascination with altered states of mind, occultism, and mysticism. While Coil&#8217;s work is not explicitly about psychedelics, their explorations and their ability to create immersive and introspective sonic environments resonated with individuals who have had similar psychedelic experiences.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Obligatory Crowley Mention</h2>



<p>Aleister Crowley, an influential occultist, left an indelible mark on Coil&#8217;s philosophical and artistic endeavors. Crowley&#8217;s teachings, which encompassed ceremonial magick, symbolism, and esoteric philosophy, found resonance within Coil&#8217;s esoteric interests. While not directly related to ASMR or frissons, Crowley&#8217;s occult legacy contributed to the band&#8217;s exploration of transcendent experiences and their desire to unravel the mysteries of consciousness.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Summary</h2>



<p>These phenomena and influences offer gateways to altered states of consciousness, introspection, and the pursuit of the numinous. Whether through the soothing whispers of ASMR, the haunting melodies of dark ambient music, or the transcendence facilitated by psychedelic substances and occult teachings, these experiences remind us of the profound and intricate nature of our senses and the mysteries that lie beyond.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Devo: The Contributions of these Legendary Pioneers</title>
		<link>/devo-legendary-contributions-to-music/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 19:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=66</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pioneering Sound The American new wave band  Devo, formed in the 1970s, has had a significant influence on music, art, and popular culture. Known for their unique sound, satirical lyrics, and distinctive visual style, Devo emerged as one of the pioneers of the new wave movement and played a vital role in shaping the alternative music scene. We Are Devo Devo&#8217;s music blended punk rock, electronic elements, and unconventional song structures, creating a sound that was both catchy and experimental. Their breakthrough came with the release of their debut album, &#8220;Q: Are We Not Men? A: We &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Pioneering Sound</h2>



<p>The American new wave band  Devo, formed in the 1970s, has had a significant influence on music, art, and popular culture. Known for their unique sound, satirical lyrics, and distinctive visual style, Devo emerged as one of the pioneers of the new wave movement and played a vital role in shaping the alternative music scene.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">We Are Devo</h2>



<p>Devo&#8217;s music blended punk rock, electronic elements, and unconventional song structures, creating a sound that was both catchy and experimental. Their breakthrough came with the release of their debut album, &#8220;Q: Are We Not Men? A: We Are Devo!&#8221; in 1978, produced by Brian Eno. The album&#8217;s quirky yet accessible tracks, such as &#8220;Jocko Homo&#8221; and a cover of the Rolling Stones&#8217; &#8220;Satisfaction,&#8221; showcased Devo&#8217;s deconstructive approach to music, questioning societal norms and consumer culture.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Style</h2>



<p>In addition to their music, Devo&#8217;s visual aesthetic played a crucial role in their influence. The band members adopted a distinct look, donning yellow hazmat suits, energy dome hats, and robotic movements, which became iconic symbols of their image. This visually striking and robotic appearance served as a critique of conformity and the dehumanizing effects of modern society.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Wry Wit and Religion, Too.</h2>



<p>Devo&#8217;s artistic endeavors extended beyond music and into various other mediums. One notable collaboration was their association with the Church of the SubGenius, a satirical religious organization founded in the late 1970s. The Church of the SubGenius promoted a humorous critique of mainstream culture and claimed to offer salvation through a parody of traditional religion. Devo&#8217;s involvement with the Church was primarily in the form of performing at SubGenius events and incorporating SubGenius themes into their work.</p>



<p>Devo&#8217;s connection to the Church of the SubGenius further solidified their status as countercultural figures, as both entities shared a similar satirical approach to questioning authority and cultural norms. Through their collaboration, Devo contributed to the spread of the SubGenius philosophy and helped expose it to a wider audience.</p>



<p></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Overall, Devo&#8217;s influence can be seen in their unique music, subversive imagery, and collaborations with the Church of the SubGenius. They challenged the conventions of popular culture, delivering thought-provoking social commentary through their music and aesthetic choices. Their impact on subsequent generations of musicians, artists, and fans is evident in the continued appreciation for their innovative approach and their lasting legacy in the alternative music landscape.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>David Tibet: Exploring the Enigmatic Music and Spiritual Influences</title>
		<link>/david-tibet-exploring-the-enigmatic-music-and-spiritual-influences/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 15:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[David Tibet, a visionary musician and artist, has carved a unique path in the realm of experimental music with his long-running project, Current 93. This article delves into the music, life, and history of David Tibet, focusing on his influential project and the profound impact of his spiritual beliefs on his music. Furthermore, we will explore the ways in which his music has influenced other artists and musicians, including potential connections to Marilyn Manson, Tool, and other popular figures. I. The Musical Journey of David Tibet: A. Formation of Current 93: Current 93 was formed in the &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>David Tibet, a visionary musician and artist, has carved a unique path in the realm of experimental music with his long-running project, Current 93. This article delves into the music, life, and history of David Tibet, focusing on his influential project and the profound impact of his spiritual beliefs on his music. Furthermore, we will explore the ways in which his music has influenced other artists and musicians, including potential connections to Marilyn Manson, Tool, and other popular figures.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>I. The Musical Journey of David Tibet:</strong></p>



<p><br>A. Formation of Current 93: Current 93 was formed in the early 1980s and quickly gained recognition for their experimental and atmospheric soundscapes. David Tibet served as the driving force behind the project, exploring themes of mysticism, spirituality, and existentialism through his music.</p>



<p>B. Evolving Sound and Collaborations: Over the years, Current 93&#8217;s sound evolved from its early industrial and folk influences to incorporate elements of neofolk, post-industrial, and ambient music. Tibet collaborated with various musicians, such as Steven Stapleton of Nurse With Wound and Michael Cashmore, enriching the sonic palette of Current 93.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>II. Spiritual Influences on David Tibet&#8217;s Music:</strong></p>



<p><br>A. Esoteric and Mystical Beliefs: David Tibet&#8217;s music is deeply influenced by his esoteric and mystical beliefs, drawing inspiration from various spiritual traditions, including Gnosticism, Thelema, and Christian mysticism. These beliefs manifest in the lyrical themes, symbolism, and occult imagery woven throughout his compositions.</p>



<p>B. Exploration of Darkness and Transcendence: Tibet&#8217;s music often delves into themes of darkness, suffering, and transcendence. It reflects his introspective and contemplative approach to spirituality, exploring the existential questions of life, death, and the nature of existence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>III. Influence on Other Artists and Musicians:</strong></p>



<p><br>A. Impact on Experimental Music Scene: David Tibet and Current 93 have exerted a significant influence on the experimental music scene, inspiring and paving the way for a myriad of artists exploring unconventional sonic territories. Their willingness to push boundaries and blend genres has left an indelible mark on the experimental music landscape.</p>



<p>B. Connections to Marilyn Manson and Tool: While there may not be direct collaborations or formal connections between David Tibet and Marilyn Manson or Tool, there are shared thematic elements that resonate with their work. All three artists have explored dark and introspective themes, delving into the human psyche and the complexities of existence.</p>



<p>C. Inspiration for a Multitude of Artists: David  Tibet&#8217;s unique blend of spirituality, introspection, and experimental soundscapes has inspired a wide range of artists and musicians. His ability to create atmospheric and emotionally charged music has resonated with both established and emerging artists seeking to push the boundaries of their own artistic expression.</p>



<p>David Tibet&#8217;s musical journey through Current 93 has been a profound exploration of spirituality, mysticism, and existential questions. His music reflects a deep introspection and draws from a diverse range of spiritual beliefs, resulting in a unique and influential body of work. Tibet&#8217;s influence extends beyond his own musical projects, inspiring and shaping the experimental music scene, and resonating with artists and musicians seeking to push the boundaries of their own creative endeavors. As David Tibet continues to forge his artistic path, his enigmatic music and spiritual influences will undoubtedly leave an indelible legacy on the world of experimental music and beyond.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The History of Ghost and Their Occult Metal Legacy</title>
		<link>/unveiling-the-mysteries-the-history-of-ghost-and-their-occult-metal-legacy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 15:12:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.virginorpigeon.org/?p=97</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ghost, the enigmatic occult metal band, has captivated audiences worldwide with their dark and melodic sound, theatrical performances, and cryptic imagery. This article delves into the history of Ghost, exploring the mythology they have crafted around their &#8220;Church,&#8221; their music, and the connections between Tobias Forge (the mastermind behind Ghost) and Freemasonry. Additionally, we will examine any potential influences of Thelema within their music and aesthetic. I. The Emergence of Ghost and their Mythology:A. Birth of the Nameless Ghouls: Ghost emerged in 2006, shrouded in mystery, as they concealed their identities beneath masks and adopted the moniker &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Ghost, the enigmatic occult metal band, has captivated audiences worldwide with their dark and melodic sound, theatrical performances, and cryptic imagery. This article delves into the history of Ghost, exploring the mythology they have crafted around their &#8220;Church,&#8221; their music, and the connections between Tobias Forge (the mastermind behind Ghost) and Freemasonry. Additionally, we will examine any potential influences of Thelema within their music and aesthetic.</p>



<p>I. The Emergence of Ghost and their Mythology:<br />A. Birth of the Nameless Ghouls: Ghost emerged in 2006, shrouded in mystery, as they concealed their identities beneath masks and adopted the moniker of Nameless Ghouls. This anonymity added to the allure of the band, allowing their music and mythology to take center stage.</p>



<p>B. The Church and Papa Emeritus: Ghost created a fictional Church, complete with rituals and a hierarchy, led by a succession of characters known as Papa Emeritus. This mythology added depth to their music and stage presence, enhancing the occult atmosphere surrounding the band.</p>



<p>II. Tobias Forge and Freemasonry:<br />A. The Connection to Freemasonry: Tobias Forge, the mastermind behind Ghost, has openly acknowledged his interest in Freemasonry and its symbolism. While not a practicing Freemason, Forge has drawn inspiration from the teachings, rituals, and symbols associated with the craft.</p>



<p>B. Symbolism in Ghost&#8217;s Music: Ghost incorporates various esoteric symbols and references in their music, such as the inverted cross, pentagrams, and references to alchemy. These symbols, influenced by Forge&#8217;s interest in Freemasonry and occult traditions, add layers of meaning to their songs and performances.</p>



<p>III. Thelema and Ghost&#8217;s Musical Aesthetic:<br />A. The Influence of Aleister Crowley: Aleister Crowley, the influential occultist and founder of Thelema, has left a significant impact on occult-related music and art. While there is no explicit confirmation of direct connections between Ghost and Thelema, some thematic elements and symbolism in their music can be reminiscent of Thelemic ideas.</p>



<p>B. The Pursuit of Individual Will: Thelema emphasizes the pursuit of one&#8217;s True Will, the unique purpose and destiny of each individual. This concept resonates with Ghost&#8217;s exploration of individualism and self-expression, as they encourage their audience to embrace their true selves and reject societal norms.</p>



<p>IV. Musical Legacy and Impact:<br />A. Rise to Prominence: Ghost&#8217;s unique blend of occult imagery, theatrical performances, and infectious melodies has garnered a devoted fan base and critical acclaim. Their albums, such as &#8220;Opus Eponymous&#8221; and &#8220;Meliora,&#8221; have showcased their musical versatility and captivated audiences across the globe.</p>



<p>B. Influence on Contemporary Metal and Occult Aesthetics: Ghost&#8217;s success has influenced the resurgence of occult-themed music and aesthetics within the metal genre. Their theatrical approach, combined with melodic hooks and occult symbolism, has inspired a new wave of bands exploring similar themes.</p>



<p>Ghost&#8217;s journey through the realms of occult metal has fascinated and intrigued fans worldwide. Their mythology surrounding the &#8220;Church&#8221; and Papa Emeritus, combined with Tobias Forge&#8217;s interest in Freemasonry and occult symbolism, adds depth and intrigue to their music and performances. While connections between Ghost and Thelema may be speculative, their exploration of individualism and embrace of occult aesthetics resonate with the ideals of Thelema. As Ghost continues to weave their mysterious tapestry, their music and enigmatic presence will undoubtedly leave a lasting impact on the world of occult-inspired metal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
