<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Occult Groups &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/occult-groups/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>We place no reliance on virgin or pigeon</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 21:01:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/wp-1705263788885-150x150.gif</url>
	<title>Occult Groups &#8211; Love is the Law</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">222527107</site>	<item>
		<title>Notes on Masonry and Comparison to Other Orders</title>
		<link>/superficial-notes-on-masonry-and-a-very-brief-comparison-to-other-occult-orders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 21:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1. Origins and History: &#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucianism emerged in the early 17th century with the publication of the Rosicrucian manifestos. It gained popularity in Europe during the Renaissance and Enlightenment periods. &#8211; Freemasonry: Freemasonry has ancient roots and evolved from medieval stonemason guilds. The modern form of Freemasonry emerged in the 17th and 18th centuries, with lodges established throughout Europe and later in other parts of the world. 2. Membership and Organization: &#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucians often form smaller, esoteric and philosophical study groups or mystical orders. Membership is typically limited to individuals who have a sincere interest &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-cover is-light is-repeated wp-duotone-707070-ffffff-1" style="min-height:145px"><span aria-hidden="true" class="wp-block-cover__background has-background-dim-30 has-background-dim"></span><div role="img" class="wp-block-cover__image-background wp-image-489 is-repeated" style="background-position:50% 50%;background-image:url(/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/freemason-symbol-set-icon-signs-600w-1657190194-transformed-300x110.jpeg)"></div><div class="wp-block-cover__inner-container is-layout-flow wp-block-cover-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-center has-sitebg-color has-text-color has-larger-font-size"><mark style="background-color:rgba(0, 0, 0, 0)" class="has-inline-color has-sitebg-color"><strong>Notes on Public Occult Orders</strong></mark></p>
</div></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1. Origins and History:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism emerged in the early 17th century with the publication of the Rosicrucian manifestos. It gained popularity in Europe during the Renaissance and Enlightenment periods.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry has ancient roots and evolved from medieval stonemason guilds. The modern form of Freemasonry emerged in the 17th and 18th centuries, with lodges established throughout Europe and later in other parts of the world.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">2. Membership and Organization:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucians often form smaller, esoteric and philosophical study groups or mystical orders. Membership is typically limited to individuals who have a sincere interest in esoteric studies and spiritual development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry operates in lodges, which are local organizations that serve as meeting places for members. Freemasonry has a hierarchical structure with degrees of initiation, including the Entered Apprentice, Fellow Craft, and Master Mason degrees.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">3. Philosophical and Spiritual Orientation:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism places emphasis on the pursuit of spiritual wisdom, inner transformation, and personal evolution. It draws upon mystical Christianity, Hermeticism, and alchemy to seek spiritual insights and attain union with the Divine.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry is not inherently tied to any specific religious or philosophical system. It is a fraternal organization that promotes moral and ethical principles, brotherhood, and charitable work. Freemasonry encourages members to practice their own faith and seek personal improvement.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">4. Rituals and Symbolism:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian rituals often incorporate alchemical symbolism and meditative practices. Rosicrucians may use visualizations, symbolic gestures, and contemplative exercises to deepen their understanding and spiritual connection.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry utilizes symbolic rituals and allegories to impart moral and philosophical teachings. It employs tools and symbols from the stonemason trade, such as the square, compass, and the apron, to convey ethical principles and life lessons.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">5. Focus on Esoteric Knowledge:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucianism places a strong emphasis on esoteric knowledge, including mystical teachings, hermetic philosophy, alchemical symbolism, and metaphysical concepts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>While Freemasonry incorporates symbolic and allegorical teachings, it does not have an explicit focus on esoteric knowledge. Freemasonry aims to promote personal growth, moral virtues, and social fellowship.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">6. Membership Requirements:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br />&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian orders often have specific membership requirements, which can include a vetting process, adherence to certain ethical principles, and a commitment to study and personal development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry requires potential members to be of lawful age, believe in a Supreme Being, and have good moral character. It emphasizes equality, brotherhood, and mutual respect among members.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">7. Public Visibility and Influence:</h2>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: </h2>



<p>Rosicrucian orders, such as the Ancient Mystical Order Rosae Crucis (AMORC) and the Rosicrucian Fellowship, have established public presence and offer educational materials and correspondence courses to the public.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center"><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: </h2>



<p>Freemasonry is more widely recognized and visible, with Masonic lodges often present in communities worldwide. Freemasonry has historically played a significant role in philanthropy, community service, and social networks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading has-text-align-center">PART #2:</h2>



<p>Shriners are Freemasons. The Shriners is an appendant body of Freemasonry, specifically associated with the Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine, commonly known as Shriners International. Shriners are Freemasons who have attained the third degree, or Master Mason, in their respective Masonic lodges. The Shriners focus on charitable work, particularly supporting Shriners Hospitals for Children, which provides specialized medical care to children.</p>



<p>On the other hand, the Loyal Order of Buffaloes (often referred to as Buffalos or LOB) is a separate fraternal organization and not directly affiliated with Freemasonry. The Loyal Order of Buffaloes is an independent fraternity that promotes social fellowship, charity, and community involvement. While the Buffalos may share some similarities in terms of fellowship and community service, they are distinct from Freemasonry and do not require Masonic membership to join.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Buffaloes (LOB) is a fraternal organization that has had a presence primarily in the United Kingdom, Australia, and Canada. While the LOB does not have the same level of visibility as some other fraternal organizations, it has had a number of notable members throughout its history. Here are a few examples:</p>



<p>1. Charlie Chaplin: The legendary silent film actor and filmmaker was reported to be a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>2. Danny La Rue: The British entertainer, known for his drag performances and variety shows, was also a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>3. Anthony Eden: Sir Anthony Eden, a British politician who served as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom from 1955 to 1957, was a member of the LOB.</p>



<p>4. Bob Monkhouse: The British comedian, actor, and television presenter was a member of the LOB and often mentioned his involvement with the organization in his performances.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that while these individuals were reported to be members of the Loyal Order of Buffaloes, membership in fraternal organizations is often private, and specific details may not be widely available or confirmed.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Water Buffalos, however, is a fictional organization that parodies the Loyal Order of Buffaloes. It originated in the animated television series &#8220;The Flintstones.&#8221; In the show, the Loyal Order of Water Buffalos is depicted as a men&#8217;s fraternal organization to which Fred Flintstone and his friend Barney Rubble belong. It is portrayed as a humorous exaggeration of traditional fraternal organizations, highlighting the rituals, secret handshakes, and comedic initiation ceremonies often associated with such groups.</p>



<p>The Loyal Order of Water Buffalos serves as a satirical representation of real-life fraternal organizations, including the Loyal Order of Buffaloes. Its purpose in the show is primarily comedic and provides a backdrop for humorous situations and storytelling. It is important to note that the fictional Loyal Order of Water Buffalos should not be confused with the actual Loyal Order of Buffaloes, which is a genuine fraternal organization that promotes fellowship and charitable endeavors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">140</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Evolution of the Temple of Set: Unveiling Beliefs and Contrasting Perspectives</title>
		<link>/the-evolution-of-the-temple-of-set-unveiling-beliefs-and-contrasting-perspectives/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 19:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=62</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the realm of modern occultism, the Temple of Set stands as a distinct and intriguing organization. Founded in 1975 by Michael Aquino, a former member of the Church of Satan, the Temple of Set represents a departure from Anton LaVey&#8217;s Church of Satan in terms of philosophy and practices. This blog post aims to explore the evolution of the Temple of Set, its core beliefs, and the contrasting perspectives between Aquino and LaVey. 1. The Origins of the Temple of Set:The Temple of Set emerged as a splinter group from the Church of Satan, primarily due &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the realm of modern occultism, the Temple of Set stands as a distinct and intriguing organization. Founded in 1975 by Michael Aquino, a former member of the Church of Satan, the Temple of Set represents a departure from Anton LaVey&#8217;s Church of Satan in terms of philosophy and practices. This blog post aims to explore the evolution of the Temple of Set, its core beliefs, and the contrasting perspectives between Aquino and LaVey.</p>



<p>1. The Origins of the Temple of Set:<br>The Temple of Set emerged as a splinter group from the Church of Satan, primarily due to philosophical and ideological differences. Michael Aquino, a prominent figure within the Church of Satan, became dissatisfied with the atheistic and materialistic approach propagated by Anton LaVey. He sought to develop a more spiritual and individualistic path, leading to the formation of the Temple of Set.</p>



<p>2. Core Beliefs of the Temple of Set:<br>The Temple of Set centers its beliefs on the concept of Set, an Egyptian deity associated with chaos, individualism, and self-deification. Unlike the Church of Satan, which focuses on Satan as a symbol of rebellion and human indulgence, the Temple of Set emphasizes personal transformation, self-mastery, and the pursuit of individual excellence. The Temple embraces a more esoteric and mystical approach, incorporating elements from ancient Egyptian mythology, ceremonial magic, and psychological exploration.</p>



<p>3. Contrasting Perspectives: Temple of Set vs. Church of Satan:<br>&#8211; Theistic vs. Atheistic: While the Church of Satan adopts an atheistic stance, considering Satan as a symbol rather than a literal deity, the Temple of Set embraces a theistic perspective, regarding Set as a real entity with whom practitioners can establish a personal relationship.<br>&#8211; Individualism vs. Collectivism: The Temple of Set places a stronger emphasis on individualism and self-deification, encouraging members to explore and develop their unique potentials. In contrast, the Church of Satan promotes collective indulgence and embraces a more group-oriented approach.<br>&#8211; Magical Practices: The Temple of Set incorporates ceremonial magic and ritualistic practices as means of spiritual exploration and self-transformation. The Church of Satan, on the other hand, focuses more on ritual as psychological catharsis and theatrical expression.</p>



<p>4. Michael Aquino and his Philosophies:<br>Michael Aquino&#8217;s work with the US Army, particularly his involvement in psychological warfare, may have influenced his worldview and approach to the occult. His experiences in the military likely contributed to his interest in psychology, mind control, and the exploration of the human psyche. Aquino developed a unique synthesis of psychological and occult ideas, which he integrated into the teachings and practices of the Temple of Set.</p>



<p>The Temple of Set represents an evolution from the Church of Satan, offering an alternative approach to occultism and spiritual exploration. Michael Aquino&#8217;s divergent philosophies, influenced by his military background and psychological interests, have shaped the Temple of Set into a distinct organization. Understanding the beliefs and contrasting perspectives between the Temple of Set and the Church of Satan allows for a deeper appreciation of the diversity and complexity within modern occultism.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">62</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is Rosicrucianism?</title>
		<link>/what-is-rosicrucianism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 19:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=56</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rosicrucianism is a mystical and philosophical movement that emerged in the early 17th century. It is based on a series of manifestos known as the &#8220;Rosicrucian manifestos&#8221; that claimed to reveal secret knowledge and teachings from an ancient brotherhood of initiates. While Rosicrucianism encompasses various interpretations and branches, there are common beliefs and principles associated with the tradition. Here is an overview of the belief system and how it compares to other esoteric schools of thought: 1. Universal Knowledge and Wisdom: Rosicrucians believe in the existence of a universal wisdom, which encompasses spiritual, philosophical, and scientific truths. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Rosicrucianism is a mystical and philosophical movement that emerged in the early 17th century. It is based on a series of manifestos known as the &#8220;Rosicrucian manifestos&#8221; that claimed to reveal secret knowledge and teachings from an ancient brotherhood of initiates. While Rosicrucianism encompasses various interpretations and branches, there are common beliefs and principles associated with the tradition. Here is an overview of the belief system and how it compares to other esoteric schools of thought:</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>1. Universal Knowledge and Wisdom:</strong></p>



<p><br />Rosicrucians believe in the existence of a universal wisdom, which encompasses spiritual, philosophical, and scientific truths. They seek to attain this knowledge through self-transformation and the pursuit of spiritual enlightenment.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>2. Inner Transformation:</strong></p>



<p><br />Central to Rosicrucianism is the idea of inner transformation and personal evolution. Practitioners aim to develop their spiritual faculties, refine their character, and achieve a state of spiritual perfection or union with the Divine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>3. Mystical Christianity and Hermeticism:</strong></p>



<p><br />Rosicrucianism draws upon Christian symbolism and teachings, particularly emphasizing the mystical aspects of Christianity. It incorporates elements of Hermeticism, a philosophical and magical tradition influenced by ancient Egyptian and Greek teachings. Rosicrucians seek to harmonize these traditions and find spiritual truth through their combined wisdom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>4. Threefold Path of Study, Contemplation, and Service:</strong></p>



<p><br />Rosicrucians follow a threefold path that consists of study, contemplation, and service. They engage in rigorous study of esoteric texts, philosophical treatises, and sacred scriptures to deepen their understanding. Contemplation and meditation are used to access inner wisdom and cultivate spiritual insight. Service to humanity and the world is seen as an essential aspect of spiritual growth and expression of divine love.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>5. Alchemy and Symbolism:</strong></p>



<p><br />Rosicrucianism incorporates alchemical symbolism and teachings as a means of inner transformation and spiritual transmutation. Alchemy is seen not only as a literal practice of transforming base metals into gold but also as an allegory for the purification and elevation of the soul.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>6. Brotherhood and Fraternity:</strong></p>



<p><br />Rosicrucians emphasize the importance of brotherhood and fraternity, viewing themselves as part of a spiritual community or fellowship. They believe in the existence of a hidden brotherhood of initiates who possess advanced spiritual knowledge and work for the betterment of humanity.</p>



<p>Compared to other esoteric schools of thought, Rosicrucianism shares some commonalities while maintaining its distinct characteristics:</p>



<p><br />&#8211; It draws upon Christian and Hermetic traditions, blending mystical and philosophical elements.</p>



<p><br />&#8211; The focus on inner transformation and personal evolution is similar to other mystical and spiritual paths.</p>



<p><br />&#8211; Rosicrucianism places a significant emphasis on universal knowledge and the pursuit of spiritual wisdom.</p>



<p><br />&#8211; The integration of alchemical symbolism and practices distinguishes it from some other esoteric traditions.</p>



<p>Rosicrucianism differs from other fraternal religious groups in a number of ways. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>1. Origins and History:</strong></p>



<p><br />&#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucianism emerged in the early 17th century with the publication of the Rosicrucian manifestos. It gained popularity in Europe during the Renaissance and Enlightenment periods.</p>



<p><br />&#8211; Freemasonry: Freemasonry has ancient roots and evolved from medieval stonemason guilds. The modern form of Freemasonry emerged in the 17th and 18th centuries, with lodges established throughout Europe and later in other parts of the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>2. Membership and Organization:</strong></p>



<p><br />&#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucians often form smaller, esoteric and philosophical study groups or mystical orders. Membership is typically limited to individuals who have a sincere interest in esoteric studies and spiritual development.</p>



<p><br />&#8211; Freemasonry: Freemasonry operates in lodges, which are local organizations that serve as meeting places for members. Freemasonry has a hierarchical structure with degrees of initiation, including the Entered Apprentice, Fellow Craft, and Master Mason degrees.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>3. Philosophical and Spiritual Orientation</strong></p>



<p><br />&#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucianism places emphasis on the pursuit of spiritual wisdom, inner transformation, and personal evolution. It draws upon mystical Christianity, Hermeticism, and alchemy to seek spiritual insights and attain union with the Divine.</p>



<p><br>&#8211; Freemasonry: Freemasonry is not inherently tied to any specific religious or philosophical system. It is a fraternal organization that promotes moral and ethical principles, brotherhood, and charitable work. Freemasonry encourages members to practice their own faith and seek personal improvement.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>4. Rituals and Symbolism:</strong></p>



<p><br />&#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucian rituals often incorporate alchemical symbolism and meditative practices. Rosicrucians may use visualizations, symbolic gestures, and contemplative exercises to deepen their understanding and spiritual connection.</p>



<p><br />&#8211; Freemasonry: Freemasonry utilizes symbolic rituals and allegories to impart moral and philosophical teachings. It employs tools and symbols from the stonemason trade, such as the square, compass, and the apron, to convey ethical principles and life lessons.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>5. Focus on Esoteric Knowledge</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucianism places a strong emphasis on esoteric knowledge, including mystical teachings, hermetic philosophy, alchemical symbolism, and metaphysical concepts.</p>



<p><br />&#8211; Freemasonry: While Freemasonry incorporates symbolic and allegorical teachings, it does not have an explicit focus on esoteric knowledge. Freemasonry aims to promote personal growth, moral virtues, and social fellowship.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>6. Membership Requirements:</strong></p>



<p>&#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucian orders often have specific membership requirements, which can include a vetting process, adherence to certain ethical principles, and a commitment to study and personal development.</p>



<p><br />&#8211; Freemasonry: Freemasonry requires potential members to be of lawful age, believe in a Supreme Being, and have good moral character. It emphasizes equality, brotherhood, and mutual respect among members.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>7. Public Visibility and Influence:</strong></p>



<p><br />&#8211; Rosicrucianism: Rosicrucian orders, such as the Ancient Mystical Order Rosae Crucis (AMORC) and the Rosicrucian Fellowship, have established public presence and offer educational materials and correspondence courses to the public.</p>



<p><br />&#8211; Freemasonry: Freemasonry is more widely recognized and visible, with Masonic lodges often present in communities worldwide. Freemasonry has historically played a significant role in philanthropy, community service, and social networks.</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">56</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Freemasonry: The Hidden Growth and the Preservation of Esoteric Knowledge</title>
		<link>/freemasonry-the-hidden-growth-and-the-preservation-of-esoteric-knowledge-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 16:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we continue our exploration into the vast realm of Freemasonry, we now turn our attention to its growth behind the scenes, particularly during the early colonial period in America. We will also delve into the fascinating role Freemasonry played in preserving arcane and esoteric knowledge, which could have otherwise been lost over time. While acknowledging that modern society may no longer depend on these ancient practices, we must recognize and appreciate the significant historical impact Freemasonry holds. 1. Freemasonry&#8217;s Growth in Early Colonial America: Freemasonry found fertile ground for expansion during the colonial period of American &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As we continue our exploration into the vast realm of Freemasonry, we now turn our attention to its growth behind the scenes, particularly during the early colonial period in America. We will also delve into the fascinating role Freemasonry played in preserving arcane and esoteric knowledge, which could have otherwise been lost over time. While acknowledging that modern society may no longer depend on these ancient practices, we must recognize and appreciate the significant historical impact Freemasonry holds.</p>



<p>1. Freemasonry&#8217;s Growth in Early Colonial America:</p>



<p><br>Freemasonry found fertile ground for expansion during the colonial period of American history. Masonic lodges began to emerge throughout the colonies, drawing members from various social, political, and religious backgrounds. The inclusive nature of Freemasonry, promoting equality and brotherhood, made it a appealing platform for networking, personal growth, and philanthropy, attracting many influential figures of the time.</p>



<p>2. The Hidden Role of Freemasonry:</p>



<p><br>Behind the scenes, Freemasonry served as a unique repository for arcane and esoteric knowledge, preserving ancient wisdom that may otherwise have been lost. Masonic rituals, symbols, and teachings acted as vessels through which this knowledge was passed down from generation to generation. By embedding these teachings within their practices, Freemasons ensured the longevity and accessibility of these esoteric traditions.</p>



<p>3. The Preservation of Esoteric Knowledge:</p>



<p><br>Within Freemasonry, esoteric knowledge encompasses a vast array of ancient teachings, including elements of alchemy, astrology, numerology, and various mystical traditions. The symbolic language used in Masonic rituals and ceremonies provided a means to convey these teachings in a manner that transcended linguistic and cultural barriers. This preservation of esoteric knowledge allowed it to persist across centuries, safeguarding the wisdom of the past for future generations.</p>



<p>4. The Role of Freemasonry in Human History:<br />While modern society may no longer rely on arcane and esoteric practices in the same way as earlier periods, the role of Freemasonry in preserving this knowledge should not be underestimated. It has acted as a bridge connecting us to our historical roots, enabling us to understand and appreciate the ancient wisdom that has shaped human civilization. By safeguarding this knowledge, Freemasonry has contributed significantly to the collective consciousness of humanity.</p>



<p>Freemasonry&#8217;s growth behind the scenes, particularly during early colonial America, cannot be understated. The hidden role of Freemasonry in preserving arcane and esoteric knowledge has been instrumental in our understanding of human history and its profound impact. While modern society may no longer rely on these ancient practices, we must recognize and honor the invaluable role Freemasonry has played throughout the ages. It continues to serve as a reminder of the rich tapestry of knowledge that has shaped our world, connecting us to our collective past and inspiring us to seek wisdom and enlightenment.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">130</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tracing the Origins and Influence of Freemasonry: A Fascinating Journey into History</title>
		<link>/tracing-the-origins-and-influence-of-freemasonry-a-fascinating-journey-into-history/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 15:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=126</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Freemasonry, with its rich symbolism, rituals, and mysterious origins, has captured the attention and imagination of many throughout history. In this exhaustive exploration, we will delve into the history of Freemasonry, its alleged connection with the construction of Solomon&#8217;s Temple, its links to occultism, and the intriguing possibility of it serving as a historical society preserving ancient religious knowledge. The origin of Freemasonry, its alleged association with Solomon&#8217;s Temple, and its indirect or direct influence on the birth of occultism have fueled fascinating conjectures throughout history. While various hypotheses propose ancient connections and hidden knowledge, it is &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Freemasonry, with its rich symbolism, rituals, and mysterious origins, has captured the attention and imagination of many throughout history. In this exhaustive exploration, we will delve into the history of Freemasonry, its alleged connection with the construction of Solomon&#8217;s Temple, its links to occultism, and the intriguing possibility of it serving as a historical society preserving ancient religious knowledge.</p>



<ol>
<li>Origins of Freemasonry:<br>The exact origins of Freemasonry remain the subject of much debate. The earliest documented Masonic lodges emerged in the late 16th and early 17th centuries in England. However, many theories posit that Freemasonry can be traced back to ancient civilizations, drawing inspiration from the stonemasons who built impressive structures.</li>



<li>Freemasonry and Solomon&#8217;s Temple:<br>One popular theory suggests a connection between Freemasonry and the construction of Solomon&#8217;s Temple. While there is no concrete evidence, Freemasonry incorporates elements from the story of the temple&#8217;s construction in its rituals and symbolism. These references to the temple serve as allegories and moral lessons rather than historical claims.</li>



<li>Freemasonry and Occultism:<br>During the Enlightenment era, Freemasonry attracted numerous intellectual and spiritual seekers. The Order&#8217;s emphasis on philosophy, esoteric knowledge, and symbolism made it an attractive platform for fostering occult and mystical ideas. Influential figures like Aleister Crowley, Éliphas Lévi, and Albert Pike sought to incorporate occult principles into their interpretations of Freemasonry, evolving into occultist movements like Thelema.</li>



<li>Freemasonry as a Keeper of Ancient Knowledge:<br>Some theorists propose that Freemasonry may have served as a custodian of ancient religious traditions and esoteric knowledge, preserving them in plain sight. The idea suggests that Masonic symbols, rituals, and even coded language serve as hidden repositories of wisdom from fallen empires or lost civilizations. Such claims often draw upon theories of steganography and cryptography, suggesting hidden messages encoded within Masonic texts, rituals, and architectural designs.</li>



<li>The Reality of Freemasonry:<br>It is essential to note that Freemasonry, as an organization, has evolved over centuries and encompasses diverse viewpoints, practices, and interpretations. While some individuals within Freemasonry may engage in the study of ancient religious traditions or esoteric knowledge, the organization itself serves a broader purpose, focusing on personal growth, moral teachings, philanthropy, and fraternal bonds.</li>
</ol>



<p>The origin of Freemasonry, its alleged association with Solomon&#8217;s Temple, and its indirect or direct influence on the birth of occultism have fueled fascinating conjectures throughout history. While various hypotheses propose ancient connections and hidden knowledge, it is crucial to approach these claims with a critical mindset. Freemasonry&#8217;s enduring impact lies in its ability to inspire personal growth, foster fraternity, and serve as a vessel for philosophical and moral teachings, as it continues to adapt and evolve in the modern world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">126</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aleister Crowley and the Influence of Occult Organizations on Thelema</title>
		<link>/aleister-crowley-and-the-influence-of-occult-organizations-on-thelema/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 15:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magick]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aleister Crowley, a prominent figure in the occult world, was associated with several influential occult organizations during his lifetime. These associations played a significant role in shaping his spiritual and philosophical system known as Thelema. In this blog post, we will explore the similarities between Thelema and Freemasonry, the Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn, as well as the Ordo Templi Orientis (O.T.O.) and the A∴A∴, shedding light on how Crowley drew inspiration from each of these organizations. Similarly, the A∴A∴, building on the spiritual path of the Golden Dawn, aimed to guide practitioners toward spiritual enlightenment &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Aleister Crowley, a prominent figure in the occult world, was associated with several influential occult organizations during his lifetime. These associations played a significant role in shaping his spiritual and philosophical system known as Thelema. In this blog post, we will explore the similarities between Thelema and Freemasonry, the Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn, as well as the Ordo Templi Orientis (O.T.O.) and the A∴A∴, shedding light on how Crowley drew inspiration from each of these organizations.</p>



<ol>
<li>Thelema and Freemasonry:<br>Aleister Crowley was deeply influenced by Freemasonry, which he saw as a repository of ancient symbolism and initiatory practices. The concept of initiation, the use of ritual, and the hierarchical structure found in Freemasonry served as foundations for Thelema. However, Crowley believed that Freemasonry had lost touch with its original spiritual essence, prompting him to create a new system that he felt better aligned with his own beliefs.</li>



<li>Thelema and the Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn:<br>Crowley&#8217;s involvement with the Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn provided him with a wealth of knowledge in ceremonial magic, Qabalah, and the Western esoteric tradition. The Golden Dawn&#8217;s emphasis on tarot, astrology, and the use of ritual magic greatly influenced Thelema&#8217;s practices. The Golden Dawn&#8217;s emphasis on individual spiritual development and self-discovery also resonated profoundly with Crowley&#8217;s philosophy of personal freedom and self-realization.</li>



<li>The O.T.O. and the A∴A∴:<br>Crowley&#8217;s creation of the Ordo Templi Orientis (O.T.O.) and the Argentum Astrum (A∴A∴) demonstrated his desire to establish organizations that would serve as vehicles for the dissemination and exploration of Thelemic teachings. The O.T.O., inspired by Freemasonry and other mystical traditions, aimed to provide a framework for the promotion of Thelemic principles, including the pursuit of individual will and the exploration of sexual mysticism.</li>
</ol>



<p>Similarly, the A∴A∴, building on the spiritual path of the Golden Dawn, aimed to guide practitioners toward spiritual enlightenment and self-realization through a system of grades and initiations. The A∴A∴ also embraced the concept of the True Will, emphasizing the importance of finding and aligning oneself with one&#8217;s true purpose in life.</p>



<p>Aleister Crowley&#8217;s involvement with various occult organizations played a substantial role in the development and design of Thelema. The prevalent influence of Freemasonry, the Hermetic Order of the Golden Dawn, the O.T.O., and the A∴A∴ is evident in Thelema&#8217;s symbolism, rituals, and spiritual concepts. While Crowley drew inspiration from these organizations, he also brought his unique perspective and ideas, resulting in the creation of a distinct spiritual system that continues to resonate with practitioners today. Understanding these influences allows us to appreciate the rich tapestry of ideas that shaped Thelema and its lasting impact on the occult world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">122</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Comparative Analysis of Scientology and Thelema: Uncovering Similarities and Discerning Differences</title>
		<link>/a-comparative-analysis-of-scientology-and-thelema-uncovering-similarities-and-discerning-differences-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 14:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=70</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the realm of esoteric and occult beliefs, two prominent systems have captured the attention of seekers and critics alike: Scientology and Thelema. While both systems have their own unique characteristics, examining their similarities and dissimilarities can provide valuable insights into their foundations, practices, and the potential influence they may have had on one another. In this blog post, we will compare and contrast Scientology and Thelema, exploring their core principles, practices, and the controversial assertions surrounding their origins. b. Scientology: Scientology centers around the concept of spiritual liberation and self-improvement. Hubbard introduced the idea of &#8220;thetans&#8221; &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the realm of esoteric and occult beliefs, two prominent systems have captured the attention of seekers and critics alike: Scientology and Thelema. While both systems have their own unique characteristics, examining their similarities and dissimilarities can provide valuable insights into their foundations, practices, and the potential influence they may have had on one another. In this blog post, we will compare and contrast Scientology and Thelema, exploring their core principles, practices, and the controversial assertions surrounding their origins.</p>



<ol>
<li>Founding Figures:<br />a. L. Ron Hubbard and Crowley: L. Ron Hubbard, the founder of Scientology, and Aleister Crowley, the key proponent of Thelema, were both influential figures but belonged to different time periods and movements. While there are some claims that Hubbard may have drawn inspiration from Crowley&#8217;s ideas, there is no concrete evidence to support the assertion that he consciously perverted or stole Crowley&#8217;s concepts.</li>



<li>Core Principles:<br />a. Thelema: Thelema, as developed by Crowley, is based on the core principle of &#8220;Do what thou wilt shall be the whole of the Law.&#8221; It emphasizes individualism, personal freedom, and the pursuit of one&#8217;s true will, which is seen as aligning with divine will or purpose.</li>
</ol>



<p>b. Scientology: Scientology centers around the concept of spiritual liberation and self-improvement. Hubbard introduced the idea of &#8220;thetans&#8221; (immortal spiritual beings) and the concept that individuals can enhance their spiritual abilities through counseling and auditing practices.</p>



<ol start="3">
<li>Religious Approach and Practices:<br />a. Thelema: Thelema is often considered a religious philosophy, blending elements of occultism and mysticism. It incorporates ceremonial rituals, magickal practices, and initiation ceremonies within its framework.</li>
</ol>



<p>b. Scientology: Scientology is generally viewed as a religion, utilizing audiology as a form of spiritual counseling. Scientologists engage in various courses, training sessions, and auditing to progress along the &#8220;Bridge to Total Freedom.&#8221;</p>



<ol start="4">
<li>Influence and Ideas:<br />a. Potential Connections: There have been speculations about Hubbard&#8217;s familiarity with Crowley&#8217;s work, particularly since both individuals were involved in occult circles during their lifetimes. However, there is no definitive evidence to suggest that Hubbard specifically perverted Crowley&#8217;s ideas to control or enslave individuals within Scientology.</li>
</ol>



<p>b. Individual Paths: While Crowley&#8217;s Thelema primarily focuses on individual spiritual liberation, Scientology centers more on personal development and improvement within a structured framework. The fundamental intentions of both systems differ significantly.</p>



<p>While some parallels may be drawn between Scientology and Thelema, they fundamentally differ in terms of core principles, practices, and purposes. While both systems have faced their share of controversies throughout history, asserting that Hubbard deliberately stole and perverted Crowley&#8217;s ideas to manipulate Scientologists seems speculative and lacks concrete evidence. Understanding the unique aspects of each belief system allows for a more nuanced discussion, providing a deeper appreciation for their profound impact on their respective followers and the broader spiritual landscape.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">70</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Intriguing History of L. Ron Hubbard, Aleister Crowley, Jack Parsons, and  Marjorie Cameron</title>
		<link>/lrh_scumbag/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Firsto Lasto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 14:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occult Groups]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=48</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The evolution of Scientology, a controversial religious movement developed by L. Ron Hubbard, is not without its captivating historical connections. This blog post dives deep into the intriguing relationship between Hubbard, Aleister Crowley, Jack Parsons, and Crowley&#8217;s wife. By exploring their interactions and examining the influence they had on one another, we can gain valuable insights into the development of Hubbard and his pioneering religious movement, Scientology. 1. L. Ron Hubbard and Aleister Crowley:a. Early Connections: While there are claims that L. Ron Hubbard and Aleister Crowley met, no concrete evidence suggests that they had a close &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The evolution of Scientology, a controversial religious movement developed by L. Ron Hubbard, is not without its captivating historical connections. This blog post dives deep into the intriguing relationship between Hubbard, Aleister Crowley, Jack Parsons, and Crowley&#8217;s wife. By exploring their interactions and examining the influence they had on one another, we can gain valuable insights into the development of Hubbard and his pioneering religious movement, Scientology.</p>



<p>1. L. Ron Hubbard and Aleister Crowley:<br>a. Early Connections: While there are claims that L. Ron Hubbard and Aleister Crowley met, no concrete evidence suggests that they had a close relationship. However, both individuals were active during the same period within esoteric circles, with Crowley&#8217;s influence being prominent among occultists.</p>



<p>b. Influential Ideas: Hubbard, as a young man, had a fascination for occultism and metaphysical practices. Although specifics of their influence on Hubbard are unclear, it is plausible that Crowley&#8217;s philosophies, such as &#8220;Do what thou wilt,&#8221; and his involvement in ceremonial magick, may have influenced Hubbard&#8217;s later spiritual concepts.</p>



<p>2. Jack Parsons and L. Ron Hubbard:<br>a. Collaboration on the Babalon Working: Jack Parsons, an American rocket propulsion researcher and a dedicated follower of Crowley, collaborated with Hubbard in 1946 on a series of rituals known as the Babalon Working. The objective was to manifest the divine feminine, symbolized by the goddess Babalon.</p>



<p>b. Hubbard&#8217;s Role and Departure: Hubbard participated as a &#8220;scribe&#8221; in the Babalon Working rituals, documenting the events. However, following some controversial events and alleged personal conflicts, Hubbard left abruptly, taking with him Parsons&#8217; girlfriend, Sara Northrup. This departure strained their relationship.</p>



<p>c. Influence on Scientology: It is debated how directly the experiences with Parsons and his involvement in the Babalon Working influenced Hubbard and affected the development of Scientology. While there may have been shared ideas and concepts explored during their brief collaboration, it is difficult to determine the extent of Parsons&#8217; influence on Scientology&#8217;s doctrines.</p>



<p>3. Influence of Crowley&#8217;s Wife, Marjorie Cameron:<br>a. Close Association: Jack Parsons, a devoted follower of Crowley, was married to Marjorie Cameron, an artist, poet, and occultist. Cameron often participated in Parsons&#8217; magickal rituals and ceremonies, embracing some of Crowley&#8217;s ideologies and practices.</p>



<p>b. Cameron&#8217;s Influence on Parsons: Cameron&#8217;s influence on Parsons&#8217; occult research and practices is documented, and her participation in ceremonies likely influenced Parsons&#8217; understanding of Crowley&#8217;s teachings and his pursuit of spiritual experiences.</p>



<p>c. Hubbard&#8217;s Involvement and Departure: Hubbard&#8217;s involvement with Cameron is less clear, although some sources suggest he had interactions with her during his time with Parsons. However, the exact nature and extent of their relationship remain speculative and inconclusive.</p>



<p>While L. Ron Hubbard&#8217;s interactions with Aleister Crowley, Jack Parsons, and Crowley&#8217;s wife, Marjorie Cameron, are undeniably fascinating, their impact on Scientology&#8217;s development is difficult to ascertain with absolute certainty. Although Hubbard engaged in collaborative occult rituals with Parsons, the exact influence of Crowley and Parsons on Scientology remains ambiguous. It is essential to approach the subject with caution, relying on verified information rather than speculation to fully comprehend the intricate history surrounding the development of Scientology and Hubbard&#8217;s relationships with these notable figures of the occult.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">48</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
